<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><mtg_carddatabase><bdd_date><![CDATA[1-5-2013]]></bdd_date><bdd_version><![CDATA[1.00]]></bdd_version><bdd_name>Magic the Gathering® Card Database</bdd_name><bdd_editor>Wizards of the Coast LLC</bdd_editor><sets><set><name><![CDATA[Conflux]]></name><code><![CDATA[CFX]]></code><code_magiccards><![CDATA[CFX]]></code_magiccards><date><![CDATA[01/2009]]></date><is_promo><![CDATA[False]]></is_promo></set></sets><cards><card><id><![CDATA[179513]]></id><name><![CDATA[Absorb Vis]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{6}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target player loses 4 life and you gain 4 life.<br>Basic landcycling {1}{B} ({1}{B}, Discard this card: Search your library for a basic land card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Brandon Kitkouski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[40]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Unlike the normal cycling ability, basic landcycling doesn't allow you to draw a card. Instead, it lets you search your library for a basic land card. You don't choose the type of basic land card you'll find until you're performing the search. After you choose a basic land card in your library, you reveal it, put it into your hand, then shuffle your library. <br>2/1/2009 : Basic landcycling is a form of cycling. Any ability that triggers on a card being cycled also triggers on a card being basic landcycled. Any ability that stops a cycling ability from being activated also stops a basic landcycling ability from being activated. <br>2/1/2009 : Basic landcycling is an activated ability. Effects that interact with activated abilities (such as Stifle or Rings of Brighthearth) will interact with basic landcycling. Effects that interact with spells (such as Remove Soul or Faerie Tauntings) will not. <br>2/1/2009 : You can choose not to find a basic land card, even if there is one in your library.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153946]]></id><name><![CDATA[Aerie Mystics]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Bird Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>{1}{G}{U}: Creatures you control gain shroud until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[They are cautious with their body language and facial expressions. Any stray movement could betray the positions of the troops they protect and cost many lives.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mark Zug]]></artist><number><![CDATA[1]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[189271]]></id><name><![CDATA[Ancient Ziggurat]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool. Spend this mana only to cast a creature spell.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Built in honor of Alara's creatures, the ziggurat vanished long ago. When Progenitus awakened, the temple emerged again.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[John Avon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[141]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Mana produced by Ancient Ziggurat can be spent on any part of a creature spell's total cost. This includes additional costs (such as kicker) and alternative costs (such as evoke or Worldheart Phoenix's alternative cost). <br>2/1/2009 :  Mana produced by Ancient Ziggurat can't be spent on activated abilities that put a creature card directly onto the battlefield, such as unearth or ninjutsu.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[183068]]></id><name><![CDATA[Apocalypse Hydra]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Hydra]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{X}{R}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[0]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Apocalypse Hydra enters the battlefield with X +1/+1 counters on it. If X is 5 or more, it enters the battlefield with an additional X +1/+1 counters on it.<br>{1}{R}, Remove a +1/+1 counter from Apocalypse Hydra: Apocalypse Hydra deals 1 damage to target creature or player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jason Chan]]></artist><number><![CDATA[98]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : For example, if X is 4, Apocalypse Hydra enters the battlefield with four +1/+1 counters on it, but if X is 5, it enters the battlefield with ten +1/+1 counters on it. <br>2/1/2009 : The first ability checks the number you chose for X, not the amount of mana you actually spent.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[137936]]></id><name><![CDATA[Armillary Sphere]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{2}, {T}, Sacrifice Armillary Sphere: Search your library for up to two basic land cards, reveal them, and put them into your hand. Then shuffle your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The mysterious purpose of two of the rings had eluded Esper mages—until now.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Franz Vohwinkel]]></artist><number><![CDATA[134]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[150826]]></id><name><![CDATA[Asha's Favor]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature has flying, first strike, and vigilance.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[As his new wings lifted him high above Bant, Taric felt his earthly aspirations transform into heavenly resolve.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Donato Giancola]]></artist><number><![CDATA[2]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[184992]]></id><name><![CDATA[Aven Squire]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Bird Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[When the meek charge into battle, courage becomes infectious.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[David Palumbo]]></artist><number><![CDATA[3]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[180278]]></id><name><![CDATA[Aven Trailblazer]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Bird Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[*]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Domain — Aven Trailblazer's toughness is equal to the number of basic land types among lands you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The bird wore the form of a man, bereft of filigree. Why do the Texts not speak of it?"<br>—Belator of Esper]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chris Rahn]]></artist><number><![CDATA[4]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : To determine the number of basic land types among lands you control, look at the lands you have on the battlefield and ask yourself whether the subtypes Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, and Forest appear within that group. The number of times you say yes (topping out at five) tells you how powerful your domain abilities will be. <br>2/1/2009 : How many lands you control of a particular basic land type is irrelevant to a domain ability, as long as that number is greater than zero. As far as domain is concerned, ten Forests is the same as one Forest. <br>2/1/2009 : A number of nonbasic lands have basic land types. Domain abilities don't count the number of lands you control -- they count the number of basic land types among lands you control, even if that means checking the same land twice. For example, if you control a Tundra, an Overgrown Tomb, and a Madblind Mountain, you'll have a Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, and Forest among the lands you control. Your domain abilities will be maxed out. <br>2/1/2009 : Aven Trailblazer's second ability is a "characteristic-defining ability." It applies at all times in all zones.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[186613]]></id><name><![CDATA[Banefire]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{X}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Banefire deals X damage to target creature or player.<br>If X is 5 or more, Banefire can't be countered by spells or abilities and the damage can't be prevented.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[For Sarkhan Vol, the dragon is the purest expression of life's savage splendor.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Raymond Swanland]]></artist><number><![CDATA[58]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Banefire checks the number you chose for X, not the amount of mana you actually spent. <br>2/1/2009 : Banefire can be targeted by spells that try to counter it (such as Countersquall) regardless of what the value of X is. If X is 5 or more, those spells will still resolve, but the part of their effect that would counter Banefire won't do anything. Any other effects those spells have will work as normal. <br>2/1/2009 : Banefire's ability won't prevent it from being countered by the game rules if its target has become an illegal target.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[177931]]></id><name><![CDATA[Beacon Behemoth]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Beast]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}: Target creature with power 5 or greater gains vigilance until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[When its smoky plumes light Naya's sky, every creature from the smallest pip fawn to the largest rannet heeds the warning.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jesper Ejsing]]></artist><number><![CDATA[78]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[180267]]></id><name><![CDATA[Blood Tyrant]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Vampire]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{U}{B}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying, trample<br>At the beginning of your upkeep, each player loses 1 life. Put a +1/+1 counter on Blood Tyrant for each 1 life lost this way.<br>Whenever a player loses the game, put five +1/+1 counters on Blood Tyrant.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Karl Kopinski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[99]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Blood Tyrant's second ability causes each player to lose 1 life, including you. Blood Tyrant will count each player's life loss, including yours, when determining how many +1/+1 counters it gets. <br>2/1/2009 : Blood Tyrant's third ability will trigger no matter how a player loses the game: due to a state-based action (as a result of having a life total of 0 or less, trying to draw a card from an empty library, or having ten poison counters), a spell or ability that says that player loses the game, a concession, or a game loss awarded by a judge. <br>2/1/2009 : In a multiplayer game using the limited range of influence option (such as a Grand Melee game), if a spell or ability says that you win the game, it instead causes all of your opponents within your range of influence to lose the game. This is another way by which Blood Tyrant's third ability can trigger.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[159610]]></id><name><![CDATA[Bloodhall Ooze]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Ooze]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[At the beginning of your upkeep, if you control a black permanent, you may put a +1/+1 counter on Bloodhall Ooze.<br>At the beginning of your upkeep, if you control a green permanent, you may put a +1/+1 counter on Bloodhall Ooze.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[A drop of blood spilled from the first dragon.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jaime Jones]]></artist><number><![CDATA[59]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : The "intervening 'if' clause" means that (1) the ability won't trigger at all unless you control a permanent of the specified color, and (2) the ability will do nothing unless you control a permanent of the specified color at the time it resolves. <br>2/1/2009 : A permanent that's both black and green will allow both abilities to trigger (as will separate black permanents and green permanents, of course).]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[189270]]></id><name><![CDATA[Bone Saw]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact — Equipment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{0}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Equipped creature gets +1/+0.<br>Equip {1} ({1}: Attach to target creature you control. Equip only as a sorcery.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[In a world where death is always violent, cruel weapons are as common as rocks.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Pete Venters]]></artist><number><![CDATA[135]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[180147]]></id><name><![CDATA[Brackwater Elemental]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Brackwater Elemental attacks or blocks, sacrifice it at the beginning of the next end step.<br>Unearth {2}{U} ({2}{U}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Thomas M. Baxa]]></artist><number><![CDATA[21]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[184994]]></id><name><![CDATA[Canyon Minotaur]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Minotaur Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[On Jund, the deep canyons were the best places to hide. When the goblins wandered into Naya, they found that was not so true.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Prescott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[60]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[183055]]></id><name><![CDATA[Celestial Purge]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Exile target black or red permanent.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["This new chaos confounds us. We must fling it into our winds, our storms. These we can control."<br>—Bezzit Plar, Esper stormcaller]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[David Palumbo]]></artist><number><![CDATA[5]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : Lands are colorless (even if their frames have some colored elements to them). You can't target a Swamp, a Mountain, or any other land with Celestial Purge (unless some other effect has turned that land black or red).]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179438]]></id><name><![CDATA[Charnelhoard Wurm]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Wurm]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{B}{R}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample<br>Whenever Charnelhoard Wurm deals damage to an opponent, you may return target card from your graveyard to your hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Jund's dragons hoard only sangrite crystals. Its wurms aren't so picky.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Lars Grant-West]]></artist><number><![CDATA[100]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : If Charnelhoard Wurm is dealt lethal damage at the same time it deals damage to an opponent, Charnelhoard Wurm will be in your graveyard by the time you put its ability on the stack. In that case, you can target it with its own ability.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[180516]]></id><name><![CDATA[Child of Alara]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Avatar]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{W}{U}{B}{R}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample<br>When Child of Alara dies, destroy all nonland permanents. They can't be regenerated.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The progeny of the Maelstrom shows no allegiance—and no mercy—to any of the five shards.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Argyle]]></artist><number><![CDATA[101]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[159612]]></id><name><![CDATA[Cliffrunner Behemoth]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Rhino Beast]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Cliffrunner Behemoth has haste as long as you control a red permanent.<br>Cliffrunner Behemoth has lifelink as long as you control a white permanent.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It's revered for its power, celebrated for its grace, and feared for the avalanches triggered by its thunderous feet.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Wayne Reynolds]]></artist><number><![CDATA[79]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : As long as at least one permanent you control is the specified color, the ability will "work" and grant this creature the bonus. Otherwise, it won't have the bonus. <br>2/1/2009 : Whether Cliffrunner Behemoth has haste matters only when attackers are declared. Once it's been declared as an attacker, it doesn't matter if it loses haste. <br>2/1/2009 : Whether Cliffrunner Behemoth has lifelink matters only when it deals damage (that is, at the point when its combat damage resolves, or at the point when a spell or ability that causes it to deal damage resolves). For example, if your only white permanent is a creature that receives lethal damage at the same time Cliffrunner Behemoth deals damage, the lifelink ability will still apply and you'll gain life.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179437]]></id><name><![CDATA[Conflux]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}{U}{B}{R}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[8]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Search your library for a white card, a blue card, a black card, a red card, and a green card. Reveal those cards and put them into your hand. Then shuffle your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[After years of world-bending machinations, Bolas's triumph is at hand.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Karl Kopinski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[102]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : You don't have to find all five cards. <br>2/1/2009 : You may find multicolored cards with Conflux. The white card you find, for example, can be any number of colors, as long as white is one of them. What colors it is won't impact what other cards you can find. For example, you may find a white-blue card as the white card and another white-blue card as the blue card.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[180272]]></id><name><![CDATA[Constricting Tendrils]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target creature gets -3/-0 until end of turn.<br>Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Priests of Bant protect their temples with traps more elaborate than any mosaic floor.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[David Palumbo]]></artist><number><![CDATA[22]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2008 : Cycling is an activated ability. Effects that interact with activated abilities (such as Stifle or Rings of Brighthearth) will interact with cycling. Effects that interact with spells (such as Remove Soul or Faerie Tauntings) will not.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[183053]]></id><name><![CDATA[Controlled Instincts]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant red or green creature<br>Enchanted creature doesn't untap during its controller's untap step.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Togk Manytooth struggled helplessly as the kathari circled above him. For a warrior, immobilization is a fate worse than death.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ralph Horsley]]></artist><number><![CDATA[23]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Controlled Instincts may target and may enchant an untapped creature. <br>2/1/2009 : Controlled Instincts can enchant only a creature that's red or green. If at any time the enchanted creature is neither red nor green, Controlled Instincts is put into its owner's graveyard as a state-based action.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[183054]]></id><name><![CDATA[Corrupted Roots]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant Forest or Plains<br>Whenever enchanted land becomes tapped, its controller loses 2 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The bones of Jund's dead resurfaced in Naya, poisoning the jungle and killing the sunseeders' crops.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mark Hyzer]]></artist><number><![CDATA[41]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Corrupted Roots can enchant only a Forest or a Plains. It checks the enchanted land's subtypes, not its name. If at any time the enchanted land is neither a Forest nor a Plains (due to Unstable Frontier's ability, perhaps), Corrupted Roots is put into its owner's graveyard as a state-based action. <br>2/1/2009 : Corrupted Roots doesn't care why the enchanted land becomes tapped. If that land changes from being untapped to being tapped for any reason, the ability will trigger.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[186327]]></id><name><![CDATA[Countersquall]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{U}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Counter target noncreature spell. Its controller loses 2 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Each of the twenty-three winds of Esper is named and chronicled, and every possible interaction with the flow of magic is exhaustively detailed.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Anthony Francisco]]></artist><number><![CDATA[103]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[182607]]></id><name><![CDATA[Court Homunculus]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Homunculus]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Court Homunculus gets +1/+1 as long as you control another artifact.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Mages of Esper measure their wealth and status by the number of servants in their retinues.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Matt Cavotta]]></artist><number><![CDATA[6]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[180322]]></id><name><![CDATA[Cumber Stone]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Creatures your opponents control get -1/-0.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The stone is more potent than ever. The flesh that creeps into our land will become even more slovenly and weak."<br>—Niclavs, archmage of Esper]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Warren Mahy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[24]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[189081]]></id><name><![CDATA[Cylian Sunsinger]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elf Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{R}{G}{W}: Cylian Sunsinger and each other creature with the same name as it get +3/+3 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The sun shines bright upon the strong."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jesper Ejsing]]></artist><number><![CDATA[80]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : When the ability resolves, it gives the +3/+3 bonus to the source of the ability and each other creature that shares a name with that source, even if that source isn't actually named Cylian Sunsinger. This could happen if Skill Borrower gains this ability, or if Cylian Sunsinger's name is changed (due to Mirrorweave, perhaps) before the ability resolves. <br>2/1/2009 : If Cylian Sunsinger has left the battlefield by the time its ability resolves, its ability will affect each creature whose name is the same as the name Cylian Sunsinger had as it last existed on the battlefield.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[185143]]></id><name><![CDATA[Dark Temper]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Dark Temper deals 2 damage to target creature. If you control a black permanent, destroy the creature instead.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[When you've got the temperament of a dragon, every argument is one you'll win.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jaime Jones]]></artist><number><![CDATA[61]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : This checks the colors of permanents you control as it resolves. <br>2/1/2009 : Dark Temper has a self-replacement effect, which applies before other prevention or replacement effects would. If you control a black permanent as Dark Temper resolves, it doesn't deal damage at all (so damage prevention or redirection effects would have no effect); it simply destroys the targeted creature.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[180334]]></id><name><![CDATA[Darklit Gargoyle]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Gargoyle]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>{B}: Darklit Gargoyle gets +2/-1 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It shines in the darkness of its master's ambitions.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Howard Lyon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[7]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179239]]></id><name><![CDATA[Drag Down]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Domain — Target creature gets -1/-1 until end of turn for each basic land type among lands you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The barbarians of Jund believe the bottomless tar pits extend forever into other, darker worlds.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Trevor Claxton]]></artist><number><![CDATA[42]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : To determine the number of basic land types among lands you control, look at the lands you have on the battlefield and ask yourself whether the subtypes Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, and Forest appear within that group. The number of times you say yes (topping out at five) tells you how powerful your domain abilities will be. <br>2/1/2009 : How many lands you control of a particular basic land type is irrelevant to a domain ability, as long as that number is greater than zero. As far as domain is concerned, ten Forests is the same as one Forest. <br>2/1/2009 : A number of nonbasic lands have basic land types. Domain abilities don't count the number of lands you control -- they count the number of basic land types among lands you control, even if that means checking the same land twice. For example, if you control a Tundra, an Overgrown Tomb, and a Madblind Mountain, you'll have a Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, and Forest among the lands you control. Your domain abilities will be maxed out.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[186392]]></id><name><![CDATA[Dragonsoul Knight]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Knight]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[First strike<br>{W}{U}{B}{R}{G}: Until end of turn, Dragonsoul Knight becomes a Dragon, gets +5/+3, and gains flying and trample.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The farther he roamed from Jund and its dragons, the more he felt their essence in himself.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Justin Sweet]]></artist><number><![CDATA[62]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : When Dragonsoul Knight's activated ability resolves, Dragonsoul Knight will gain flying and trample in addition to its other abilities. However, becoming a Dragon will make it lose all other creature types. It will no longer be a Human or a Knight. <br>2/1/2009 : If Dragonsoul Knight gains flying after blockers have been declared, it won't cause those blocks to change. <br>2/1/2009 : You can activate Dragonsoul Knight's ability more than once during a turn. The second time it resolves, it will probably have no visible effect other than giving Dragonsoul Knight another +5/+3.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[159629]]></id><name><![CDATA[Dreadwing]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Zombie]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}{U}{R}: Dreadwing gets +3/+0 and gains flying until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Dreadwings spring from lofty perches to surprise kathari in midflight. They smother their prey and then consume it as they glide gently toward the ground.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mark Hyzer]]></artist><number><![CDATA[43]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[183024]]></id><name><![CDATA[Elder Mastery]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}{B}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature gets +3/+3 and has flying.<br>Whenever enchanted creature deals damage to a player, that player discards two cards.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Taste his power, hunger for his command.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Allsop]]></artist><number><![CDATA[104]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : The last ability triggers from any damage dealt by the enchanted creature, not just combat damage.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[184990]]></id><name><![CDATA[Ember Weaver]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Spider]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Reach (This can block creatures with flying.)<br>As long as you control a red permanent, Ember Weaver gets +1/+0 and has first strike.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Each night, the sun unravels and blows away. Each day, the spiders set a new one in the sky."<br>—Sunseeder myth]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Prescott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[81]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : As long as at least one permanent you control is the specified color, the ability will "work" and grant this creature the bonus. Otherwise, it won't have the bonus. <br>2/1/2009 : Whether Ember Weaver has first strike matters only at the point that the normal combat damage step would begin, and only if there hasn't already been a first-strike combat damage step that turn. If any of your creatures has first strike at that point, a first-strike combat damage step is created.-- If Ember Weaver has first strike at that point, it will assign and deal combat damage during that step (even if it loses first strike before that damage is dealt) and it won't deal combat damage during the normal combat damage step.-- If Ember Weaver doesn't have first strike at that point, it will assign and deal its combat damage during the normal combat damage step (even if it gains first strike before then).]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[184983]]></id><name><![CDATA[Esper Cormorants]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Bird]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The smiths of this land must be mad to reach so far and so high for another creature to decorate."<br>—Cagen Vargan, Jhessian sea scout]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Warren Mahy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[105]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[180158]]></id><name><![CDATA[Esperzoa]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Jellyfish]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>At the beginning of your upkeep, return an artifact you control to its owner's hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The more metal it digests, the more its jelly will fetch on the alchemists' market.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Warren Mahy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[25]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : When Esperzoa's ability resolves, if you control no other artifacts, you'll have to return Esperzoa itself.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[175035]]></id><name><![CDATA[Ethersworn Adjudicator]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Vedalken Knight]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>{1}{W}{B}, {T}: Destroy target creature or enchantment.<br>{2}{U}: Untap Ethersworn Adjudicator.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Esper mages devised their weapons to be so devastating that war seemed unnecessary.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dan Scott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[26]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[189273]]></id><name><![CDATA[Exotic Orchard]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Add to your mana pool one mana of any color that a land an opponent controls could produce.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["It was a strange morning. When we awoke, we found our trees transformed. We didn't know whether to water them or polish them."<br>—Pulan, Bant orchardist]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steven Belledin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[142]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : The colors of mana are white, blue, black, red, and green. Exotic Orchard can't be tapped for colorless mana, even if a land an opponent controls could produce colorless mana. <br>2/1/2009 : Exotic Orchard checks the effects of all mana-producing abilities of lands your opponents control, but it doesn't check their costs. For example, Vivid Crag has the ability "{T}, Remove a charge counter from Vivid Crag: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool." If an opponent controls Vivid Crag and you control Exotic Orchard, you can tap Exotic Orchard for any color of mana. It doesn't matter whether Vivid Crag has a charge counter on it, and it doesn't matter whether it's untapped. <br>2/1/2009 : When determining what colors of mana your opponents' lands could produce, Exotic Orchard takes into account any applicable replacement effects that would apply to those lands' mana abilities (such as Contamination's effect, for example). If there are more than one, consider them in any possible order. <br>2/1/2009 : Exotic Orchard doesn't care about any restrictions or riders your opponents' lands (such as Ancient Ziggurat or Hall of the Bandit Lord) put on the mana they produce. It just cares about colors of mana. <br>2/1/2009 : Lands that produce mana based only on what other lands "could produce" won't help each other unless some other land allows one of them to actually produce some type of mana. For example, if you control an Exotic Orchard and your opponent controls an Exotic Orchard and a Reflecting Pool, none of those lands would produce mana if their mana abilities were activated. On the other hand, if you control a Forest and an Exotic Orchard, and your opponent controls an Exotic Orchard and a Reflecting Pool, then each of those lands can be tapped to produce {G}. Your opponent's Exotic Orchard can produce {G} because you control a Forest. Your Exotic Orchard and your opponent's Reflecting Pool can each produce {G} because your opponent's Exotic Orchard can produce {G}.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[189378]]></id><name><![CDATA[Exploding Borders]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Domain — Search your library for a basic land card, put that card onto the battlefield tapped, then shuffle your library. Exploding Borders deals X damage to target player, where X is the number of basic land types among lands you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Reuniting a world is not a gentle process.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Zoltan Boros & Gabor Szikszai]]></artist><number><![CDATA[106]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : To determine the number of basic land types among lands you control, look at the lands you have on the battlefield and ask yourself whether the subtypes Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, and Forest appear within that group. The number of times you say yes (topping out at five) tells you how powerful your domain abilities will be. <br>2/1/2009 : How many lands you control of a particular basic land type is irrelevant to a domain ability, as long as that number is greater than zero. As far as domain is concerned, ten Forests is the same as one Forest. <br>2/1/2009 : A number of nonbasic lands have basic land types. Domain abilities don't count the number of lands you control -- they count the number of basic land types among lands you control, even if that means checking the same land twice. For example, if you control a Tundra, an Overgrown Tomb, and a Madblind Mountain, you'll have a Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, and Forest among the lands you control. Your domain abilities will be maxed out. <br>2/1/2009 : You do what the spell says in order, so you'll put a new basic land card onto the battlefield before you determine the value of X. <br>2/1/2009 : Exploding Borders will still deal damage even if you don't put a land card onto the battlefield. <br>2/1/2009 : Exploding Borders has only one target: the player. If that player becomes an illegal target by the time Exploding Borders would resolve, the entire spell is countered. You won't get to search for a basic land card.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[189082]]></id><name><![CDATA[Extractor Demon]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Demon]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Whenever another creature leaves the battlefield, you may have target player put the top two cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard.<br>Unearth {2}{B} ({2}{B}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Carl Critchlow]]></artist><number><![CDATA[44]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : If Extractor Demon and another creature leave the battlefield at the same time, Extractor Demon's triggered ability will trigger. <br>2/1/2009 : You can target any player with Extractor Demon's triggered ability. The target doesn't have to be the controller of the creature that left the battlefield.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[182608]]></id><name><![CDATA[Faerie Mechanist]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Faerie Artificer]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>When Faerie Mechanist enters the battlefield, look at the top three cards of your library. You may reveal an artifact card from among them and put it into your hand. Put the rest on the bottom of your library in any order.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Matt Cavotta]]></artist><number><![CDATA[27]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179519]]></id><name><![CDATA[Fiery Fall]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Fiery Fall deals 5 damage to target creature.<br>Basic landcycling {1}{R} ({1}{R}, Discard this card: Search your library for a basic land card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Jund feasts on the unprepared.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Daarken]]></artist><number><![CDATA[63]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Unlike the normal cycling ability, basic landcycling doesn't allow you to draw a card. Instead, it lets you search your library for a basic land card. You don't choose the type of basic land card you'll find until you're performing the search. After you choose a basic land card in your library, you reveal it, put it into your hand, then shuffle your library. <br>2/1/2009 : Basic landcycling is a form of cycling. Any ability that triggers on a card being cycled also triggers on a card being basic landcycled. Any ability that stops a cycling ability from being activated also stops a basic landcycling ability from being activated. <br>2/1/2009 : Basic landcycling is an activated ability. Effects that interact with activated abilities (such as Stifle or Rings of Brighthearth) will interact with basic landcycling. Effects that interact with spells (such as Remove Soul or Faerie Tauntings) will not. <br>2/1/2009 : You can choose not to find a basic land card, even if there is one in your library.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179439]]></id><name><![CDATA[Filigree Fracture]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Destroy target artifact or enchantment. If that permanent was blue or black, draw a card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The sphinx tyrannized Bant until a rhox mage tested the hardiness of her shiny parts.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Howard Lyon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[82]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179884]]></id><name><![CDATA[Fleshformer]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{W}{U}{B}{R}{G}: Fleshformer gets +2/+2 and gains fear until end of turn. Target creature gets -2/-2 until end of turn. Activate this ability only during your turn. (A creature with fear can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Necromancers who discovered the new sources of mana were quick to dream up new nightmares with them.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Kendall]]></artist><number><![CDATA[45]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Fleshformer's ability has only one target: the creature. If that creature becomes an illegal target by the time Fleshformer's ability would resolve, the entire ability is countered. Fleshformer won't get +2/+2 and won't gain fear. <br>2/1/2009 : Fleshformer can target itself with its ability. The result is that Fleshformer gains fear, since the +2/+2 and -2/-2 parts of the effect will balance each other out. (Fleshformer's power and toughness will each momentarily go up by 2, in case anything cares about that.)]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[189147]]></id><name><![CDATA[Font of Mythos]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[At the beginning of each player's draw step, that player draws two additional cards.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Those who drink from Malfegor's cup are tainted with hunger and stained with lies.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Allsop]]></artist><number><![CDATA[136]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>4/15/2013 : The triggered ability is put onto the stack after you have already drawn your card for the turn.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[184993]]></id><name><![CDATA[Frontline Sage]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)<br>{U}, {T}: Draw a card, then discard a card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The battle was won in the commander's head before the first weapon was drawn.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Volkan Baga]]></artist><number><![CDATA[28]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179443]]></id><name><![CDATA[Fusion Elemental]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{W}{U}{B}{R}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[8]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[8]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[As the shards merged into the Maelstrom, their mana energies fused into new monstrosities.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Michael Komarck]]></artist><number><![CDATA[107]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[186614]]></id><name><![CDATA[Giltspire Avenger]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}{W}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)<br>{T}: Destroy target creature that dealt damage to you this turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["To trespass so far from home is to ask for a lonesome grave."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chris Rahn]]></artist><number><![CDATA[108]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179505]]></id><name><![CDATA[Gleam of Resistance]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Creatures you control get +1/+2 until end of turn. Untap those creatures.<br>Basic landcycling {1}{W} ({1}{W}, Discard this card: Search your library for a basic land card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Matt Stewart]]></artist><number><![CDATA[8]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Unlike the normal cycling ability, basic landcycling doesn't allow you to draw a card. Instead, it lets you search your library for a basic land card. You don't choose the type of basic land card you'll find until you're performing the search. After you choose a basic land card in your library, you reveal it, put it into your hand, then shuffle your library. <br>2/1/2009 : Basic landcycling is a form of cycling. Any ability that triggers on a card being cycled also triggers on a card being basic landcycled. Any ability that stops a cycling ability from being activated also stops a basic landcycling ability from being activated. <br>2/1/2009 : Basic landcycling is an activated ability. Effects that interact with activated abilities (such as Stifle or Rings of Brighthearth) will interact with basic landcycling. Effects that interact with spells (such as Remove Soul or Faerie Tauntings) will not. <br>2/1/2009 : You can choose not to find a basic land card, even if there is one in your library.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179512]]></id><name><![CDATA[Gluttonous Slime]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Ooze]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flash<br>Devour 1 (As this enters the battlefield, you may sacrifice any number of creatures. This creature enters the battlefield with that many +1/+1 counters on it.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[On Jund, everything eventually ends up in something else's stomach.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Trevor Claxton]]></artist><number><![CDATA[83]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[185142]]></id><name><![CDATA[Goblin Outlander]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Goblin Scout]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{B}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Protection from white]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Egbol stared in wonder at Naya's landscape. So much to eat. So much to steal.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Trevor Claxton]]></artist><number><![CDATA[109]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179487]]></id><name><![CDATA[Goblin Razerunners]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Goblin Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}{R}, Sacrifice a land: Put a +1/+1 counter on Goblin Razerunners.<br>At the beginning of your end step, you may have Goblin Razerunners deal damage equal to the number of +1/+1 counters on it to target player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Finding themselves in a new and unexplored world, they immediately set it on fire.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Raymond Swanland]]></artist><number><![CDATA[64]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : You don't count how many +1/+1 counters are on Goblin Razerunners until its triggered ability resolves. <br>2/1/2009 : If Goblin Razerunners leaves the battlefield after its ability triggers but before it resolves, the amount of damage it deals is equal to the number of +1/+1 counters that were on it as it last existed on the battlefield.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[177927]]></id><name><![CDATA[Grixis Illusionist]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Target land you control becomes the basic land type of your choice until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["It's simple, really. If they can't find us, they can't kill us."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mark Tedin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[29]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : You choose a basic land type as the ability resolves. <br>2/1/2009 : The affected land loses its existing land types and any abilities printed on it. It becomes the chosen basic land type and now has the ability to tap to add one mana of the appropriate color to your mana pool. Grixis Illusionist's ability doesn't change the affected land's name or whether it's legendary or basic.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179804]]></id><name><![CDATA[Grixis Slavedriver]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Zombie Giant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Grixis Slavedriver leaves the battlefield, put a 2/2 black Zombie creature token onto the battlefield.<br>Unearth {3}{B} ({3}{B}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Kendall]]></artist><number><![CDATA[46]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[185811]]></id><name><![CDATA[Gwafa Hazid, Profiteer]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Human Rogue]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{W}{U}, {T}: Put a bribery counter on target creature you don't control. Its controller draws a card.<br>Creatures with bribery counters on them can't attack or block.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Everyone has a price."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Todd Lockwood]]></artist><number><![CDATA[110]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : If Gwafa Hazid leaves the battlefield, any bribery counters will remain where they are. However, without a Gwafa Hazid on the battlefield, creatures with bribery counters on them can attack and block as normal. If another Gwafa Hazid enters the battlefield, its ability will affect all creatures with bribery counters on them, including the ones that received counters from a different Gwafa Hazid. <br>2/1/2009 : Creatures with bribery counters on them can't be declared as attackers or blockers. However, if a bribery counter is put on a creature that's already been declared as an attacker or blocker, that creature will continue to attack or block that combat.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[189146]]></id><name><![CDATA[Hellkite Hatchling]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Dragon]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Devour 1 (As this enters the battlefield, you may sacrifice any number of creatures. This creature enters the battlefield with that many +1/+1 counters on it.)<br>Hellkite Hatchling has flying and trample if it devoured a creature.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[A killing machine from birth.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Daarken]]></artist><number><![CDATA[111]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Hellkite Hatchling has flying and trample if at least one creature was sacrificed as a result of the Hatchling's devour ability as it entered the battlefield. It retains those abilities even if its +1/+1 counters are somehow removed. <br>2/1/2009 : If another creature becomes a copy of Hellkite Hatchling (due to Mirrorweave, for example), the second ability checks to see whether that creature -- not the original Hellkite Hatchling -- devoured a creature as it entered the battlefield.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[174799]]></id><name><![CDATA[Hellspark Elemental]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample, haste<br>At the beginning of the end step, sacrifice Hellspark Elemental.<br>Unearth {1}{R} ({1}{R}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Justin Sweet]]></artist><number><![CDATA[65]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[183056]]></id><name><![CDATA[Ignite Disorder]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Ignite Disorder deals 3 damage divided as you choose among one, two, or three target white and/or blue creatures.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Bant is a world imprisoned by polished stone and tyrannical rule. It yearns to strike back against those who restrain it."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Zoltan Boros & Gabor Szikszai]]></artist><number><![CDATA[66]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : The number of targets must be at least 1 and at most 3. <br>2/1/2009 : You divide the damage as you cast Ignite Disorder, not as it resolves. Each target must be assigned at least 1 damage. <br>10/1/2009 : The number of targets chosen for Ignite Disorder must be at least 1 and at most 3. You divide the damage as you cast the spell, not as it resolves. Each target must be assigned at least 1 da]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157732]]></id><name><![CDATA[Infectious Horror]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Zombie Horror]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever Infectious Horror attacks, each opponent loses 2 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Not once in the history of Grixis has anyone died of old age.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Pete Venters]]></artist><number><![CDATA[47]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[154081]]></id><name><![CDATA[Inkwell Leviathan]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Leviathan]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{7}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[9]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[7]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[11]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Islandwalk, trample, shroud]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Into its maw went the seventh sea, never to be seen again while the world remains."<br>—Esper fable]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Anthony Francisco]]></artist><number><![CDATA[30]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[174791]]></id><name><![CDATA[Jhessian Balmgiver]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Cleric]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Prevent the next 1 damage that would be dealt to target creature or player this turn.<br>{T}: Target creature is unblockable this turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["You have two choices: heed my advice now or need my healing later."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[David Palumbo]]></artist><number><![CDATA[112]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : If a creature becomes unblockable after blockers have been declared, it won't cause those blocks to change.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[189272]]></id><name><![CDATA[Kaleidostone]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Kaleidostone enters the battlefield, draw a card.<br>{5}, {T}, Sacrifice Kaleidostone: Add {W}{U}{B}{R}{G} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Once broken, who knows what worlds might grow from its shards?]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chippy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[137]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[189080]]></id><name><![CDATA[Kederekt Parasite]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Horror]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever an opponent draws a card, if you control a red permanent, you may have Kederekt Parasite deal 1 damage to that player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[When the smell of passing thoughts piques its hunger, its maw becomes primed with acid and a taste for brains.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dan Scott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[48]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : The "intervening 'if' clause" means that (1) the ability won't trigger at all unless you control a permanent of the specified color, and (2) the ability will do nothing unless you control a permanent of the specified color at the time it resolves.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[189145]]></id><name><![CDATA[Knight of the Reliquary]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Knight]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Knight of the Reliquary gets +1/+1 for each land card in your graveyard.<br>{T}, Sacrifice a Forest or Plains: Search your library for a land card, put it onto the battlefield, then shuffle your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Knowledge of Bant's landscape and ruins is a weapon that the invaders can't comprehend."<br>—Elspeth]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Michael Komarck]]></artist><number><![CDATA[113]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : The activated ability's cost checks the land's subtype, not its name. You can sacrifice a nonbasic land this way as long as it has the subtype Forest or Plains. <br>2/1/2009 : Sacrificing a Forest or Plains is part of the cost of Knight of the Reliquary's activated ability. Assuming that sacrificing the land puts it into your graveyard, Knight of the Reliquary's first ability will immediately give it an additional +1/+1 when that cost is paid because there'll be a new land card in your graveyard. Paying a cost can't be responded to (with Shock, for example). <br>2/1/2009 : Knight of the Reliquary's activated ability lets you find any land card, not just a basic land card.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[180265]]></id><name><![CDATA[Knotvine Mystic]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elf Druid]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{R}{G}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}, {T}: Add {R}{G}{W} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The elves of Naya were the last to acknowledge the massive shift of mana in their world.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ariel Olivetti]]></artist><number><![CDATA[114]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[177940]]></id><name><![CDATA[Kranioceros]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Beast]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}{W}: Kranioceros gets +0/+3 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["A surly beast, the kranioceros will raise its defenses at the smallest threat. Stay out of sight and downwind, or you'll disrupt its natural migrations."<br>—Ebrel, godtoucher mentor]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Argyle]]></artist><number><![CDATA[67]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[175026]]></id><name><![CDATA[Lapse of Certainty]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Counter target spell. If that spell is countered this way, put it on top of its owner's library instead of into that player's graveyard.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Without a connection of mind and body, magic is just an idea stuck in the head, a word on the tip of a tongue.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Anthony Francisco]]></artist><number><![CDATA[9]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[185136]]></id><name><![CDATA[Maelstrom Archangel]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Angel]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{W}{U}{B}{R}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Whenever Maelstrom Archangel deals combat damage to a player, you may cast a nonland card from your hand without paying its mana cost.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[There is no world where angels fear to tread.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Cyril Van Der Haegen]]></artist><number><![CDATA[115]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : If you want to cast a card this way, you cast it as part of the resolution of Maelstrom Angel's triggered ability. Timing restrictions based on the card's type (such as creature or sorcery) are ignored. Other casting restrictions are not (such as "Cast [this card] only before attackers are declared"). <br>2/1/2009 : If you cast a card this way, you're casting it as a spell. It can be countered. <br>2/1/2009 : If you cast a card with X in its cost this way, X must be 0. <br>2/1/2009 : If you cast a card "without paying its mana cost," you can't pay any alternative costs, such as evoke or the alternative cost provided by the morph ability. However, you can pay optional additional costs, such as conspire, and you must still pay mandatory additional costs, such as the one on Goldmeadow Stalwart.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179892]]></id><name><![CDATA[Magister Sphinx]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Sphinx]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{W}{U}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>When Magister Sphinx enters the battlefield, target player's life total becomes 10.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["These benighted worlds are thick with ignorance. I will educate them. They will listen, or they will die."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steven Belledin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[116]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : This ability is not optional. <br>2/1/2009 : For a player's life total to become 10, what actually happens is that the player gains or loses the appropriate amount of life. For example, if the targeted player's life total is 4 when this ability resolves, it will cause that player to gain 6 life; alternately, if the targeted player's life total is 17 when this ability resolves, it will cause that player to lose 7 life. Other cards that interact with life gain or life loss will interact with this effect accordingly. <br>6/15/2010 : In a Two-Headed Giant game, this ability basically causes the team's life total to become 10, but only the targeted player is considered to have actually gained or lost life.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[185812]]></id><name><![CDATA[Malfegor]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Demon Dragon]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{B}{B}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>When Malfegor enters the battlefield, discard your hand. Each opponent sacrifices a creature for each card discarded this way.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[A demon cannot be trusted, and a dragon will not be ruled.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jason Chan]]></artist><number><![CDATA[117]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : This ability is not optional. You must discard your entire hand no matter how many creatures your opponents control. <br>2/1/2009 : After you discard your hand and the number of creatures each opponent must sacrifice has been determined, each opponent in turn order, starting with the player whose turn it is if that player is your opponent, chooses which creatures he or she will sacrifice, then all the chosen creatures are all sacrificed at the same time.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[189269]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mana Cylix]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}, {T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Those who dismiss the cylix as an ordinary wooden bowl are blind to the true measure of its worth.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Howard Lyon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[138]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[180159]]></id><name><![CDATA[Manaforce Mace]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact — Equipment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Domain — Equipped creature gets +1/+1 for each basic land type among lands you control.<br>Equip {3}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[As the shards merged, relics once thought mundane regained forgotten powers.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jeremy Jarvis]]></artist><number><![CDATA[139]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : To determine the number of basic land types among lands you control, look at the lands you have on the battlefield and ask yourself whether the subtypes Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, and Forest appear within that group. The number of times you say yes (topping out at five) tells you how powerful your domain abilities will be. <br>2/1/2009 : How many lands you control of a particular basic land type is irrelevant to a domain ability, as long as that number is greater than zero. As far as domain is concerned, ten Forests is the same as one Forest. <br>2/1/2009 : A number of nonbasic lands have basic land types. Domain abilities don't count the number of lands you control -- they count the number of basic land types among lands you control, even if that means checking the same land twice. For example, if you control a Tundra, an Overgrown Tomb, and a Madblind Mountain, you'll have a Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, and Forest among the lands you control. Your domain abilities will be maxed out.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[182609]]></id><name><![CDATA[Maniacal Rage]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 and can't block.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The spikes of sangrite made the goblin stronger, but they didn't make him any smarter.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Brandon Kitkouski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[68]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[186615]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mark of Asylum]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Prevent all noncombat damage that would be dealt to creatures you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[A paragon of honor, Galo Aher fell to a blast of fire. The Order of the White Orchid was so saddened that they forged a new sigil in his likeness.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Sal Villagran]]></artist><number><![CDATA[10]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : "Noncombat damage" is damage dealt as the result of a spell or ability. (In unusual cases involving a card like Words of War, noncombat damage can also be dealt as the result of a turn-based action.)]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[178560]]></id><name><![CDATA[Martial Coup]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{X}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Put X 1/1 white Soldier creature tokens onto the battlefield. If X is 5 or more, destroy all other creatures.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Their war forgotten, the nations of Bant stood united in the face of a common threat.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Greg Staples]]></artist><number><![CDATA[11]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Martial Coup checks the number you chose for X, not the amount of mana you actually spent. <br>2/1/2009 : You do what the spell says in order. If X is 5 or more, you'll put the Soldier tokens onto the battlefield, then you'll destroy all other creatures. <br>2/1/2009 : No one can cast spells or activate abilities between the time the Soldier tokens are put onto the battlefield and the time all other creatures are destroyed. For example, you can't sacrifice one of those Soldier tokens to regenerate a Skeletal Kathari.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179252]]></id><name><![CDATA[Master Transmuter]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Human Artificer]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{U}, {T}, Return an artifact you control to its owner's hand: You may put an artifact card from your hand onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Wasted potential surrounds us. Lend me that bauble, and let me see what it can be made to be."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chippy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[31]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Returning an artifact you control to its owner's hand is part of the cost of Master Transmuter's activated ability. Paying a cost can't be responded to (with Naturalize, for example). <br>2/1/2009 : Since Master Transmuter is an artifact, you may return Master Transmuter itself to your hand. If you do, the rest of the ability will still work normally. <br>2/1/2009 : The artifact card you put onto the battlefield when the ability resolves may be the same card that you returned to your hand when you paid the cost. If so, it returns to the battlefield as a new object with no relation to its previous existence.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179248]]></id><name><![CDATA[Matca Rioters]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[*]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[*]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Domain — Matca Rioters's power and toughness are each equal to the number of basic land types among lands you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[When outsiders interrupted the matca championship, things got ugly.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Argyle]]></artist><number><![CDATA[84]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : To determine the number of basic land types among lands you control, look at the lands you have on the battlefield and ask yourself whether the subtypes Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, and Forest appear within that group. The number of times you say yes (topping out at five) tells you how powerful your domain abilities will be. <br>2/1/2009 : How many lands you control of a particular basic land type is irrelevant to a domain ability, as long as that number is greater than zero. As far as domain is concerned, ten Forests is the same as one Forest. <br>2/1/2009 : A number of nonbasic lands have basic land types. Domain abilities don't count the number of lands you control -- they count the number of basic land types among lands you control, even if that means checking the same land twice. For example, if you control a Tundra, an Overgrown Tomb, and a Madblind Mountain, you'll have a Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, and Forest among the lands you control. Your domain abilities will be maxed out. <br>2/1/2009 : Matca Rioters' ability is a "characteristic-defining ability." It applies at all times in all zones.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179886]]></id><name><![CDATA[Meglonoth]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Beast]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{R}{G}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Vigilance, trample<br>Whenever Meglonoth blocks a creature, Meglonoth deals damage to that creature's controller equal to Meglonoth's power.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[When the shards merged, Mayael found herself the general of Naya's mightiest army.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Prescott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[118]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : You don't check Meglonoth's power until its triggered ability resolves. <br>2/1/2009 : If Meglonoth leaves the battlefield after its ability triggers but before it resolves, the amount of damage it deals is equal to its power as it last existed on the battlefield. <br>2/1/2009 : If Meglonoth somehow blocks more than one creature, its ability will trigger once for each creature it blocks.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[150810]]></id><name><![CDATA[Might of Alara]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Domain — Target creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn for each basic land type among lands you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The combined strength of all five planes spawned creations none had seen before.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Prescott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[85]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : To determine the number of basic land types among lands you control, look at the lands you have on the battlefield and ask yourself whether the subtypes Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, and Forest appear within that group. The number of times you say yes (topping out at five) tells you how powerful your domain abilities will be. <br>2/1/2009 : How many lands you control of a particular basic land type is irrelevant to a domain ability, as long as that number is greater than zero. As far as domain is concerned, ten Forests is the same as one Forest. <br>2/1/2009 : A number of nonbasic lands have basic land types. Domain abilities don't count the number of lands you control -- they count the number of basic land types among lands you control, even if that means checking the same land twice. For example, if you control a Tundra, an Overgrown Tomb, and a Madblind Mountain, you'll have a Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, and Forest among the lands you control. Your domain abilities will be maxed out.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[158598]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mirror-Sigil Sergeant]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Rhino Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample<br>At the beginning of your upkeep, if you control a blue permanent, you may put a token that's a copy of Mirror-Sigil Sergeant onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["If I had many lives, I would give them all for Bant."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chris Rahn]]></artist><number><![CDATA[12]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : The "intervening 'if' clause" means that (1) the ability won't trigger at all unless you control a permanent of the specified color, and (2) the ability will do nothing unless you control a permanent of the specified color at the time it resolves. <br>2/1/2009 : Normally, when a token is created by this ability, it will simply be a Mirror-Sigil Sergeant, so it'll also have the token-creating ability. (See the other ruling for weird exceptions.) At the beginning of your next upkeep, if you still control the original Sergeant, the token copy, and a blue permanent, you'll get two more token copies; the turn after that you'll get four; then eight; and so on. <br>2/1/2009 : Here's the detailed version of what happens. As the token is created, it checks the printed values of the Mirror-Sigil Sergeant it's copying -- or, if the Mirror-Sigil Sergeant whose ability triggered was itself a token, the original characteristics of that token as stated by the effect that put it onto the battlefield -- as well as any copy effects that have been applied to it. It won't copy counters on the Mirror-Sigil Sergeant, nor will it copy other effects that have changed Mirror-Sigil Sergeant's power, toughness, types, color, or so on. <br>2/1/2009 : If Mirror-Sigil Sergeant has left the battlefield by the time its triggered ability resolves, you'll still put a token onto the battlefield. That token has the copiable values of the characteristics of Mirror-Sigil Sergeant as it last existed on the battlefield. <br>2/1/2009 : Here are the weird exceptions. If any copy effects have affected the Mirror-Sigil Sergeant whose ability triggered, they're taken into account when the token is created. For example:-- If Mirror-Sigil Sergeant's ability triggers, then Mirror-Sigil Sergeant temporarily becomes a copy of another creature before its ability resolves (due to Mirrorweave, perhaps), the token will be a copy of whatever creature the Mirror-Sigil Sergeant is currently a copy of. After the turn ends, the Mirrorweaved Mirror-Sigil Sergeant reverts back to what it was, but the token will stay as it is.-- If the copy ability of a creature (such as Cemetery Puca, perhaps) makes it become a copy of Mirror-Sigil Sergeant and gain another ability, the token created by this creature at the beginning of your upkeep will be a Mirror-Sigil Sergeant with that additional ability.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[184988]]></id><name><![CDATA[Molten Frame]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Destroy target artifact creature.<br>Cycling {2} ({2}, Discard this card: Draw a card.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The metal filigree in his body glowed red-hot, and his flesh soon followed.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Izzy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[69]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2008 : Cycling is an activated ability. Effects that interact with activated abilities (such as Stifle or Rings of Brighthearth) will interact with cycling. Effects that interact with spells (such as Remove Soul or Faerie Tauntings) will not. <br>2/1/2009 : Any permanent that's both an artifact and a creature is a legal target for Molten Frame.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[138571]]></id><name><![CDATA[Nacatl Hunt-Pride]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Cat Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Vigilance<br>{R}, {T}: Target creature can't block this turn.<br>{G}, {T}: Target creature blocks this turn if able.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["We must hunt and kill the dragon before it can return to raze our ancient city."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Prescott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[13]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : If either ability is activated after blockers have been declared, it won't cause those blocks to change. <br>2/1/2009 : If you attack with Nacatl Hunt-Pride, you get the chance to activate one of its abilities before blockers are declared.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[185140]]></id><name><![CDATA[Nacatl Outlander]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Cat Scout]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{R}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Protection from blue]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Survival in the wilds of Naya left Tiyan well equipped to win the civilized battles of Bant.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Zoltan Boros & Gabor Szikszai]]></artist><number><![CDATA[119]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[183022]]></id><name><![CDATA[Nacatl Savage]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Cat Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Protection from artifacts]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Blades dull and armor dents. Marisi taught us that instinct is the only thing a true warrior needs."<br>—Ajani]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Parente]]></artist><number><![CDATA[86]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : "Protection from artifacts" means the following:-- Nacatl Savage can't be blocked by artifact creatures.-- Nacatl Savage can't be equipped. It also can't be enchanted by Auras that have somehow become artifacts in addition to enchantments.-- Nacatl Savage can't be targeted by abilities from artifact sources.-- All damage that would be dealt to Nacatl Savage by artifact sources is prevented.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179441]]></id><name><![CDATA[Nicol Bolas, Planeswalker]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Planeswalker — Bolas]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{U}{B}{B}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[8]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[5]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[+3: Destroy target noncreature permanent.<br>-2: Gain control of target creature.<br>-9: Nicol Bolas, Planeswalker deals 7 damage to target player. That player discards seven cards, then sacrifices seven permanents.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[D. Alexander Gregory]]></artist><number><![CDATA[120]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : The control-change effect has no duration. It will last until the game ends or the affected creature leaves the battlefield. It may be superseded by a later control-change effect. <br>7/1/2012 : If the damage from Nicol Bolas's third ability is prevented or redirected, the rest of the effect will still happen. Specifically, the number of cards discarded and permanents sacrificed isn't tied to the amount of damage dealt. <br>7/1/2012 : For the third ability, if the player is an illegal target when the ability tries to resolve, the ability is countered and none of its effects will happen. No damage will be dealt, no cards will be discarded, and no permanents will be sacrificed.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179434]]></id><name><![CDATA[Noble Hierarch]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Druid]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)<br>{T}: Add {G}, {W}, or {U} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[She protects the sacred groves from blight, drought, and the Unbeholden.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mark Zug]]></artist><number><![CDATA[87]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[186616]]></id><name><![CDATA[Nyxathid]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[7]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[7]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[As Nyxathid enters the battlefield, choose an opponent.<br>Nyxathid gets -1/-1 for each card in the chosen player's hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Born of volcanic forces, it thrives on the absolute panic it inspires.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Raymond Swanland]]></artist><number><![CDATA[49]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Nyxathid tracks the hand size of the chosen player even if that player ceases to be an opponent of its controller. (This could happen if that player gains control of Nyxathid, for example.) <br>2/1/2009 : In a multiplayer game, if the chosen player leaves the game, Nyxathid's second ability simply won't do anything anymore. <br>2/1/2009 : Nyxathid's two abilities are linked: The second one refers only to the player chosen by the first one. If another creature becomes a copy of Nyxathid (due to Mirrorweave, for example), the second ability won't do anything because a player was never chosen as a result of the first ability. This is true even if a different ability allowed a player to be chosen as that creature entered the battlefield. <br>2/1/2009 : If a spell or ability causes the chosen player to draw cards and then discard cards, Nyxathid's power and toughness changes accordingly as that spell or ability is resolving. For example, if the chosen player has five cards in hand and a spell causes that player to draw two cards then discard two cards, Nyxathid will start out as 2/2, then become 1/1, 0/0, and finally 2/2. This is because cards are always drawn one at a time, but multiple cards may be discarded at once. Although Nyxathid momentarily had 0 toughness while that spell was resolving, it isn't put into its owner's graveyard as a state-based action because state-based actions aren't checked until the spell has finished resolving.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[183018]]></id><name><![CDATA[Obelisk of Alara]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{6}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}{W}, {T}: You gain 5 life.<br>{1}{U}, {T}: Draw a card, then discard a card.<br>{1}{B}, {T}: Target creature gets -2/-2 until end of turn.<br>{1}{R}, {T}: Obelisk of Alara deals 3 damage to target player.<br>{1}{G}, {T}: Target creature gets +4/+4 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jeremy Jarvis]]></artist><number><![CDATA[140]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[189873]]></id><name><![CDATA[Paleoloth]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Beast]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever another creature with power 5 or greater enters the battlefield under your control, you may return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Gods do not sleep soundly in the earth's embrace."<br>—Mayael the Anima]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Christopher Moeller]]></artist><number><![CDATA[88]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : If Paleoloth and another creature with power 5 or greater enter the battlefield under your control at the same time, Paleoloth's triggered ability will trigger.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179878]]></id><name><![CDATA[Paragon of the Amesha]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Knight]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[First strike<br>{W}{U}{B}{R}{G}: Until end of turn, Paragon of the Amesha becomes an Angel, gets +3/+3, and gains flying and lifelink.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Let my lance sing with the voices of angels and the heathen cower before my shield, for I will teach this land the meaning of honor."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chris Rahn]]></artist><number><![CDATA[14]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : When Paragon of the Amesha's activated ability resolves, Paragon of the Amesha will gain flying and lifelink in addition to its other abilities. However, becoming an Angel will make it lose all other creature types. It will no longer be a Human or a Knight. <br>2/1/2009 : If Paragon of the Amesha gains flying after blockers have been declared, it won't cause those blocks to change. <br>10/1/2009 : You can activate Paragon of the Amesha's ability more than once during a turn. The second time it resolves, it will get another +3/+3 and gain another instance of lifelink. However, multiple instances of lifelink are redundant so you won't gain extra life from the new one.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[175021]]></id><name><![CDATA[Parasitic Strix]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Bird]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>When Parasitic Strix enters the battlefield, if you control a black permanent, target player loses 2 life and you gain 2 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[After finding no sustenance on the edges of Grixis, it turned to the skies of Bant.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steven Belledin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[32]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : The "intervening 'if' clause" means that (1) the ability won't trigger at all unless you control a permanent of the specified color, and (2) the ability will do nothing unless you control a permanent of the specified color at the time it resolves.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179235]]></id><name><![CDATA[Path to Exile]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Exile target creature. Its controller may search his or her library for a basic land card, put that card onto the battlefield tapped, then shuffle his or her library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Todd Lockwood]]></artist><number><![CDATA[15]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : If the targeted creature becomes an illegal target by the time Path to Exile would resolve, the entire spell is countered. The creature's controller won't get to search for a basic land card.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179518]]></id><name><![CDATA[Pestilent Kathari]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Bird Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Deathtouch (Any amount of damage this deals to a creature is enough to destroy it.)<br>{2}{R}: Pestilent Kathari gains first strike until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Kendall]]></artist><number><![CDATA[50]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179496]]></id><name><![CDATA[Progenitus]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Hydra Avatar]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{W}{W}{U}{U}{B}{B}{R}{R}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[10]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[10]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[10]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Protection from everything<br>If Progenitus would be put into a graveyard from anywhere, reveal Progenitus and shuffle it into its owner's library instead.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The Soul of the World has returned.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jaime Jones]]></artist><number><![CDATA[121]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : "Protection from everything" means the following:-- Progenitus can't be blocked.-- Progenitus can't be enchanted or equipped.-- Progenitus can't be the target of spells or abilities.-- All damage that would be dealt to Progenitus is prevented. <br>2/1/2009 : Progenitus can still be affected by effects that don't target it or deal damage to it (such as Wrath of God).]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179440]]></id><name><![CDATA[Quenchable Fire]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Quenchable Fire deals 3 damage to target player. It deals an additional 3 damage to that player at the beginning of your next upkeep step unless he or she pays {U} before that step.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[You'd better know how to pray for rain.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jean-Sébastien Rossbach]]></artist><number><![CDATA[70]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : After Quenchable Fire resolves, the targeted player becomes able to perform a special action of paying {U}. This action may be performed any time the player has priority, and it doesn't use the stack. It may be performed only once, and only before your next upkeep begins. If the player has performed the action by then, the "deal an additional 3 damage" ability won't trigger. Otherwise, it will. If it triggers, the player can't stop it by paying {U}. <br>2/1/2009 : Quenchable Fire's delayed triggered ability (and the special action of paying {U}) will affect the player who was targeted by the spell, even if the original 3 damage is prevented or redirected to a different creature or player.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[185810]]></id><name><![CDATA[Rakka Mar]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Human Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Haste<br>{R}, {T}: Put a 3/1 red Elemental creature token with haste onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The finest pawns are those with pawns of their own."<br>—Nicol Bolas]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jason Chan]]></artist><number><![CDATA[71]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[150807]]></id><name><![CDATA[Reliquary Tower]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[You have no maximum hand size.<br>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[When the aven scouts located the tower in Esper, the Knights of the Reliquary set off on a righteous crusade to recover their lost treasures.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jesper Ejsing]]></artist><number><![CDATA[143]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : If multiple effects modify your hand size, apply them in timestamp order. For example, if you put Null Profusion (an enchantment that says your maximum hand size is two) onto the battlefield and then put Reliquary Tower onto the battlefield, you'll have no maximum hand size. However, if those permanents enter the battlefield in the opposite order, your maximum hand size would be two.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[177924]]></id><name><![CDATA[Rhox Bodyguard]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Rhino Monk Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{G}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)<br>When Rhox Bodyguard enters the battlefield, you gain 3 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[An enlightened soul caged in a body made for battle.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Sal Villagran]]></artist><number><![CDATA[122]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[159634]]></id><name><![CDATA[Rhox Meditant]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Rhino Monk]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Rhox Meditant enters the battlefield, if you control a green permanent, draw a card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The weight of her conviction balances on the harmony of her soul.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Donato Giancola]]></artist><number><![CDATA[16]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : The "intervening 'if' clause" means that (1) the ability won't trigger at all unless you control a permanent of the specified color, and (2) the ability will do nothing unless you control a permanent of the specified color at the time it resolves.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[150833]]></id><name><![CDATA[Rotting Rats]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Zombie Rat]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Rotting Rats enters the battlefield, each player discards a card.<br>Unearth {1}{B} ({1}{B}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Allsop]]></artist><number><![CDATA[51]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : When Rotting Rats's enters-the-battlefield ability resolves, first the player whose turn it is chooses a card to discard, then each other player in turn order does the same, then all cards are discarded at the same time. No one sees what the other players are discarding before deciding which card to discard.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[142301]]></id><name><![CDATA[Rupture Spire]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Rupture Spire enters the battlefield tapped.<br>When Rupture Spire enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you pay {1}.<br>{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jaime Jones]]></artist><number><![CDATA[144]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179488]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sacellum Archers]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elf Archer]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{R}{W}, {T}: Sacellum Archers deals 2 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Our arrows are aimed not at the sacred behemoths but at those who dare to dream of such a trophy."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kev Walker]]></artist><number><![CDATA[89]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179254]]></id><name><![CDATA[Salvage Slasher]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Human Rogue]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Salvage Slasher gets +1/+0 for each artifact card in your graveyard.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Esper artificers never imagined that one day their scraps would be pressed against their soft and fragile throats.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Anthony Francisco]]></artist><number><![CDATA[52]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[183025]]></id><name><![CDATA[Scarland Thrinax]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Lizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{B}{R}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Sacrifice a creature: Put a +1/+1 counter on Scarland Thrinax.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["There is only one way of life in Jund: feed on the weak until you are cut down by something stronger."<br>—Jorshu of Clan Nel Toth]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Daarken]]></artist><number><![CDATA[123]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[185828]]></id><name><![CDATA[Scattershot Archer]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elf Archer]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Scattershot Archer deals 1 damage to each creature with flying.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[To train her elves for war, Mayael would drop a sackful of acorns from the tree canopy. Each archer tried to split as many as possible before the acorns hit the forest floor below.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Argyle]]></artist><number><![CDATA[90]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[174792]]></id><name><![CDATA[Scepter of Dominance]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{W}, {T}: Tap target permanent.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Whether or not you will bow to me is not open to debate. The question is, will I ever let you rise?"<br>—Fridius, telemin master]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Howard Lyon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[17]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[189084]]></id><name><![CDATA[Scepter of Fugue]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}{B}, {T}: Target player discards a card. Activate this ability only during your turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[One goes to Tidehollow either to forget or to be forgotten. Either way, the scullers will oblige.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Franz Vohwinkel]]></artist><number><![CDATA[53]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[184989]]></id><name><![CDATA[Scepter of Insight]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{3}{U}, {T}: Draw a card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The road to truth has many branches, and so must the cane with which I walk it."<br>—Voln the Elder]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steven Belledin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[33]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[186328]]></id><name><![CDATA[Scornful Æther-Lich]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Zombie Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{W}{B}: Scornful Æther-Lich gains fear and vigilance until end of turn. (Attacking doesn't cause it to tap, and it can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["With no flesh, there is no pain, no hesitation, no emotion of any kind. He is crafted perfection."<br>—Tezzeret]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steven Belledin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[34]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[182306]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sedraxis Alchemist]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Zombie Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Sedraxis Alchemist enters the battlefield, if you control a blue permanent, return target nonland permanent to its owner's hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The problem with a liquid that can dissolve anything is finding something to carry it in.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Karl Kopinski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[54]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : The "intervening 'if' clause" means that (1) the ability won't trigger at all unless you control a permanent of the specified color, and (2) the ability will do nothing unless you control a permanent of the specified color at the time it resolves. <br>2/1/2009 : This ability isn't optional. When Sedraxis Alchemist enters the battlefield, if you control a blue permanent and no other player controls a nonland permanent, you'll have to target a nonland permanent you control.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[184991]]></id><name><![CDATA[Shambling Remains]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Zombie Horror]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Shambling Remains can't block.<br>Unearth {B}{R} ({B}{R}: Return this card from your graveyard to the battlefield. It gains haste. Exile it at the beginning of the next end step or if it would leave the battlefield. Unearth only as a sorcery.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Nils Hamm]]></artist><number><![CDATA[124]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[175034]]></id><name><![CDATA[Shard Convergence]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Search your library for a Plains card, an Island card, a Swamp card, and a Mountain card. Reveal those cards and put them into your hand. Then shuffle your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Alara is broken no more.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Vance Kovacs]]></artist><number><![CDATA[91]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : You don't have to find all four cards. <br>2/1/2009 : Shard Convergence checks for cards with the subtypes Plains, Island, Swamp, and Mountain, not for cards with those names. You may find nonbasic land cards this way, as long as they have appropriate subtypes. <br>2/1/2009 : You may find "dual lands" with Shard Convergence. The Plains card you find, for example, can have a second subtype. What subtypes it has won't impact what other cards you can find. For example, you may find a Hallowed Fountain (which has subtypes Plains and Island) as the Plains card, and another Hallowed Fountain as the Island card.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[180271]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sigil of the Empty Throne]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever you cast an enchantment spell, put a 4/4 white Angel creature token with flying onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[When Asha left Bant, she ensured that the world would have protection and order in her absence.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Cyril Van Der Haegen]]></artist><number><![CDATA[18]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : The triggered ability will resolve before the enchantment spell that caused it to trigger. <br>2/1/2009 : When you cast an Aura spell, you have to choose a target for it before this ability puts an Angel token onto the battlefield. In other words, you can't play an Aura spell intending to enchant the Angel that will be created as a result. <br>2/1/2009 : Casting Sigil of the Empty Throne won't trigger its own ability. It has to be on the battlefield for its ability to work.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[174953]]></id><name><![CDATA[Skyward Eye Prophets]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{G}{W}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Vigilance<br>{T}: Reveal the top card of your library. If it's a land card, put it onto the battlefield. Otherwise, put it into your hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[They lament the doom that is coming to Bant without realizing the part their own leaders have played in it.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Matt Stewart]]></artist><number><![CDATA[125]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[183019]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sludge Strider]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Insect]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}{U}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever another artifact enters the battlefield under your control or another artifact you control leaves the battlefield, you may pay {1}. If you do, target player loses 1 life and you gain 1 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Underneath the cities of Esper are cycles of life unseen by those who feed them.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Franz Vohwinkel]]></artist><number><![CDATA[126]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : If Sludge Strider and another artifact enter the battlefield under your control at the same time, Sludge Strider's triggered ability will trigger. Similarly, if Sludge Strider and another artifact you control leave the battlefield at the same time, Sludge Strider's triggered ability will trigger. <br>2/1/2009 : If an artifact creature with 0 toughness enters the battlefield under your control, Sludge Strider's ability will trigger a total of twice: Once when that creature enters the battlefield, and once when it's put into a graveyard. Both abilities will be put on the stack after the state-based action check that puts the 0-toughness creature into the graveyard is finished.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[185137]]></id><name><![CDATA[Soul's Majesty]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Draw cards equal to the power of target creature you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[An avatar he sculpts of wisdom and strength.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jesper Ejsing]]></artist><number><![CDATA[92]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Soul's Majesty's only target is the creature. If that creature becomes an illegal target by the time Soul's Majesty would resolve, the entire spell is countered. You won't draw any cards.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[189079]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sphinx Summoner]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Sphinx]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>When Sphinx Summoner enters the battlefield, you may search your library for an artifact creature card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. If you do, shuffle your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jaime Jones]]></artist><number><![CDATA[127]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : The card you find must be both an artifact and a creature.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[185829]]></id><name><![CDATA[Spore Burst]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Domain — Put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield for each basic land type among lands you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Seeds from Jund don't drift gently on the wind. They get up and stampede.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Daarken]]></artist><number><![CDATA[93]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : To determine the number of basic land types among lands you control, look at the lands you have on the battlefield and ask yourself whether the subtypes Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, and Forest appear within that group. The number of times you say yes (topping out at five) tells you how powerful your domain abilities will be. <br>2/1/2009 : How many lands you control of a particular basic land type is irrelevant to a domain ability, as long as that number is greater than zero. As far as domain is concerned, ten Forests is the same as one Forest. <br>2/1/2009 : A number of nonbasic lands have basic land types. Domain abilities don't count the number of lands you control -- they count the number of basic land types among lands you control, even if that means checking the same land twice. For example, if you control a Tundra, an Overgrown Tomb, and a Madblind Mountain, you'll have a Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, and Forest among the lands you control. Your domain abilities will be maxed out.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[180345]]></id><name><![CDATA[Suicidal Charge]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{B}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Sacrifice Suicidal Charge: Creatures your opponents control get -1/-1 until end of turn. Those creatures attack this turn if able.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["They think they're winning. But they're just lining up to be dinner."<br>—Rakka Mar]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Daarken]]></artist><number><![CDATA[128]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Suicidal Charge's ability affects only the creatures your opponents control at the time it resolves. If another creature comes under the control of one of those players by the time that turn's combat step begins, it won't have to attack.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179523]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sylvan Bounty]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target player gains 8 life.<br>Basic landcycling {1}{G} ({1}{G}, Discard this card: Search your library for a basic land card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Some who scouted new lands chose to stay.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chris Rahn]]></artist><number><![CDATA[94]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Unlike the normal cycling ability, basic landcycling doesn't allow you to draw a card. Instead, it lets you search your library for a basic land card. You don't choose the type of basic land card you'll find until you're performing the search. After you choose a basic land card in your library, you reveal it, put it into your hand, then shuffle your library. <br>2/1/2009 : Basic landcycling is a form of cycling. Any ability that triggers on a card being cycled also triggers on a card being basic landcycled. Any ability that stops a cycling ability from being activated also stops a basic landcycling ability from being activated. <br>2/1/2009 : Basic landcycling is an activated ability. Effects that interact with activated abilities (such as Stifle or Rings of Brighthearth) will interact with basic landcycling. Effects that interact with spells (such as Remove Soul or Faerie Tauntings) will not. <br>2/1/2009 : You can choose not to find a basic land card, even if there is one in your library.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[189085]]></id><name><![CDATA[Telemin Performance]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target opponent reveals cards from the top of his or her library until he or she reveals a creature card. That player puts all noncreature cards revealed this way into his or her graveyard, then you put the creature card onto the battlefield under your control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Izzy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[35]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : If there are no creature cards in the targeted opponent's library, that player will put his or her entire library into his or her graveyard.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[180341]]></id><name><![CDATA[Thornling]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental Shapeshifter]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{G}: Thornling gains haste until end of turn.<br>{G}: Thornling gains trample until end of turn.<br>{G}: Thornling is indestructible this turn.<br>{1}: Thornling gets +1/-1 until end of turn.<br>{1}: Thornling gets -1/+1 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kev Walker]]></artist><number><![CDATA[95]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Lethal damage and effects that say "destroy" won't cause an indestructible creature to be put into the graveyard. However, an indestructible creature can be put into the graveyard for a number of reasons. The most likely reasons are if it's sacrificed, if it's legendary and another legendary creature with the same name is on the battlefield, or if its toughness is 0 or less.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[170956]]></id><name><![CDATA[Toxic Iguanar]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Lizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Toxic Iguanar has deathtouch as long as you control a green permanent. (Any amount of damage a creature with deathtouch deals to a creature is enough to destroy it.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[There are no "weak" creatures on Jund. Even the smallest can strike a deadly blow.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Brandon Kitkouski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[72]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : As long as at least one permanent you control is the specified color, the ability will "work" and grant this creature the bonus. Otherwise, it won't have the bonus. <br>2/1/2009 : Whether Toxic Iguanar has deathtouch matters only when it deals damage (that is, at the point when its combat damage resolves, or at the point when a spell or ability that causes it to deal damage resolves). For example, if your only green permanent is a creature that receives lethal damage at the same time Toxic Iguanar deals damage to a creature, the deathtouch ability will still apply and the creature Toxic Iguanar dealt damage to will be destroyed.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179508]]></id><name><![CDATA[Traumatic Visions]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Counter target spell.<br>Basic landcycling {1}{U} ({1}{U}, Discard this card: Search your library for a basic land card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Cyril Van Der Haegen]]></artist><number><![CDATA[36]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Unlike the normal cycling ability, basic landcycling doesn't allow you to draw a card. Instead, it lets you search your library for a basic land card. You don't choose the type of basic land card you'll find until you're performing the search. After you choose a basic land card in your library, you reveal it, put it into your hand, then shuffle your library. <br>2/1/2009 : Basic landcycling is a form of cycling. Any ability that triggers on a card being cycled also triggers on a card being basic landcycled. Any ability that stops a cycling ability from being activated also stops a basic landcycling ability from being activated. <br>2/1/2009 : Basic landcycling is an activated ability. Effects that interact with activated abilities (such as Stifle or Rings of Brighthearth) will interact with basic landcycling. Effects that interact with spells (such as Remove Soul or Faerie Tauntings) will not. <br>2/1/2009 : You can choose not to find a basic land card, even if there is one in your library.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[184995]]></id><name><![CDATA[Tukatongue Thallid]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Fungus]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Tukatongue Thallid dies, put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Jund's thallids tried to disguise their deliciousness by covering themselves in spines harvested from the tukatongue tree.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Vance Kovacs]]></artist><number><![CDATA[96]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[189078]]></id><name><![CDATA[Unstable Frontier]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.<br>{T}: Target land you control becomes the basic land type of your choice until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The goblins went to sleep in Jund and awoke in Grixis. They'd never seen a zombie before. They would never see one again.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[John Avon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[145]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : You choose a basic land type as the ability resolves. <br>2/1/2009 : The affected land loses its existing land types and any abilities printed on it. It becomes the chosen basic land type and now has the ability to tap to add one mana of the appropriate color to your mana pool. Unstable Frontier's ability doesn't change the affected land's name or whether it's legendary or basic.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[177932]]></id><name><![CDATA[Unsummon]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Return target creature to its owner's hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Send it back to its own strange world so we can avoid another inglorious combat with these wicked beings."<br>—Captain Valek of Jhess]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Izzy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[37]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[180344]]></id><name><![CDATA[Vagrant Plowbeasts]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Beast]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{G}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}: Regenerate target creature with power 5 or greater.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Plowbeasts of Naya escaped their harnesses in droves, content to snack on the conveniently cultivated fields of Eos and Valeron.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Zoltan Boros & Gabor Szikszai]]></artist><number><![CDATA[129]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : This ability checks the targeted creature's power only at the time the ability is activated and at the time it resolves. The regeneration shield it creates will work no matter what that creature's power is at the time it would be destroyed.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[185144]]></id><name><![CDATA[Valeron Outlander]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Scout]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Protection from black]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[After years of honing her philosophy in debate with stubborn rhoxes, Niella was ready to convert any heathen.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Matt Stewart]]></artist><number><![CDATA[130]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[184984]]></id><name><![CDATA[Valiant Guard]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[As the outsiders invaded Bant, soldiers who once saw sigils as the highest marks of glory began to see the scars of battle as tokens of equal worth.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chris Rahn]]></artist><number><![CDATA[19]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[183063]]></id><name><![CDATA[Vectis Agents]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Human Rogue]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{U}{B}: Vectis Agents gets -2/-0 until end of turn and is unblockable this turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[With their life energy suppressed under their etherium enhancements, thieves from Esper found it surprisingly easy to explore the ruins of Grixis.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chippy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[131]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[185141]]></id><name><![CDATA[Vedalken Outlander]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Vedalken Scout]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{W}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Protection from red]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The Seekers of Carmot searched across the unknown lands for the mystical red stone that could reforge Esper in ethereal perfection.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Izzy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[132]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179245]]></id><name><![CDATA[Viashino Slaughtermaster]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Viashino Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Double strike<br>{B}{G}: Viashino Slaughtermaster gets +1/+1 until end of turn. Activate this ability only once each turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["I'll fight two at once, and then lick their guts from my blades."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Raymond Swanland]]></artist><number><![CDATA[73]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[183058]]></id><name><![CDATA[View from Above]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target creature gains flying until end of turn. If you control a white permanent, return View from Above to its owner's hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["This air feels so heavy and thick. There are no winds to speak of. I fear the knowledge that comes from a place like this."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Howard Lyon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[38]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : This checks the colors of permanents you control as it resolves. <br>2/1/2009 : If you control a white permanent, View from Above moves from the stack to your hand as part of its resolution. It never hits the graveyard. If you don't control a white permanent, View from Above is put into the graveyard from the stack as normal. <br>2/1/2009 : If View from Above is countered for any reason (for example, if its target has become illegal), none of its effects happen. It will be put into your graveyard as normal.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[150847]]></id><name><![CDATA[Voices from the Void]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Domain — Target player discards a card for each basic land type among lands you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[As Grixis collided with the rest of Alara, the worlds began to hear the hateful whispers of the forgotten dead.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[rk post]]></artist><number><![CDATA[55]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : To determine the number of basic land types among lands you control, look at the lands you have on the battlefield and ask yourself whether the subtypes Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, and Forest appear within that group. The number of times you say yes (topping out at five) tells you how powerful your domain abilities will be. <br>2/1/2009 : How many lands you control of a particular basic land type is irrelevant to a domain ability, as long as that number is greater than zero. As far as domain is concerned, ten Forests is the same as one Forest. <br>2/1/2009 : A number of nonbasic lands have basic land types. Domain abilities don't count the number of lands you control -- they count the number of basic land types among lands you control, even if that means checking the same land twice. For example, if you control a Tundra, an Overgrown Tomb, and a Madblind Mountain, you'll have a Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, and Forest among the lands you control. Your domain abilities will be maxed out.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[180274]]></id><name><![CDATA[Volcanic Fallout]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Volcanic Fallout can't be countered.<br>Volcanic Fallout deals 2 damage to each creature and each player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["How can we outrun the sky?"<br>—Hadran, sunseeder of Naya]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Zoltan Boros & Gabor Szikszai]]></artist><number><![CDATA[74]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Volcanic Fallout can be targeted by spells that try to counter it (such as Countersquall). Those spells will still resolve, but the part of their effect that would counter Volcanic Fallout won't do anything. Any other effects those spells have will work as normal.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[186329]]></id><name><![CDATA[Voracious Dragon]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Dragon]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Devour 1 (As this enters the battlefield, you may sacrifice any number of creatures. This creature enters the battlefield with that many +1/+1 counters on it.)<br>When Voracious Dragon enters the battlefield, it deals damage to target creature or player equal to twice the number of Goblins it devoured.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dominick Domingo]]></artist><number><![CDATA[75]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Voracious Dragon can devour any type of creatures, not just Goblins. <br>2/1/2009 : "The number of Goblins it devoured" means "The number of Goblins sacrificed as a result of its devour ability as it entered the battlefield." For each creature that Voracious Dragon devoured, this ability checks its creature type as it last existed on the battlefield to see if it was a Goblin at that time.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[189874]]></id><name><![CDATA[Wall of Reverence]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Spirit Wall]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Defender, flying<br>At the beginning of your end step, you may gain life equal to the power of target creature you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The lives of elves are long, but their memories are longer. Even after death, they do not desert their homes.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Wayne Reynolds]]></artist><number><![CDATA[20]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : This ability triggers and resolves before "until end of turn" effects have worn off.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[180279]]></id><name><![CDATA[Wandering Goblins]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Goblin Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Domain — {3}: Wandering Goblins gets +1/+0 until end of turn for each basic land type among lands you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Tired of waiting for a dragon to eat them, some hardy goblins struck out to become meals for the unknown.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Karl Kopinski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[76]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : To determine the number of basic land types among lands you control, look at the lands you have on the battlefield and ask yourself whether the subtypes Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, and Forest appear within that group. The number of times you say yes (topping out at five) tells you how powerful your domain abilities will be. <br>2/1/2009 : How many lands you control of a particular basic land type is irrelevant to a domain ability, as long as that number is greater than zero. As far as domain is concerned, ten Forests is the same as one Forest. <br>2/1/2009 : A number of nonbasic lands have basic land types. Domain abilities don't count the number of lands you control -- they count the number of basic land types among lands you control, even if that means checking the same land twice. For example, if you control a Tundra, an Overgrown Tomb, and a Madblind Mountain, you'll have a Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, and Forest among the lands you control. Your domain abilities will be maxed out.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179489]]></id><name><![CDATA[Wild Leotau]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Cat]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice Wild Leotau unless you pay {G}.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Leotau that were born wild make the best mounts. It's like riding a thunderstorm."<br>—Rafiq of the Many]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Michael Komarck]]></artist><number><![CDATA[97]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[175401]]></id><name><![CDATA[Worldheart Phoenix]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Phoenix]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>You may cast Worldheart Phoenix from your graveyard by paying {W}{U}{B}{R}{G} rather than paying its mana cost. If you do, it enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Aleksi Briclot]]></artist><number><![CDATA[77]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Casting Worldheart Phoenix from your graveyard by paying its alternative cost doesn't change when you can cast it. You can cast it only at the normal time you could cast a creature spell. <br>2/1/2009 : If you cast Worldheart Phoenix this way, it is a spell and can be countered. <br>2/1/2009 : As soon as you start to cast Worldheart Phoenix from your graveyard, the card moves onto the stack. At that point, it's too late for an opponent to prevent you from casting it by removing it from your graveyard.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[142298]]></id><name><![CDATA[Worldly Counsel]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Domain — Look at the top X cards of your library, where X is the number of basic land types among lands you control. Put one of those cards into your hand and the rest on the bottom of your library in any order.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Every horizon hides a new possibility.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Matt Cavotta]]></artist><number><![CDATA[39]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/4/2004 : You choose the order on the bottom of your library.  <br>2/1/2009 : To determine the number of basic land types among lands you control, look at the lands you have on the battlefield and ask yourself whether the subtypes Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, and Forest appear within that group. The number of times you say yes (topping out at five) tells you how powerful your domain abilities will be. <br>2/1/2009 : How many lands you control of a particular basic land type is irrelevant to a domain ability, as long as that number is greater than zero. As far as domain is concerned, ten Forests is the same as one Forest. <br>2/1/2009 : A number of nonbasic lands have basic land types. Domain abilities don't count the number of lands you control -- they count the number of basic land types among lands you control, even if that means checking the same land twice. For example, if you control a Tundra, an Overgrown Tomb, and a Madblind Mountain, you'll have a Plains, Island, Swamp, Mountain, and Forest among the lands you control. Your domain abilities will be maxed out.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[174907]]></id><name><![CDATA[Wretched Banquet]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Destroy target creature if it has the least power or is tied for least power among creatures on the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The meek inherit nothing."<br>—Sedris, the Traitor King]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Nils Hamm]]></artist><number><![CDATA[56]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Wretched Banquet may target any creature. The creature's power is checked only as Wretched Banquet resolves. If another creature has less power than the targeted creature at that time, Wretched Banquet does nothing.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[179891]]></id><name><![CDATA[Yoke of the Damned]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>When a creature dies, destroy enchanted creature.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The demon's yoke is part leash, part noose.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Paul Bonner]]></artist><number><![CDATA[57]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[185138]]></id><name><![CDATA[Zombie Outlander]]></name><set><![CDATA[CFX]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Zombie Scout]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{U}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Protection from green]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The ripe smell of life drifted into Grixis. The dead caught the scent and with reckless hunger followed it back into Jund.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Nils Hamm]]></artist><number><![CDATA[133]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card></cards></mtg_carddatabase>