<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><mtg_carddatabase><bdd_date><![CDATA[1-5-2013]]></bdd_date><bdd_version><![CDATA[1.00]]></bdd_version><bdd_name>Magic the Gathering® Card Database</bdd_name><bdd_editor>Wizards of the Coast LLC</bdd_editor><sets><set><name><![CDATA[Eventide]]></name><code><![CDATA[EVE]]></code><code_magiccards><![CDATA[EVE]]></code_magiccards><date><![CDATA[07/2008]]></date><is_promo><![CDATA[False]]></is_promo></set></sets><cards><card><id><![CDATA[153427]]></id><name><![CDATA[Aerie Ouphes]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Ouphe]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Sacrifice Aerie Ouphes: Aerie Ouphes deals damage equal to its power to target creature with flying.<br>Persist (When this creature dies, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jesper Ejsing]]></artist><number><![CDATA[65]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If Aerie Ouphes has no -1/-1 counters on it when you sacrifice it to activate its first ability, persist will return Aerie Ouphes to the battlefield with a -1/-1 counter on it before that ability resolves. The ability will check the power of Aerie Ouphes at the time you sacrificed it, not the power of the returned Aerie Ouphes (which is actually a new object with no relation to its previous existence).]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157974]]></id><name><![CDATA[Altar Golem]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Golem]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{7}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[*]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[*]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample<br>Altar Golem's power and toughness are each equal to the number of creatures on the battlefield.<br>Altar Golem doesn't untap during your untap step.<br>Tap five untapped creatures you control: Untap Altar Golem.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Rob Alexander]]></artist><number><![CDATA[166]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[158293]]></id><name><![CDATA[Antler Skulkin]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Scarecrow]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{2}: Target white creature gains persist until end of turn. (When it dies, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Every skull has a tale to tell, and a skulkin is many dire tales cobbled together.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Kendall]]></artist><number><![CDATA[167]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If a nontoken creature that gains persist this way is put into a graveyard, that card will be returned to the battlefield with a -1/-1 counter on it. However, because it's a new object with no relation to its previous existence, that permanent will not have persist. <br>8/1/2008 : If a creature has multiple instances of persist, the result is largely the same as having just one instance of persist. When the creature is put into a graveyard, each persist ability will trigger. The first one to resolve will return the creature to the battlefield with a -1/-1 counter on it. The rest will do nothing.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[146006]]></id><name><![CDATA[Archon of Justice]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Archon]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>When Archon of Justice dies, exile target permanent.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[In dark times, Truth bears a blade.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jason Chan]]></artist><number><![CDATA[1]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151137]]></id><name><![CDATA[Ashling, the Extinguisher]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Elemental Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever Ashling, the Extinguisher deals combat damage to a player, choose target creature that player controls. He or she sacrifices that creature.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The Aurora had transformed her into a relentless force of destruction.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Wayne Reynolds]]></artist><number><![CDATA[33]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The target of the ability is chosen when Ashling's ability is put on the stack. When the ability resolves, the player dealt combat damage by Ashling sacrifices that creature if he or she still controls it. Neither regeneration nor indestructibility can save a creature from being sacrificed.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[158104]]></id><name><![CDATA[Balefire Liege]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Spirit Horror]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{RW}{RW}{RW}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Other red creatures you control get +1/+1.<br>Other white creatures you control get +1/+1.<br>Whenever you cast a red spell, Balefire Liege deals 3 damage to target player.<br>Whenever you cast a white spell, you gain 3 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ralph Horsley]]></artist><number><![CDATA[132]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The abilities are separate and cumulative. If another creature you control is both of the listed colors, it will get a total of +2/+2.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153480]]></id><name><![CDATA[Ballynock Trapper]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Kithkin Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Tap target creature.<br>Whenever you cast a white spell, you may untap Ballynock Trapper.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[No matter how large or small, fierce or fleeting, the kithkin have a trap for it.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Randy Gallegos]]></artist><number><![CDATA[2]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[154350]]></id><name><![CDATA[Banishing Knack]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Until end of turn, target creature gains "{T}: Return target nonland permanent to its owner's hand."]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Suddenly he realized that everything was connected by invisible strings, strings that could be pulled—or cut.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Howard Lyon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[17]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The targeted creature's controller, not Banishing Knack's controller, is the one who can activate the creature's new ability. <br>8/1/2008 : "Summoning sickness" applies. The new ability can't be activated unless the targeted creature has been under its controller's control since the beginning of that player's most recent turn or it has haste.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151165]]></id><name><![CDATA[Battlegate Mimic]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Shapeshifter]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{RW}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever you cast a spell that's both red and white, Battlegate Mimic becomes 4/2 and gains first strike until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Mimics don't need perfect disguises. They need only the perfect victims: the naive, the young, or the poor of sight.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Franz Vohwinkel]]></artist><number><![CDATA[133]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The ability triggers whenever you cast a spell that's both of its listed colors. It doesn't matter whether that spell also happens to be any other colors. <br>8/1/2008 : If you cast a spell that's the two appropriate colors for the second time in a turn, the ability triggers again. The Mimic will once again become the power and toughness stated in its ability, which could overwrite power- and toughness-setting effects that have been applied to it in the meantime. <br>8/1/2008 : Any other abilities the Mimic may have gained are not affected. <br>10/1/2009 : The effect from the ability overwrites other effects that set power and/or toughness if and only if those effects existed before the ability resolved. It will not overwrite effects that modify power or toughness (whether from a static ability, counters, or a resolved spell or ability), nor will it overwrite effects that set power and toughness which come into existence after the ability resolves. Effects that switch the creature's power and toughness are always applied after any other power or toughness changing effects, including this one, regardless of the order in which they are created.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157407]]></id><name><![CDATA[Batwing Brume]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{WB}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn if {W} was spent to cast Batwing Brume. Each player loses 1 life for each attacking creature he or she controls if {B} was spent to cast Batwing Brume. (Do both if {W}{B} was spent.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Richard Kane Ferguson]]></artist><number><![CDATA[81]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The spell cares about what mana was spent to pay its total cost, not just what mana was spent to pay the hybrid part of its cost. <br>8/1/2008 : The spell checks on resolution to see if any mana of the stated colors was spent to pay its cost. If so, it doesn't matter how much mana of that color was spent. <br>8/1/2008 : If the spell is copied, the copy will never have had mana of the stated color paid for it, no matter what colors were spent on the original spell.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157415]]></id><name><![CDATA[Beckon Apparition]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{WB}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Exile target card from a graveyard. Put a 1/1 white and black Spirit creature token with flying onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[When a graveyard is full, the gwyllions rattle the tombs and unleash the spirits into the sky.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Larry MacDougall]]></artist><number><![CDATA[82]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The controller of Beckon Apparition gets the token. <br>1/24/2013 : Beckon Apparition will be on the stack when you choose its target. It can’t target itself. <br>1/24/2013 : If the target card is an illegal target when Beckon Apparition tries to resolve (if it's no longer in the graveyard, for instance), the spell will be countered and none of its effects will happen. You won’t get a Spirit token.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153478]]></id><name><![CDATA[Belligerent Hatchling]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{RW}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[First strike<br>Belligerent Hatchling enters the battlefield with four -1/-1 counters on it.<br>Whenever you cast a red spell, remove a -1/-1 counter from Belligerent Hatchling.<br>Whenever you cast a white spell, remove a -1/-1 counter from Belligerent Hatchling.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Prescott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[134]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If you cast a spell that's both of the listed colors, both abilities will trigger. You'll remove a total of two -1/-1 counters from the Hatchling. <br>8/1/2008 : If there are no -1/-1 counters on it when the triggered ability resolves, the ability does nothing. There is no penalty for not being able to remove a counter.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151098]]></id><name><![CDATA[Bloodied Ghost]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Spirit]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{WB}{WB}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Bloodied Ghost enters the battlefield with a -1/-1 counter on it.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Only a knife left for a fortnight in the hollow of a ghastbark tree can inflict a wound so grave."<br>—Kithkin superstition]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mike Dringenberg]]></artist><number><![CDATA[83]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[158901]]></id><name><![CDATA[Bloom Tender]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elf Druid]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: For each color among permanents you control, add one mana of that color to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Beauty is a seed, waiting to blossom under her capable hands.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chippy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[66]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : For each color (white, blue, black, red, and green), check to see if you control a permanent of that color. You can count the same permanent for multiple colors. For example, if you control a green enchantment and a white-black creature, Bloom Tender's ability produces {W}{B}{G}. <br>8/1/2008 : Bloom Tender won't add more than one mana of any particular color to your mana pool. At most, it will produce {W}{U}{B}{R}{G}. <br>8/1/2008 : Bloom Tender can't add colorless mana to your mana pool, even if you control a colorless permanent.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153419]]></id><name><![CDATA[Cache Raiders]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Merfolk Rogue]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[At the beginning of your upkeep, return a permanent you control to its owner's hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[What the current doesn't take, they do.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Pete Venters]]></artist><number><![CDATA[18]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : This ability isn't targeted. You choose a permanent to return when the ability resolves. No one will be able to respond to the choice.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157400]]></id><name><![CDATA[Call the Skybreaker]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{UR}{UR}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Put a 5/5 blue and red Elemental creature token with flying onto the battlefield.<br>Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It hears and answers every orison across Shadowmoor.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Randy Gallegos]]></artist><number><![CDATA[98]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Casting a card by using its retrace ability works just like casting any other card, with two exceptions: You're casting the card from your graveyard rather than your hand, and you must discard a land card in addition to any other costs. <br>8/1/2008 : A retrace card cast from your graveyard follows the normal timing rules for its card type. <br>8/1/2008 : When a retrace card you cast from your graveyard resolves or is countered, it's put back into your graveyard. You may use the retrace ability to cast it again. <br>8/1/2008 : If the active player casts a spell that has retrace, that player may cast that card again after it resolves, before another player can remove the card from the graveyard. The active player has priority after the spell resolves, so he or she can immediately cast a new spell. Since casting a card with retrace from the graveyard moves that card onto the stack, no one else would have the chance to affect it while it's still in the graveyard.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[152033]]></id><name><![CDATA[Canker Abomination]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Treefolk Horror]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{BG}{BG}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[As Canker Abomination enters the battlefield, choose an opponent. Canker Abomination enters the battlefield with a -1/-1 counter on it for each creature that player controls.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Once the hideous disease takes hold, it spreads through both bark and mind.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Brandon Kitkouski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[115]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157393]]></id><name><![CDATA[Cankerous Thirst]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{BG}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[If {B} was spent to cast Cankerous Thirst, you may have target creature get -3/-3 until end of turn. If {G} was spent to cast Cankerous Thirst, you may have target creature get +3/+3 until end of turn. (Do both if {B}{G} was spent.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Nothing warms the bark on a chilly day like a draught of elf.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Carl Frank]]></artist><number><![CDATA[116]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The spell cares about what mana was spent to pay its total cost, not just what mana was spent to pay the hybrid part of its cost. <br>8/1/2008 : The spell checks on resolution to see if any mana of the stated colors was spent to pay its cost. If so, it doesn't matter how much mana of that color was spent. <br>8/1/2008 : If the spell is copied, the copy will never have had mana of the stated color paid for it, no matter what colors were spent on the original spell. <br>8/1/2008 : The spell cares about what mana was spent to pay its total cost, not just what mana was spent to pay the hybrid part of its cost. <br>8/1/2008 : When you cast the spell, you choose its targets before you pay for it. <br>8/1/2008 : The spell checks on resolution to see if any mana of the stated colors was spent to pay its cost. If so, it doesn't matter how much mana of that color was spent. <br>8/1/2008 : If the spell is copied, the copy will never have had mana of the stated color paid for it, no matter what colors were spent on the original spell. <br>8/1/2008 : As you cast Cankerous Thirst, you must target a creature for the first effect and you must target a creature for the second effect. Both targets may be the same. As Cankerous Thirst resolves, you decide whether to apply either effect.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153433]]></id><name><![CDATA[Cascade Bluffs]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.<br>{UR}, {T}: Add {U}{U}, {U}{R}, or {R}{R} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Travelers bathe in the falls to wash away curses from the pucas who lurk nearby.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Brandon Kitkouski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[175]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151060]]></id><name><![CDATA[Cauldron Haze]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{WB}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Choose any number of target creatures. Each of those creatures gains persist until end of turn. (When it dies, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Brandon Kitkouski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[84]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If a nontoken creature that gains persist this way is put into a graveyard, that card will be returned to the battlefield with a -1/-1 counter on it. However, because it's a new object with no relation to its previous existence, that permanent will not have persist. <br>8/1/2008 : If a creature has multiple instances of persist, the result is largely the same as having just one instance of persist. When the creature is put into a graveyard, each persist ability will trigger. The first one to resolve will return the creature to the battlefield with a -1/-1 counter on it. The rest will do nothing.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153469]]></id><name><![CDATA[Cenn's Enlistment]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Put two 1/1 white Kithkin Soldier creature tokens onto the battlefield.<br>Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The more the scarier.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Matt Cavotta]]></artist><number><![CDATA[3]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Casting a card by using its retrace ability works just like casting any other card, with two exceptions: You're casting the card from your graveyard rather than your hand, and you must discard a land card in addition to any other costs. <br>8/1/2008 : A retrace card cast from your graveyard follows the normal timing rules for its card type. <br>8/1/2008 : When a retrace card you cast from your graveyard resolves or is countered, it's put back into your graveyard. You may use the retrace ability to cast it again. <br>8/1/2008 : If the active player casts a spell that has retrace, that player may cast that card again after it resolves, before another player can remove the card from the graveyard. The active player has priority after the spell resolves, so he or she can immediately cast a new spell. Since casting a card with retrace from the graveyard moves that card onto the stack, no one else would have the chance to affect it while it's still in the graveyard.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[158903]]></id><name><![CDATA[Chaotic Backlash]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Chaotic Backlash deals damage to target player equal to twice the number of white and/or blue permanents he or she controls.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The concept of thoughtweft fascinates the Nighthearth cult. Imagine, bringing agony to an entire people by torturing just one.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Carl Frank]]></artist><number><![CDATA[49]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Each permanent is counted only once. For example, if the targeted player controls a white creature, a blue enchantment, and a white-blue creature, Chaotic Backlash will deal 6 damage to that player.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151067]]></id><name><![CDATA[Cinder Pyromancer]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Cinder Pyromancer deals 1 damage to target player.<br>Whenever you cast a red spell, you may untap Cinder Pyromancer.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["If the whole world burns, I'll never grow cold."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Greg Staples]]></artist><number><![CDATA[50]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[152092]]></id><name><![CDATA[Clout of the Dominus]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{UR}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>As long as enchanted creature is blue, it gets +1/+1 and has shroud. (It can't be the target of spells or abilities.)<br>As long as enchanted creature is red, it gets +1/+1 and has haste.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jaime Jones]]></artist><number><![CDATA[99]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If the enchanted creature is both of the listed colors, it will get both bonuses.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153471]]></id><name><![CDATA[Cold-Eyed Selkie]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Merfolk Rogue]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{GU}{GU}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Islandwalk<br>Whenever Cold-Eyed Selkie deals combat damage to a player, you may draw that many cards.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[She follows the old tributaries built when merrows still shaped the tides.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jaime Jones]]></artist><number><![CDATA[149]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157420]]></id><name><![CDATA[Crackleburr]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{UR}{UR}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{UR}{UR}, {T}, Tap two untapped red creatures you control: Crackleburr deals 3 damage to target creature or player.<br>{UR}{UR}, {Q}, Untap two tapped blue creatures you control: Return target creature to its owner's hand. ({Q} is the untap symbol.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mike Dringenberg]]></artist><number><![CDATA[100]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If the permanent is already untapped, you can't activate its {Q} ability. That's because you can't pay the "Untap this permanent" cost. <br>8/1/2008 : The "summoning sickness" rule applies to {Q}. If a creature with an {Q} ability hasn't been under your control since your most recent turn began, you can't activate that ability. Ignore this rule if the creature also has haste. <br>8/1/2008 : When you activate an {Q} ability, you untap the creature with that ability as a cost. The untap can't be responded to. (The actual ability can be responded to, of course.) <br>8/1/2008 : To activate either ability, you'll need Crackleburr plus two other creatures. Crackleburr must have been under your control since your most recent turn began (or have haste), but the other two creatures don't.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157285]]></id><name><![CDATA[Crag Puca]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Shapeshifter]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{UR}{UR}{UR}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{UR}: Switch Crag Puca's power and toughness until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Be happy when you see a puca shaped like mischief. It's far better than one shaped like death."<br>—Dindun of Kulrath Mine]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[John Howe]]></artist><number><![CDATA[101]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>4/15/2013 : Effects that switch power and toughness apply after all other effects that change power and/or toughness, regardless of which effect was created first. <br>4/15/2013 : Switching a creature’s power and toughness twice (or any even number of times) effectively returns the creature to the power and toughness it had before any switches.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157206]]></id><name><![CDATA[Creakwood Ghoul]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Plant Zombie]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{BG}{BG}: Exile target card from a graveyard. You gain 1 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Some eat the living. Some eat the dead. It eats the past.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Thomas M. Baxa]]></artist><number><![CDATA[34]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If the targeted card is removed from the graveyard before the ability resolves, the entire ability is countered. You won't gain 1 life.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157406]]></id><name><![CDATA[Creakwood Liege]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Horror]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{BG}{BG}{BG}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Other black creatures you control get +1/+1.<br>Other green creatures you control get +1/+1.<br>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a 1/1 black and green Worm creature token onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Cole Eastburn]]></artist><number><![CDATA[117]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The abilities are separate and cumulative. If another creature you control is both of the listed colors, it will get a total of +2/+2. <br>8/1/2008 : Since the token is black and green, it will get +2/+2 from Creakwood Liege as long as the Liege is on the battlefield.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[158103]]></id><name><![CDATA[Crumbling Ashes]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[At the beginning of your upkeep, destroy target creature with a -1/-1 counter on it.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["I was there to watch my brothers' quenching. I drew the slightest warmth from their dying rage."<br>—Illulia of Nighthearth]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chuck Lukacs]]></artist><number><![CDATA[35]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : This ability is mandatory. If you're the only player who controls a creature with a -1/-1 counter on it as your upkeep begins, you must target one of your own creatures. <br>8/1/2008 : You can't target a creature unless it already has a -1/-1 counter on it as your upkeep begins. Putting a -1/-1 counter on a creature during your upkeep won't let Crumbling Ashes destroy it that turn. <br>8/1/2008 : If the targeted creature loses all its -1/-1 counters by the time the ability resolves, the ability will be countered because its only target is illegal. The creature won't be destroyed.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157288]]></id><name><![CDATA[Deathbringer Liege]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Horror]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{WB}{WB}{WB}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Other white creatures you control get +1/+1.<br>Other black creatures you control get +1/+1.<br>Whenever you cast a white spell, you may tap target creature.<br>Whenever you cast a black spell, you may destroy target creature if it's tapped.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Drew Tucker]]></artist><number><![CDATA[85]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The abilities are separate and cumulative. If another creature you control is both of the listed colors, it will get a total of +2/+2. <br>8/1/2008 : If you cast a spell that's both white and black, the last two abilities will both trigger. You may use them together to destroy any creature. To do so, put the "destroy" ability on the stack first, then put the "tap" ability on the stack, with each one targeting the same creature. When the abilities resolve, they'll tap the creature, then destroy it. <br>6/15/2010 : The last ability can target any creature, not just a tapped creature (it doesn't say "target tapped creature"). When the ability resolves, check whether the creature is tapped or not. If it's tapped, you may destroy it. If it's not tapped, the ability does nothing.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153488]]></id><name><![CDATA[Deity of Scars]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Spirit Avatar]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{BG}{BG}{BG}{BG}{BG}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[7]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[7]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample<br>Deity of Scars enters the battlefield with two -1/-1 counters on it.<br>{BG}, Remove a -1/-1 counter from Deity of Scars: Regenerate Deity of Scars.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["His skin cuts swords."<br>—The Seer's Parables]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Prescott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[118]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : You can pay {B/G} and remove a -1/-1 counter to activate the ability any time you want. Deity of Scars doesn't need to be in danger of being destroyed. <br>8/1/2008 : Removing a -1/-1 counter from Deity of Scars is a cost of activating its activated ability. You can't activate the ability if there are no -1/-1 counters on Deity of Scars. <br>8/1/2008 : Deity of Scars's ability causes it to have more toughness when you activate the ability (as a result of losing a -1/-1 counter) and then puts a regeneration shield on it when the ability resolves. If you activate the ability in advance of Deity of Scars being dealt 5 damage, for example, Deity of Scars will be 6/6 before the damage is dealt to it. It won't use the regeneration shield unless it's dealt more damage that turn.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157419]]></id><name><![CDATA[Desecrator Hag]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Hag]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{BG}{BG}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Desecrator Hag enters the battlefield, return to your hand the creature card in your graveyard with the greatest power. If two or more cards are tied for greatest power, you choose one of them.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Loose earth is not a burial but an appetizer.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Fred Harper]]></artist><number><![CDATA[119]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : This ability doesn't target a card. It will determine which card is returned to your hand as it resolves. If there's a tie, you choose which of the tied cards to return to your hand at that time. <br>8/1/2008 : If the creature card has "*" in its power or toughness, the ability that defines "*" works in all zones.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[150995]]></id><name><![CDATA[Divinity of Pride]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Spirit Avatar]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{WB}{WB}{WB}{WB}{WB}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying, lifelink<br>Divinity of Pride gets +4/+4 as long as you have 25 or more life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["She spoke of mystery and portent, of such unfathomable things that my mind screamed for pity."<br>—The Seer's Parables]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Greg Staples]]></artist><number><![CDATA[86]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151154]]></id><name><![CDATA[Dominus of Fealty]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Spirit Avatar]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{UR}{UR}{UR}{UR}{UR}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may gain control of target permanent until end of turn. If you do, untap it and it gains haste until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Nothing is truly your own. It is his, whether you know it or not."<br>—The Seer's Parables]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kev Walker]]></artist><number><![CDATA[102]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If you already control the targeted permanent when the ability resolves, you still need to choose whether or not to apply the effect. If you choose to apply it, the permanent untaps and gains haste. If you don't, it doesn't.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[146010]]></id><name><![CDATA[Doomgape]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{BG}{BG}{BG}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[10]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[10]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample<br>At the beginning of your upkeep, sacrifice a creature. You gain life equal to that creature's toughness.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It eats and eats until the juiciest morsel it can find is itself.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Allsop]]></artist><number><![CDATA[120]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If you have no other creatures to sacrifice, you'll have to sacrifice Doomgape itself. You'll gain life equal to its toughness.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153039]]></id><name><![CDATA[Double Cleave]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{RW}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target creature gains double strike until end of turn. (It deals both first-strike and regular combat damage.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["When in doubt, kill 'em twice."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[rk post]]></artist><number><![CDATA[135]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151079]]></id><name><![CDATA[Drain the Well]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{BG}{BG}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Destroy target land. You gain 2 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Trows have learned that it's not wise to eat cinders without a bucket or two of water nearby.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Warren Mahy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[121]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153036]]></id><name><![CDATA[Dream Fracture]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Counter target spell. Its controller draws a card.<br>Draw a card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Creation is a paradox. It hatches from its opposite."<br>—Olka, Mistmeadow witch]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Howard Lyon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[19]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157207]]></id><name><![CDATA[Dream Thief]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Faerie Rogue]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>When Dream Thief enters the battlefield, draw a card if you've cast another blue spell this turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Awylla's salvaged dreams would finally be put to good use.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Howard Lyon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[20]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Dream Thief doesn't check whether you've cast another blue spell until its enters-the-battlefield ability resolves. If Dream Thief's enters-the-battlefield ability triggers, then you cast a blue instant spell in response, you'll get the bonus. <br>8/1/2008 : Although Dream Thief says it looks for "another blue spell," there's no requirement that Dream Thief actually be cast as a spell (or be blue) for this part of its ability to work. For example, if a spell such as Zombify puts Dream Thief directly onto the battlefield, its ability will still check whether you've cast a blue spell this turn, even though you didn't cast Dream Thief itself as a spell.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[150975]]></id><name><![CDATA[Duergar Assailant]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Dwarf Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{RW}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Sacrifice Duergar Assailant: Duergar Assailant deals 1 damage to target attacking or blocking creature.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Some duergars dismiss the world above as a fable. They react violently when their comfortable illusions are dispelled.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Paul Bonner]]></artist><number><![CDATA[136]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153437]]></id><name><![CDATA[Duergar Cave-Guard]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Dwarf Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)<br>{RW}: Duergar Cave-Guard gets +1/+0 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Duergars who grow too large to live in the tunnels are sent topside to defend the entrances from intruders.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Allsop]]></artist><number><![CDATA[51]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[159068]]></id><name><![CDATA[Duergar Hedge-Mage]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Dwarf Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{RW}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Duergar Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Mountains, you may destroy target artifact.<br>When Duergar Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Plains, you may destroy target enchantment.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Allsop]]></artist><number><![CDATA[137]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Each of the triggered abilities has an "intervening 'if' clause." That means (1) the ability won't trigger at all unless you control two or more lands of the appropriate land type when the Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, and (2) the ability will do nothing if you don't control two or more lands of the appropriate land type by the time it resolves. <br>8/1/2008 : Both abilities trigger at the same time. You can put them on the stack in any order. <br>8/1/2008 : Each of the triggered abilities look at your lands individually. This means that if you only control two dual-lands of the appropriate types, both of the abilities will trigger <br>8/1/2008 : Both abilities are optional; you choose whether to use them when they resolve. If an ability has a target, you must choose a target even if you don't plan to use the ability.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151106]]></id><name><![CDATA[Duergar Mine-Captain]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Dwarf Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{RW}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}{RW}, {Q}: Attacking creatures get +1/+0 until end of turn. ({Q} is the untap symbol.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Duergars are prodigious workers with long memories. Some still fulfill intricately detailed orders given decades, if not centuries, before.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Matt Cavotta]]></artist><number><![CDATA[138]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If the permanent is already untapped, you can't activate its {Q} ability. That's because you can't pay the "Untap this permanent" cost. <br>8/1/2008 : The "summoning sickness" rule applies to {Q}. If a creature with an {Q} ability hasn't been under your control since your most recent turn began, you can't activate that ability. Ignore this rule if the creature also has haste. <br>8/1/2008 : When you activate an {Q} ability, you untap the creature with that ability as a cost. The untap can't be responded to. (The actual ability can be responded to, of course.) <br>8/1/2008 : This ability affects only creatures that are attacking at the time it resolves. It won't affect creatures that attack later in the turn.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151164]]></id><name><![CDATA[Duskdale Wurm]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Wurm]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[7]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[7]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample (If this creature would assign enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it assign the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Last time, it tore up the Wilt-Leaf, turned Mistmeadow into a mudhole, and made the river jump its banks. On the bright side, we were eating venison for weeks."<br>—Donal Alloway, cenn of Kinscaer]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dan Dos Santos]]></artist><number><![CDATA[67]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151155]]></id><name><![CDATA[Edge of the Divinity]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{WB}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>As long as enchanted creature is white, it gets +1/+2.<br>As long as enchanted creature is black, it gets +2/+1.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The divinity's patronage confers both wicked grace and graceful wickedness.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dan Scott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[87]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If the enchanted creature is both of the listed colors, it will get both bonuses.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157975]]></id><name><![CDATA[Endless Horizons]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Endless Horizons enters the battlefield, search your library for any number of Plains cards and exile them. Then shuffle your library.<br>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a card you own exiled with Endless Horizons into your hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Joshua Hagler]]></artist><number><![CDATA[4]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If Endless Horizons leaves the battlefield, the remaining Plains cards stay exiled. If Endless Horizons returns to the battlefield, it's a new object with no relation to its previous existence. The previously exiled Plains cards will still stay exiled. <br>8/1/2008 : If a different player gains control of Endless Horizons, its ability will trigger at the beginning of that player's upkeep, but it won't do anything when it resolves.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157199]]></id><name><![CDATA[Endure]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Prevent all damage that would be dealt to you and permanents you control this turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The Aurora had lessened the kithkins' kindness, deepened their paranoia, and dulled their sense of pain.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ralph Horsley]]></artist><number><![CDATA[5]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157978]]></id><name><![CDATA[Evershrike]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental Spirit]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{WB}{WB}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Evershrike gets +2/+2 for each Aura attached to it.<br>{X}{WB}{WB}: Return Evershrike from your graveyard to the battlefield. You may put an Aura card with converted mana cost X or less from your hand onto the battlefield attached to it. If you don't, exile Evershrike.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dan Dos Santos]]></artist><number><![CDATA[88]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : You can activate Evershrike's ability only while it's in your graveyard. <br>8/1/2008 : You can't put an Aura onto the battlefield this way unless that Aura can legally be attached to Evershrike. For example, you can't put an Aura card with "enchant player" onto the battlefield this way. <br>8/1/2008 : You can activate Evershrike's ability with X = 0. If you do, you'll return Evershrike to the battlefield from your graveyard, then exile it. (There are no Aura cards with converted mana cost 0.) <br>8/1/2008 : You can activate Evershrike's ability even if you have no Auras in your hand, or if you have an Aura in your hand that you don't want to put on it or can't put on it. In either case, you'll return Evershrike to the battlefield from your graveyard, then exile it. No player has the opportunity to cast spells or activate abilities while Evershrike is on the battlefield.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[152087]]></id><name><![CDATA[Fable of Wolf and Owl]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{GU}{GU}{GU}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever you cast a green spell, you may put a 2/2 green Wolf creature token onto the battlefield.<br>Whenever you cast a blue spell, you may put a 1/1 blue Bird creature token with flying onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The forest grew fangs. The sky spread its wings.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Heather Hudson]]></artist><number><![CDATA[150]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[158296]]></id><name><![CDATA[Fang Skulkin]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Scarecrow]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{2}: Target black creature gains wither until end of turn. (It deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Everything falls apart. But living things fall apart in the most fascinating ways."<br>—Mowagh the Gwyllion]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ron Brown]]></artist><number><![CDATA[168]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151118]]></id><name><![CDATA[Favor of the Overbeing]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{GU}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>As long as enchanted creature is green, it gets +1/+1 and has vigilance.<br>As long as enchanted creature is blue, it gets +1/+1 and has flying.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Enlightenment is the mundane seen from the vantage point of the divine.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chippy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[151]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If the enchanted creature is both of the listed colors, it will get both bonuses.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153446]]></id><name><![CDATA[Fetid Heath]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.<br>{WB}, {T}: Add {W}{W}, {W}{B}, or {B}{B} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Do not linger in such places, child. There the gwyllions dance. If they find you, you will join in their revels for eternity."<br>—Talara, elvish safewright]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Daarken]]></artist><number><![CDATA[176]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157200]]></id><name><![CDATA[Fiery Bombardment]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Chroma — {2}, Sacrifice a creature: Fiery Bombardment deals damage to target creature or player equal to the number of red mana symbols in the sacrificed creature's mana cost.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It kills two beasts with one thrown.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Nils Hamm]]></artist><number><![CDATA[52]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Chroma abilities check only mana costs, which are found in a card's upper right corner. They don't count mana symbols that appear in a card's text box. <br>8/1/2008 : Chroma abilities count hybrid mana symbols of the appropriate color. For example, a card with mana cost {3}{U/R}{U/R} has two red mana symbols in its mana cost.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[158106]]></id><name><![CDATA[Figure of Destiny]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Kithkin]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{RW}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{RW}: Figure of Destiny becomes a 2/2 Kithkin Spirit.<br>{RW}{RW}{RW}: If Figure of Destiny is a Spirit, it becomes a 4/4 Kithkin Spirit Warrior.<br>{RW}{RW}{RW}{RW}{RW}{RW}: If Figure of Destiny is a Warrior, it becomes an 8/8 Kithkin Spirit Warrior Avatar with flying and first strike.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Scott M. Fischer]]></artist><number><![CDATA[139]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : None of these abilities has a duration. If one of them resolves, it will remain in effect until the game ends, Figure of Destiny leaves the battlefield, or some subsequent effect changes its characteristics, whichever comes first. <br>8/1/2008 : Figure of Destiny's abilities overwrite its power, toughness, and creature types. Typically, those abilities are activated in the order they appear on the card. However, if Figure of Destiny is an 8/8 Kithkin Spirit Warrior Avatar with flying and first strike, and you activate its first ability, it will become a 2/2 Kithkin Spirit that still has flying and first strike. <br>8/1/2008 : You can activate Figure of Destiny's second and third abilities regardless of what creature types it is. Each of those abilities checks Figure of Destiny's creature types when that ability resolves. If Figure of Destiny isn't the appropriate creature type at that time, the ability does nothing. <br>8/1/2008 : Figure of Destiny's second ability checks whether it's a Spirit, and its third ability checks whether it's a Warrior. It doesn't matter how it became the appropriate creature type. <br>10/1/2009 : The effect from the ability overwrites other effects that set power and/or toughness if and only if those effects existed before the ability resolved. It will not overwrite effects that modify power or toughness (whether from a static ability, counters, or a resolved spell or ability), nor will it overwrite effects that set power and toughness which come into existence after the ability resolves. Effects that switch the creature's power and toughness are always applied after any other power or toughness changing effects, including this one, regardless of the order in which they are created.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151149]]></id><name><![CDATA[Fire at Will]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{RW}{RW}{RW}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Fire at Will deals 3 damage divided as you choose among one, two, or three target attacking or blocking creatures.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Make these shots count. The more foes we drop now, the fewer we'll have trying to kill us later."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Pete Venters]]></artist><number><![CDATA[140]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The number of targets must be at least 1 and at most 3. You divide the damage as you cast Fire at Will, not as it resolves. Each target must be assigned at least 1 damage. <br>8/1/2008 : You may target both attacking creatures and blocking creatures as you cast Fire at Will.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153432]]></id><name><![CDATA[Flame Jab]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flame Jab deals 1 damage to target creature or player.<br>Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Fire's out. Should be safe now."<br>—Gnarltrunk]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[rk post]]></artist><number><![CDATA[53]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Casting a card by using its retrace ability works just like casting any other card, with two exceptions: You're casting the card from your graveyard rather than your hand, and you must discard a land card in addition to any other costs. <br>8/1/2008 : A retrace card cast from your graveyard follows the normal timing rules for its card type. <br>8/1/2008 : When a retrace card you cast from your graveyard resolves or is countered, it's put back into your graveyard. You may use the retrace ability to cast it again. <br>8/1/2008 : If the active player casts a spell that has retrace, that player may cast that card again after it resolves, before another player can remove the card from the graveyard. The active player has priority after the spell resolves, so he or she can immediately cast a new spell. Since casting a card with retrace from the graveyard moves that card onto the stack, no one else would have the chance to affect it while it's still in the graveyard.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151089]]></id><name><![CDATA[Flickerwisp]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>When Flickerwisp enters the battlefield, exile another target permanent. Return that card to the battlefield under its owner's control at the beginning of the next end step.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Its wings disturb more than air.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jeremy Enecio]]></artist><number><![CDATA[6]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The exiled card will return to the battlefield at the beginning of the end step even if Flickerwisp is no longer on the battlefield. <br>8/1/2008 : If a Flickerwisp you cast exiles another Flickerwisp, the second Flickerwisp will return to the battlefield at the End step. Its ability will trigger and exile another target permanent. That permanent won't return to the battlefield until the next turn's End step.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153481]]></id><name><![CDATA[Flooded Grove]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.<br>{GU}, {T}: Add {G}{G}, {G}{U}, or {U}{U} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[At full moon, the river seeps over its banks and crawls through the woods like a blanket of serpents.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Kendall]]></artist><number><![CDATA[177]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151153]]></id><name><![CDATA[Gift of the Deity]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{BG}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>As long as enchanted creature is black, it gets +1/+1 and has deathtouch. (Any amount of damage it deals to a creature is enough to destroy that creature.)<br>As long as enchanted creature is green, it gets +1/+1 and all creatures able to block it do so.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Prescott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[122]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If the enchanted creature is both of the listed colors, it will get both bonuses.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[152046]]></id><name><![CDATA[Gilder Bairn]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Ouphe]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{GU}{GU}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{2}{GU}, {Q}: For each counter on target permanent, put another of those counters on that permanent. ({Q} is the untap symbol.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Do the glowing trinkets show it the way home, or do they set a twisted path for someone else to follow?]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Nils Hamm]]></artist><number><![CDATA[152]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If the permanent is already untapped, you can't activate its {Q} ability. That's because you can't pay the "Untap this permanent" cost. <br>8/1/2008 : The "summoning sickness" rule applies to {Q}. If a creature with an {Q} ability hasn't been under your control since your most recent turn began, you can't activate that ability. Ignore this rule if the creature also has haste. <br>8/1/2008 : When you activate an {Q} ability, you untap the creature with that ability as a cost. The untap can't be responded to. (The actual ability can be responded to, of course.) <br>8/1/2008 : Gilder Bairn's ability will replicate each kind of counter on the targeted permanent, not just +1/+1 or -1/-1 counters.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153439]]></id><name><![CDATA[Glamerdye]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Change the text of target spell or permanent by replacing all instances of one color word with another.<br>Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ralph Horsley]]></artist><number><![CDATA[21]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Casting a card by using its retrace ability works just like casting any other card, with two exceptions: You're casting the card from your graveyard rather than your hand, and you must discard a land card in addition to any other costs. <br>8/1/2008 : A retrace card cast from your graveyard follows the normal timing rules for its card type. <br>8/1/2008 : When a retrace card you cast from your graveyard resolves or is countered, it's put back into your graveyard. You may use the retrace ability to cast it again. <br>8/1/2008 : If the active player casts a spell that has retrace, that player may cast that card again after it resolves, before another player can remove the card from the graveyard. The active player has priority after the spell resolves, so he or she can immediately cast a new spell. Since casting a card with retrace from the graveyard moves that card onto the stack, no one else would have the chance to affect it while it's still in the graveyard. <br>8/1/2008 : Glamerdye's effect has no duration. It will last until the game ends or the affected spell or permanent leaves the relevant zone, with the following exception: If Glamerdye affects an artifact, creature, enchantment, or planeswalker spell, it will also affect the permanent that spell becomes when it resolves. <br>8/1/2008 : You choose the two color words when Glamerdye resolves. You can't change a word to the same word; you must choose a different word. <br>8/1/2008 : Glamerdye affects each instance of the chosen word in the text box of the spell or permanent, as long as it's being used as a color word. Glamerdye won't change such words in card names, such as White Knight. It also won't change mana symbols. <br>8/1/2008 : Glamerdye can change color words preceded by "non." For example, if you have it change "red" to "green," it will also change "nonred" to "nongreen." <br>8/1/2008 : Glamerdye changes only words actually printed on the spell or permanent (if it's a card), words that are part of the spell or permanent's original characteristics as stated by the effect that created it (if it's a token or a copy of a spell), or words that were granted to the spell or permanent as part of a copy effect. It won't change words that are granted to the spell or permanent by any other effects. For example, if an Aura grants a creature protection from blue, you can change that to protection from red by targeting the Aura, but not by targeting the creature. Glamerdye also can't change what color was chosen for a permanent (such as Painter's Servant) as it entered the battlefield. <br>8/1/2008 : Glamerdye can't affect the keyword fear.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157977]]></id><name><![CDATA[Glen Elendra Archmage]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Faerie Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>{U}, Sacrifice Glen Elendra Archmage: Counter target noncreature spell.<br>Persist (When this creature dies, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Warren Mahy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[22]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153428]]></id><name><![CDATA[Grazing Kelpie]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Beast]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{GU}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{GU}, Sacrifice Grazing Kelpie: Put target card from a graveyard on the bottom of its owner's library.<br>Persist (When this creature dies, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Drew Tucker]]></artist><number><![CDATA[153]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153056]]></id><name><![CDATA[Groundling Pouncer]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Faerie]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{GU}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{GU}: Groundling Pouncer gets +1/+3 and gains flying until end of turn. Activate this ability only once each turn and only if an opponent controls a creature with flying.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Endry was determined to teach his groundlings a few winged-faerie tricks.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Richard Whitters]]></artist><number><![CDATA[154]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : It matters that an opponent controls a creature with flying only as you activate this ability. Once you've activated it, Groundling Pouncer will still get +1/+3 and gain flying, even if all of your opponents' creatures with flying leave the battlefield in response to the ability or after the ability resolves.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[159069]]></id><name><![CDATA[Gwyllion Hedge-Mage]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Hag Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{WB}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Gwyllion Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Plains, you may put a 1/1 white Kithkin Soldier creature token onto the battlefield.<br>When Gwyllion Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Swamps, you may put a -1/-1 counter on target creature.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Todd Lockwood]]></artist><number><![CDATA[89]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Each of the triggered abilities has an "intervening 'if' clause." That means (1) the ability won't trigger at all unless you control two or more lands of the appropriate land type when the Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, and (2) the ability will do nothing if you don't control two or more lands of the appropriate land type by the time it resolves. <br>8/1/2008 : Both abilities trigger at the same time. You can put them on the stack in any order. <br>8/1/2008 : Each of the triggered abilities look at your lands individually. This means that if you only control two dual-lands of the appropriate types, both of the abilities will trigger <br>8/1/2008 : Both abilities are optional; you choose whether to use them when they resolve. If an ability has a target, you must choose a target even if you don't plan to use the ability.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157980]]></id><name><![CDATA[Hag Hedge-Mage]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Hag Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{BG}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Hag Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Swamps, you may have target player discard a card.<br>When Hag Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Forests, you may put target card from your graveyard on top of your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Scott Altmann]]></artist><number><![CDATA[123]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Each of the triggered abilities has an "intervening 'if' clause." That means (1) the ability won't trigger at all unless you control two or more lands of the appropriate land type when the Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, and (2) the ability will do nothing if you don't control two or more lands of the appropriate land type by the time it resolves. <br>8/1/2008 : Both abilities trigger at the same time. You can put them on the stack in any order. <br>8/1/2008 : Each of the triggered abilities look at your lands individually. This means that if you only control two dual-lands of the appropriate types, both of the abilities will trigger <br>8/1/2008 : Both abilities are optional; you choose whether to use them when they resolve. If an ability has a target, you must choose a target even if you don't plan to use the ability.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157394]]></id><name><![CDATA[Hallowed Burial]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Put all creatures on the bottom of their owners' libraries.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["I'd rather hear the screams of battle than the quiet that follows."<br>—Talara, elvish safewright]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Kendall]]></artist><number><![CDATA[7]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : All creatures leave the battlefield simultaneously. They're not destroyed; they're just put on the bottom of their owners' libraries. This includes token creatures, though they'll cease to exist as soon as Hallowed Burial finishes resolving. <br>8/1/2008 : Each player chooses the relative order of the cards he or she is putting on the bottom of his or her library, regardless of who controlled them while they were on the battlefield. Players don't reveal this order to other players.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[152089]]></id><name><![CDATA[Harvest Gwyllion]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Hag]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{WB}{WB}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[She speaks only in vile epithets, spitting out curses and obscenities that harm others just by the hearing.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Nils Hamm]]></artist><number><![CDATA[90]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[147413]]></id><name><![CDATA[Hatchet Bully]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Goblin Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{2}{R}, {T}, Put a -1/-1 counter on a creature you control: Hatchet Bully deals 2 damage to target creature or player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["It's not much for eating, but I think we can find somethin' to do with it."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Paul Bonner]]></artist><number><![CDATA[54]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[152155]]></id><name><![CDATA[Hateflayer]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)<br>{2}{R}, {Q}: Hateflayer deals damage equal to its power to target creature or player. ({Q} is the untap symbol.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It has no safe side.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Thomas M. Baxa]]></artist><number><![CDATA[55]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If the permanent is already untapped, you can't activate its {Q} ability. That's because you can't pay the "Untap this permanent" cost. <br>8/1/2008 : The "summoning sickness" rule applies to {Q}. If a creature with an {Q} ability hasn't been under your control since your most recent turn began, you can't activate that ability. Ignore this rule if the creature also has haste. <br>8/1/2008 : When you activate an {Q} ability, you untap the creature with that ability as a cost. The untap can't be responded to. (The actual ability can be responded to, of course.) <br>8/1/2008 : Wither applies to any damage Hateflayer deals to a creature, which includes both its combat damage and damage from its activated ability.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157201]]></id><name><![CDATA[Hearthfire Hobgoblin]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Goblin Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{RW}{RW}{RW}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Double strike]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Hobgoblins are best left alone. They sharpen their farm implements far more than is necessary for their work in the fields.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steven Belledin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[141]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[141942]]></id><name><![CDATA[Heartlash Cinder]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Haste<br>Chroma — When Heartlash Cinder enters the battlefield, it gets +X/+0 until end of turn, where X is the number of red mana symbols in the mana costs of permanents you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Prescott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[56]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Chroma abilities check only mana costs, which are found in a card's upper right corner. They don't count mana symbols that appear in a card's text box. <br>8/1/2008 : Chroma abilities count hybrid mana symbols of the appropriate color. For example, a card with mana cost {3}{U/R}{U/R} has two red mana symbols in its mana cost. <br>8/1/2008 : The effect counts the mana symbols in this cards mana cost as well.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[150992]]></id><name><![CDATA[Helix Pinnacle]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Shroud<br>{X}: Put X tower counters on Helix Pinnacle.<br>At the beginning of your upkeep, if there are 100 or more tower counters on Helix Pinnacle, you win the game.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dan Scott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[68]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Helix Pinnacle's triggered ability has an "intervening 'if' clause." That means (1) the ability won't trigger at all unless Helix Pinnacle already has 100 or more tower counters on it as your upkeep begins, and (2) the ability will do nothing if Helix Pinnacle has lost enough counters such that it has fewer than 100 counters on it when the ability resolves. <br>8/1/2008 : If Helix Pinnacle leaves the battlefield before its triggered ability resolves, check the number of counters that were on it as it last existed on the battlefield.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151090]]></id><name><![CDATA[Hobgoblin Dragoon]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Goblin Knight]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{RW}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying, first strike]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The faeries snickered at first. A common hob in Oona's skies? But his lance ended their mockery, and now the sound of a cicada's wings brings a shudder to the faerie heart.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Matt Cavotta]]></artist><number><![CDATA[142]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[158294]]></id><name><![CDATA[Hoof Skulkin]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Scarecrow]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{3}: Target green creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It hunts with the memory of a long lost herd.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Joshua Hagler]]></artist><number><![CDATA[169]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153426]]></id><name><![CDATA[Hotheaded Giant]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Giant Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Haste<br>Hotheaded Giant enters the battlefield with two -1/-1 counters on it unless you've cast another red spell this turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[As he races the moon each night, he draws a glowing equator across the world.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Fred Harper]]></artist><number><![CDATA[57]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Hotheaded Giant doesn't check whether you've cast another red spell until Hotheaded Giant enters the battlefield. <br>8/1/2008 : Although Hotheaded Giant says it looks for "another red spell," there's no requirement that Hotheaded Giant actually be cast as a spell (or be red) for this part of its ability to work. For example, if a spell such as Zombify puts Hotheaded Giant directly onto the battlefield, its ability will still check whether you've cast a red spell this turn even though you didn't cast Hotheaded Giant itself as a spell.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157412]]></id><name><![CDATA[Idle Thoughts]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{2}: Draw a card if you have no cards in hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Inspiration strikes the uncluttered mind.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steven Belledin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[23]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : You can activate the ability whether or not you have any cards in your hand. However, you'll draw a card only if your hand is empty when the ability resolves. (This card works differently than the _Tempest_(TM) card Fool's Tome.)]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[152049]]></id><name><![CDATA[Impelled Giant]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Giant Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample<br>Tap an untapped red creature you control other than Impelled Giant: Impelled Giant gets +X/+0 until end of turn, where X is the power of the creature tapped this way.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mark Zug]]></artist><number><![CDATA[58]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Since the activated ability doesn't have a tap symbol in its cost, you can tap creatures that haven't been under your control since your most recent turn began to pay the cost. <br>8/1/2008 : The power of the creature you tap is checked as the ability resolves, not as the creature is tapped, and not at any later time should the power of that creature change. If that creature is no longer on the battlefield as the ability resolves, use the power it had when it was last on the battlefield.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153422]]></id><name><![CDATA[Indigo Faerie]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Faerie Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>{U}: Target permanent becomes blue in addition to its other colors until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["You should see your face right now."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Prescott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[24]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : This ability doesn't overwrite any previous colors. Rather, it adds another color. <br>8/1/2008 : If something affected by Indigo Faerie's ability is normally colorless, it will simply be blue. It won't be both blue and colorless. <br>8/1/2008 : After Indigo Faerie's ability resolves, an effect that changes the affected permanent's colors will overwrite Indigo Faerie's effect. For example, if Indigo Faerie's ability is activated on Llanowar Elves, the Elves will be blue and green; if Aphotic Wisps is then cast on the same creature, it'll be just black.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[154263]]></id><name><![CDATA[Inside Out]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{UR}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Switch target creature's power and toughness until end of turn.<br>Draw a card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Seyden's temperament didn't take well to the puca's magic. Nor did his face.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Zoltan Boros & Gabor Szikszai]]></artist><number><![CDATA[103]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>4/15/2013 : Effects that switch power and toughness apply after all other effects that change power and/or toughness, regardless of which effect was created first. <br>4/15/2013 : Switching a creature’s power and toughness twice (or any even number of times) effectively returns the creature to the power and toughness it had before any switches.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[142010]]></id><name><![CDATA[Inundate]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Return all nonblue creatures to their owners' hands.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["For years, the landfolk have emptied their refuse into the waters. It's time to return the favor."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mark Zug]]></artist><number><![CDATA[25]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : A hybrid creature that's blue and another color is *not* a nonblue creature. Since it's blue, it can't be nonblue!]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151108]]></id><name><![CDATA[Invert the Skies]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{GU}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Creatures your opponents control lose flying until end of turn if {G} was spent to cast Invert the Skies, and creatures you control gain flying until end of turn if {U} was spent to cast it. (Do both if {G}{U} was spent.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Randy Gallegos]]></artist><number><![CDATA[155]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The spell cares about what mana was spent to pay its total cost, not just what mana was spent to pay the hybrid part of its cost. <br>8/1/2008 : The spell checks on resolution to see if any mana of the stated colors was spent to pay its cost. If so, it doesn't matter how much mana of that color was spent. <br>8/1/2008 : If the spell is copied, the copy will never have had mana of the stated color paid for it, no matter what colors were spent on the original spell. <br>8/1/2008 : Invert the Skies affects only creatures on the battlefield at the time it resolves. If a creature enters the battlefield later that turn, it won't be affected. <br>8/1/2008 : If a creature changes controllers later in the turn, that won't change how Invert the Skies affected it]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[158295]]></id><name><![CDATA[Jawbone Skulkin]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Scarecrow]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{2}: Target red creature gains haste until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Ah, skull of shrew—a very potent substance. In powdered form, it gives thrice the zing of noggle hoof pulp."<br>—Boghald, Barrenton medic]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jeff Easley]]></artist><number><![CDATA[170]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[152096]]></id><name><![CDATA[Kithkin Spellduster]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Kithkin Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>{1}{W}, Sacrifice Kithkin Spellduster: Destroy target enchantment.<br>Persist (When this creature dies, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Trevor Hairsine]]></artist><number><![CDATA[8]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[154346]]></id><name><![CDATA[Kithkin Zealot]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Kithkin Cleric]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Kithkin Zealot enters the battlefield, you gain 1 life for each black and/or red permanent target opponent controls.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The more his flock fears, the more power he wields.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Scott Altmann]]></artist><number><![CDATA[9]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Each permanent is counted only once. For example, if the targeted player controls a black creature, a red enchantment, and a black-red creature, you'll gain 3 life.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157971]]></id><name><![CDATA[Leering Emblem]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact — Equipment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever you cast a spell, equipped creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.<br>Equip {2}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The banner was not a symbol of victory, but a herald of the carnage to come.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ron Brown]]></artist><number><![CDATA[171]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The bonus is given to the creature Leering Emblem is attached to as the ability resolves.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151139]]></id><name><![CDATA[Light from Within]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Chroma — Each creature you control gets +1/+1 for each white mana symbol in its mana cost.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Muscle does not make one strong. It only masks the soul's light. True strength lies in purity of purpose."<br>—Donal Alloway, cenn of Kinscaer]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Aleksi Briclot]]></artist><number><![CDATA[10]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Chroma abilities check only mana costs, which are found in a card's upper right corner. They don't count mana symbols that appear in a card's text box. <br>8/1/2008 : Chroma abilities count hybrid mana symbols of the appropriate color. For example, a card with mana cost {3}{U/R}{U/R} has two red mana symbols in its mana cost. <br>8/1/2008 : Light from Within affects each creature individually. For example, if you control a creature with mana cost {1}{W}{W} and a creature with mana cost {W/B}{W/B}{W/B}{W/B}{W/B}, the first creature gets +2/+2 and the second creature gets +5/+5.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[147437]]></id><name><![CDATA[Lingering Tormentor]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Spirit]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Fear (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)<br>Persist (When this creature dies, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The bogeyman doesn't disappear when you close your eyes.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Joshua Hagler]]></artist><number><![CDATA[36]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151059]]></id><name><![CDATA[Loyal Gyrfalcon]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Bird]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Defender, flying<br>Whenever you cast a white spell, Loyal Gyrfalcon loses defender until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It's tethered not to keep it from fleeing but to keep it from eating everything in sight.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Darrell Riche]]></artist><number><![CDATA[11]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[142015]]></id><name><![CDATA[Marshdrinker Giant]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Giant Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Marshdrinker Giant enters the battlefield, destroy target Island or Swamp an opponent controls.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[When giants rise from their long slumbers, they rarely remember how fragile the waking world can be.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Daarken]]></artist><number><![CDATA[69]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151158]]></id><name><![CDATA[Merrow Bonegnawer]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Merfolk Rogue]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Target player exiles a card from his or her graveyard. <br>Whenever you cast a black spell, you may untap Merrow Bonegnawer.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Banished to the Dark Meanders for hideous crimes, some merrows find a taste for the darkness . . . and the dead.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jim Nelson]]></artist><number><![CDATA[37]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The targeted player chooses which card to exile.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151088]]></id><name><![CDATA[Merrow Levitator]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Merfolk Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Target creature gains flying until end of turn.<br>Whenever you cast a blue spell, you may untap Merrow Levitator.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[He fancies himself a master thief, claiming to "steal the ground" from his victims.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jim Pavelec]]></artist><number><![CDATA[26]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151132]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mindwrack Liege]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Horror]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{UR}{UR}{UR}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Other blue creatures you control get +1/+1.<br>Other red creatures you control get +1/+1.<br>{UR}{UR}{UR}{UR}: You may put a blue or red creature card from your hand onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Richard Whitters]]></artist><number><![CDATA[104]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The abilities are separate and cumulative. If another creature you control is both of the listed colors, it will get a total of +2/+2.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[152106]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mirror Sheen]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{UR}{UR}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}{UR}{UR}: Copy target instant or sorcery spell that targets you. You may choose new targets for the copy.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Even treefolk witches steer clear of the unpredictable woods near Glen Elendra. Spells refract off the glamer-polished trees and the eyes of lurking pucas.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[John Avon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[105]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The targeted spell can have any number of targets, as long as you are one of them. <br>8/1/2008 : It doesn't matter who controls the spell. <br>8/1/2008 : The copy will have the same targets as the spell it's copying unless you choose new ones. You may change any number of the targets, including all of them or none of them.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153441]]></id><name><![CDATA[Monstrify]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target creature gets +4/+4 until end of turn.<br>Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Gackt came to regret keeping his pet toads on his head.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Lars Grant-West]]></artist><number><![CDATA[70]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Casting a card by using its retrace ability works just like casting any other card, with two exceptions: You're casting the card from your graveyard rather than your hand, and you must discard a land card in addition to any other costs. <br>8/1/2008 : A retrace card cast from your graveyard follows the normal timing rules for its card type. <br>8/1/2008 : When a retrace card you cast from your graveyard resolves or is countered, it's put back into your graveyard. You may use the retrace ability to cast it again. <br>8/1/2008 : If the active player casts a spell that has retrace, that player may cast that card again after it resolves, before another player can remove the card from the graveyard. The active player has priority after the spell resolves, so he or she can immediately cast a new spell. Since casting a card with retrace from the graveyard moves that card onto the stack, no one else would have the chance to affect it while it's still in the graveyard.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157403]]></id><name><![CDATA[Moonhold]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{RW}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target player can't play land cards this turn if {R} was spent to cast Moonhold and can't play creature cards this turn if {W} was spent to cast it. (Do both if {R}{W} was spent.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mike Dringenberg]]></artist><number><![CDATA[143]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The spell cares about what mana was spent to pay its total cost, not just what mana was spent to pay the hybrid part of its cost. <br>8/1/2008 : The spell checks on resolution to see if any mana of the stated colors was spent to pay its cost. If so, it doesn't matter how much mana of that color was spent. <br>8/1/2008 : If the spell is copied, the copy will never have had mana of the stated color paid for it, no matter what colors were spent on the original spell. <br>8/1/2008 : The spell cares about what mana was spent to pay its total cost, not just what mana was spent to pay the hybrid part of its cost. <br>8/1/2008 : When you cast the spell, you choose its targets before you pay for it. <br>8/1/2008 : The spell checks on resolution to see if any mana of the stated colors was spent to pay its cost. If so, it doesn't matter how much mana of that color was spent. <br>8/1/2008 : If the spell is copied, the copy will never have had mana of the stated color paid for it, no matter what colors were spent on the original spell. <br>8/1/2008 : Moonhold is not a counterspell. It will have no effect on creature spells the targeted player cast before Moonhold resolved. <br>8/1/2008 : Moonhold doesn't stop effects that "put a card onto the battlefield."]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[152091]]></id><name><![CDATA[Murkfiend Liege]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Horror]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{GU}{GU}{GU}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Other green creatures you control get +1/+1.<br>Other blue creatures you control get +1/+1.<br>Untap all green and/or blue creatures you control during each other player's untap step.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Carl Critchlow]]></artist><number><![CDATA[156]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The abilities are separate and cumulative. If another creature you control is both of the listed colors, it will get a total of +2/+2. <br>8/1/2008 : All your green and/or blue creatures untap during each other player's untap step. You have no choice about what untaps. Those creatures untap at the same time as the active player's permanents. <br>8/1/2008 : During each other player's untap step, effects that would otherwise cause your green and/or blue creatures to stay tapped don't apply because they only apply during *your* untap step. For example, if you control Nettle Sentinel (a green creature that says "Nettle Sentinel doesn't untap during your untap step"), you untap it during each other player's untap step. <br>8/1/2008 : Multiple Murkfiend Lieges are redundant when it comes to the untap effect. You can't untap your permanents more than once in a single untap step.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[152080]]></id><name><![CDATA[Necroskitter]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)<br>Whenever a creature an opponent controls with a -1/-1 counter on it dies, you may return that card to the battlefield under your control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jaime Jones]]></artist><number><![CDATA[38]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : It doesn't matter whose graveyard the creature is put into. It matters only that an opponent controlled it when it left the battlefield. <br>8/1/2008 : It doesn't matter how many -1/-1 counters were on the creature when it was put into a graveyard from the battlefield, as long as it had at least one. <br>8/1/2008 : The card returns to the battlefield without any -1/-1 counters on it (unless some other effect causes it to enter the battlefield with some).]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153474]]></id><name><![CDATA[Needle Specter]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Specter]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)<br>Whenever Needle Specter deals combat damage to a player, that player discards that many cards.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Christopher Moeller]]></artist><number><![CDATA[39]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151095]]></id><name><![CDATA[Nettle Sentinel]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elf Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Nettle Sentinel doesn't untap during your untap step.<br>Whenever you cast a green spell, you may untap Nettle Sentinel.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Though Shadowmoor's monster-haunted wilds beckon, she never leaves her post.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kev Walker]]></artist><number><![CDATA[71]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157414]]></id><name><![CDATA[Nightmare Incursion]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Search target player's library for up to X cards, where X is the number of Swamps you control, and exile them. Then that player shuffles his or her library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chuck Lukacs]]></artist><number><![CDATA[40]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The cards are exiled face up, so everyone can see what they are. (This is true of every effect that exiles cards, unless the effect specifically says it exiles those cards face down.)]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151099]]></id><name><![CDATA[Nightsky Mimic]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Shapeshifter]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{WB}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever you cast a spell that's both white and black, Nightsky Mimic becomes 4/4 and gains flying until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[A mimic need only touch a being to learn its shape, but touching usually leads to mauling and messily eating.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Franz Vohwinkel]]></artist><number><![CDATA[91]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The ability triggers whenever you cast a spell that's both of its listed colors. It doesn't matter whether that spell also happens to be any other colors. <br>8/1/2008 : If you cast a spell that's the two appropriate colors for the second time in a turn, the ability triggers again. The Mimic will once again become the power and toughness stated in its ability, which could overwrite power- and toughness-setting effects that have been applied to it in the meantime. <br>8/1/2008 : Any other abilities the Mimic may have gained are not affected. <br>10/1/2009 : The effect from the ability overwrites other effects that set power and/or toughness if and only if those effects existed before the ability resolved. It will not overwrite effects that modify power or toughness (whether from a static ability, counters, or a resolved spell or ability), nor will it overwrite effects that set power and toughness which come into existence after the ability resolves. Effects that switch the creature's power and toughness are always applied after any other power or toughness changing effects, including this one, regardless of the order in which they are created.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[150986]]></id><name><![CDATA[Nip Gwyllion]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Hag]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{WB}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Lifelink (Damage dealt by this creature also causes you to gain that much life.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Once your life and all your worldly possessions have been surrendered to her, a gwyllion can be surprisingly civilized.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Alex Horley-Orlandelli]]></artist><number><![CDATA[92]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[154258]]></id><name><![CDATA[Nobilis of War]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Spirit Avatar]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{RW}{RW}{RW}{RW}{RW}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Attacking creatures you control get +2/+0.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["A great siege is a banquet to him; a long and terrible battle, the most exquisite delicacy."<br>—The Seer's Parables]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Christopher Moeller]]></artist><number><![CDATA[144]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : This is a static ability. Your creatures will get +2/+0 from the moment they're declared as attackers until the moment the combat phase ends, they're removed from combat, or Nobilis of War leaves the battlefield, whichever comes first.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157286]]></id><name><![CDATA[Noggle Bandit]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Noggle Rogue]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{UR}{UR}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Noggle Bandit can't be blocked except by creatures with defender.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Noggles believe that they were the first race ever to walk Shadowmoor. They don't "steal." They just take back what's rightfully theirs.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Thomas Denmark]]></artist><number><![CDATA[106]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[158899]]></id><name><![CDATA[Noggle Bridgebreaker]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Noggle Rogue]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{UR}{UR}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Noggle Bridgebreaker enters the battlefield, return a land you control to its owner's hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["It's always funny till someone gets hurt. Then it's hilarious."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Thomas M. Baxa]]></artist><number><![CDATA[107]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[159066]]></id><name><![CDATA[Noggle Hedge-Mage]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Noggle Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{UR}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Noggle Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Islands, you may tap two target permanents.<br>When Noggle Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Mountains, you may have Noggle Hedge-Mage deal 2 damage to target player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Larry MacDougall]]></artist><number><![CDATA[108]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Each of the triggered abilities has an "intervening 'if' clause." That means (1) the ability won't trigger at all unless you control two or more lands of the appropriate land type when the Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, and (2) the ability will do nothing if you don't control two or more lands of the appropriate land type by the time it resolves. <br>8/1/2008 : Both abilities trigger at the same time. You can put them on the stack in any order. <br>8/1/2008 : Each of the triggered abilities look at your lands individually. This means that if you only control two dual-lands of the appropriate types, both of the abilities will trigger <br>8/1/2008 : Both abilities are optional; you choose whether to use them when they resolve. If an ability has a target, you must choose a target even if you don't plan to use the ability.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[152032]]></id><name><![CDATA[Noggle Ransacker]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Noggle Rogue]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{UR}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Noggle Ransacker enters the battlefield, each player draws two cards, then discards a card at random.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Noggles live purely by what they can scavenge. There is not a single thing a noggle eats, wears, or uses that did not once belong to another.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Alex Horley-Orlandelli]]></artist><number><![CDATA[109]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : First the player whose turn it is draws two cards, then each other player in turn order does so. Then the player whose turn it is randomly selects a card from his or her hand, then each other player in turn order does so. Finally, all cards selected this way are discarded at the same time.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153448]]></id><name><![CDATA[Noxious Hatchling]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{BG}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Noxious Hatchling enters the battlefield with four -1/-1 counters on it.<br>Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)<br>Whenever you cast a black spell, remove a -1/-1 counter from Noxious Hatchling.<br>Whenever you cast a green spell, remove a -1/-1 counter from Noxious Hatchling.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Nils Hamm]]></artist><number><![CDATA[124]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If you cast a spell that's both of the listed colors, both abilities will trigger. You'll remove a total of two -1/-1 counters from the Hatchling. <br>8/1/2008 : If there are no -1/-1 counters on it when the triggered ability resolves, the ability does nothing. There is no penalty for not being able to remove a counter.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153058]]></id><name><![CDATA[Nucklavee]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Beast]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{UR}{UR}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Nucklavee enters the battlefield, you may return target red sorcery card from your graveyard to your hand.<br>When Nucklavee enters the battlefield, you may return target blue instant card from your graveyard to your hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It loathes all tastes but two: spells and flesh.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Trevor Hairsine]]></artist><number><![CDATA[110]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[150977]]></id><name><![CDATA[Odious Trow]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Troll]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{BG}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}{BG}: Regenerate Odious Trow.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Trows are the vile trolls that lurk in the bogs of Shadowmoor. They reappear each night to frighten the living and gnaw the dead.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Warren Mahy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[125]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153475]]></id><name><![CDATA[Oona's Grace]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target player draws a card.<br>Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Oona grants her favored subjects a dream from her own guarded heart.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Rebecca Guay]]></artist><number><![CDATA[27]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Casting a card by using its retrace ability works just like casting any other card, with two exceptions: You're casting the card from your graveyard rather than your hand, and you must discard a land card in addition to any other costs. <br>8/1/2008 : A retrace card cast from your graveyard follows the normal timing rules for its card type. <br>8/1/2008 : When a retrace card you cast from your graveyard resolves or is countered, it's put back into your graveyard. You may use the retrace ability to cast it again. <br>8/1/2008 : If the active player casts a spell that has retrace, that player may cast that card again after it resolves, before another player can remove the card from the graveyard. The active player has priority after the spell resolves, so he or she can immediately cast a new spell. Since casting a card with retrace from the graveyard moves that card onto the stack, no one else would have the chance to affect it while it's still in the graveyard.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153473]]></id><name><![CDATA[Outrage Shaman]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Goblin Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Chroma — When Outrage Shaman enters the battlefield, it deals damage to target creature equal to the number of red mana symbols in the mana costs of permanents you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[A boggart's mind is a tinderbox of volatile thoughts, hungry for a spark.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Cole Eastburn]]></artist><number><![CDATA[59]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Chroma abilities check only mana costs, which are found in a card's upper right corner. They don't count mana symbols that appear in a card's text box. <br>8/1/2008 : Chroma abilities count hybrid mana symbols of the appropriate color. For example, a card with mana cost {3}{U/R}{U/R} has two red mana symbols in its mana cost. <br>8/1/2008 : The effect counts the mana symbols in this cards mana cost as well.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151151]]></id><name><![CDATA[Overbeing of Myth]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Spirit Avatar]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{GU}{GU}{GU}{GU}{GU}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[*]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[*]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Overbeing of Myth's power and toughness are each equal to the number of cards in your hand.<br>At the beginning of your draw step, draw an additional card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["She walks among us unseen, learning from our imperfections."<br>—The Seer's Parables]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chippy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[157]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157210]]></id><name><![CDATA[Patrol Signaler]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Kithkin Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}{W}, {Q}: Put a 1/1 white Kithkin Soldier creature token onto the battlefield. ({Q} is the untap symbol.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Many a keen-eared bogle has run afoul of a clever and silently orchestrated kithkin ambush.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Prescott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[12]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If the permanent is already untapped, you can't activate its {Q} ability. That's because you can't pay the "Untap this permanent" cost. <br>8/1/2008 : The "summoning sickness" rule applies to {Q}. If a creature with an {Q} ability hasn't been under your control since your most recent turn began, you can't activate that ability. Ignore this rule if the creature also has haste. <br>8/1/2008 : When you activate an {Q} ability, you untap the creature with that ability as a cost. The untap can't be responded to. (The actual ability can be responded to, of course.)]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151113]]></id><name><![CDATA[Phosphorescent Feast]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Chroma — Reveal any number of cards in your hand. You gain 2 life for each green mana symbol in those cards' mana costs.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The boggarts gorged themselves until their bellies glowed.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ron Spencer]]></artist><number><![CDATA[72]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Chroma abilities check only mana costs, which are found in a card's upper right corner. They don't count mana symbols that appear in a card's text box. <br>8/1/2008 : Chroma abilities count hybrid mana symbols of the appropriate color. For example, a card with mana cost {3}{U/R}{U/R} has two red mana symbols in its mana cost.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153431]]></id><name><![CDATA[Primalcrux]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}{G}{G}{G}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[*]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[*]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample<br>Chroma — Primalcrux's power and toughness are each equal to the number of green mana symbols in the mana costs of permanents you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[When nature is backed into a corner, just like its children, it lashes out.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Wayne Reynolds]]></artist><number><![CDATA[73]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : This will count the number of symbols in its mana cost while it's on the battlefield. The ability functions while it's in other zones, but since it isn't a permanent while in those zones it won't count itself. <br>8/1/2008 : Chroma abilities check only mana costs, which are found in a card's upper right corner. They don't count mana symbols that appear in a card's text box. <br>8/1/2008 : Chroma abilities count hybrid mana symbols of the appropriate color. For example, a card with mana cost {3}{U/R}{U/R} has two red mana symbols in its mana cost.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[152034]]></id><name><![CDATA[Puncture Blast]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)<br>Puncture Blast deals 3 damage to target creature or player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Gnarltrunk didn't remember having quite that many knotholes.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Carl Critchlow]]></artist><number><![CDATA[60]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : This is the only instant or sorcery spell that has wither. It works like anything else with wither: If it deals damage to a creature, the damage results in -1/-1 counters; if it deals damage to a player or planeswalker, the damage behaves normally.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157397]]></id><name><![CDATA[Pyrrhic Revival]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{WB}{WB}{WB}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Each player returns each creature card from his or her graveyard to the battlefield with an additional -1/-1 counter on it.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[They found themselves alive again, still bearing their mortal wounds.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Richard Kane Ferguson]]></artist><number><![CDATA[93]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Pyrrhic Revival can cause creatures to be put onto the battlefield that have 0 toughness due to the -1/-1 counter from this effect. Those creatures are put right back into their owners' graveyards as a state-based action. No spells or abilities that would remove counters or otherwise affect those creatures can be cast or activated before that happens. Still, the creatures did momentarily pop onto the battlefield, so any relevant triggered abilities (including their own enters-the-battlefield or leaves-the-battlefield abilities) will trigger. They'll be put on the stack after state-based actions are checked.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[152086]]></id><name><![CDATA[Quillspike]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Beast]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{BG}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{BG}, Remove a -1/-1 counter from a creature you control: Quillspike gets +3/+3 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[While it's true that a quillspike does heal the sick, it's just because it finds them tastier that way.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Carl Critchlow]]></artist><number><![CDATA[126]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153487]]></id><name><![CDATA[Raven's Crime]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target player discards a card.<br>Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It plucks away memories like choice bits of carrion.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Warren Mahy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[41]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Casting a card by using its retrace ability works just like casting any other card, with two exceptions: You're casting the card from your graveyard rather than your hand, and you must discard a land card in addition to any other costs. <br>8/1/2008 : A retrace card cast from your graveyard follows the normal timing rules for its card type. <br>8/1/2008 : When a retrace card you cast from your graveyard resolves or is countered, it's put back into your graveyard. You may use the retrace ability to cast it again. <br>8/1/2008 : If the active player casts a spell that has retrace, that player may cast that card again after it resolves, before another player can remove the card from the graveyard. The active player has priority after the spell resolves, so he or she can immediately cast a new spell. Since casting a card with retrace from the graveyard moves that card onto the stack, no one else would have the chance to affect it while it's still in the graveyard.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153442]]></id><name><![CDATA[Razorfin Abolisher]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Merfolk Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}{U}, {T}: Return target creature with a counter on it to its owner's hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Once you have been marked by the merrow, you are not long for their waters.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[William O'Connor]]></artist><number><![CDATA[28]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Razorfin Abolisher's ability can target a creature with any kind of counter on it, not just a -1/-1 counter. <br>8/1/2008 : If the targeted creature no longer has any counters on it when the ability resolves, the ability will be countered because its only target is illegal. The creature will stay on the battlefield.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153435]]></id><name><![CDATA[Recumbent Bliss]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature can't attack or block.<br>At the beginning of your upkeep, you may gain 1 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Kithkin somnomancers enjoy the peaceful dreams wafting from their victims.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Todd Lockwood]]></artist><number><![CDATA[13]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The triggered ability is on the Aura, not the creature. It triggers at the beginning of the upkeep of Recumbent Bliss's controller, not the enchanted creature's controller, and Recumbent Bliss's controller will gain the life.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[147373]]></id><name><![CDATA[Regal Force]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{G}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Regal Force enters the battlefield, draw a card for each green creature you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It rarely moves, standing stock still in its clearing. When it does stir, ravens stop their cawing and crickets their chirping. All of nature watches in awed silence.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Brandon Kitkouski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[74]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[158108]]></id><name><![CDATA[Rekindled Flame]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Rekindled Flame deals 4 damage to target creature or player.<br>At the beginning of your upkeep, if an opponent has no cards in hand, you may return Rekindled Flame from your graveyard to your hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Zoltan Boros & Gabor Szikszai]]></artist><number><![CDATA[61]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Rekindled Flame's triggered ability has an "intervening 'if' clause." That means (1) the ability won't trigger at all unless one of your opponents already has no cards in hand as your upkeep begins, and (2) the ability will do nothing if each of your opponents manages to get a card in hand by the time it resolves. <br>8/1/2008 : You don't specify an opponent; the ability will check all of them to see if at least one meets the condition. The opponent that meets the condition when the ability triggers and the one who meets the condition when it resolves can be different players.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[158902]]></id><name><![CDATA[Rendclaw Trow]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Troll]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{BG}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)<br>Persist (When this creature dies, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Warren Mahy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[127]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157291]]></id><name><![CDATA[Restless Apparition]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Spirit]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{WB}{WB}{WB}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{WB}{WB}{WB}: Restless Apparition gets +3/+3 until end of turn.<br>Persist (When this creature dies, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jeff Easley]]></artist><number><![CDATA[94]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151114]]></id><name><![CDATA[Rise of the Hobgoblins]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{RW}{RW}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Rise of the Hobgoblins enters the battlefield, you may pay {X}. If you do, put X 1/1 red and white Goblin Soldier creature tokens onto the battlefield.<br>{RW}: Red creatures and white creatures you control gain first strike until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[A river even the merrow dare not cross.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jeff Miracola]]></artist><number><![CDATA[145]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : When the enters-the-battlefield ability resolves, you choose the value of X, pay for it, and put the tokens onto the battlefield. You can activate mana abilities to pay for {X}, but no one can cast spells or activate abilities in response to this choice.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151068]]></id><name><![CDATA[Riverfall Mimic]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Shapeshifter]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{UR}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever you cast a spell that's both blue and red, Riverfall Mimic becomes 3/3 and is unblockable until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Mimics don't hide their natural form well, but their disguises work well enough on boggarts.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Franz Vohwinkel]]></artist><number><![CDATA[111]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The ability triggers whenever you cast a spell that's both of its listed colors. It doesn't matter whether that spell also happens to be any other colors. <br>8/1/2008 : If you cast a spell that's the two appropriate colors for the second time in a turn, the ability triggers again. The Mimic will once again become the power and toughness stated in its ability, which could overwrite power- and toughness-setting effects that have been applied to it in the meantime. <br>8/1/2008 : Any other abilities the Mimic may have gained are not affected. <br>10/1/2009 : The effect from the ability overwrites other effects that set power and/or toughness if and only if those effects existed before the ability resolved. It will not overwrite effects that modify power or toughness (whether from a static ability, counters, or a resolved spell or ability), nor will it overwrite effects that set power and toughness which come into existence after the ability resolves. Effects that switch the creature's power and toughness are always applied after any other power or toughness changing effects, including this one, regardless of the order in which they are created.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153434]]></id><name><![CDATA[Rugged Prairie]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.<br>{RW}, {T}: Add {R}{R}, {R}{W}, or {W}{W} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Hobs bury their kin far from home. They believe the dry, open ground keeps hags from stealing the bones and gwyllions from stealing the spirits.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Fred Fields]]></artist><number><![CDATA[178]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157204]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sanity Grinding]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{U}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Chroma — Reveal the top ten cards of your library. For each blue mana symbol in the mana costs of the revealed cards, target opponent puts the top card of his or her library into his or her graveyard. Then put the cards you revealed this way on the bottom of your library in any order.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Lars Grant-West]]></artist><number><![CDATA[29]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Chroma abilities check only mana costs, which are found in a card's upper right corner. They don't count mana symbols that appear in a card's text box. <br>8/1/2008 : Chroma abilities count hybrid mana symbols of the appropriate color. For example, a card with mana cost {3}{U/R}{U/R} has two red mana symbols in its mana cost. <br>8/1/2008 : If there are fewer than ten cards in your library, reveal them all. For each blue mana symbol in those cards' mana costs, the targeted opponent puts the top card of his or her library into his or her graveyard. Then you reorder your entire library as you choose.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157973]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sapling of Colfenor]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Treefolk Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{BG}{BG}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Sapling of Colfenor is indestructible.<br>Whenever Sapling of Colfenor attacks, reveal the top card of your library. If it's a creature card, you gain life equal to that card's toughness, lose life equal to its power, then put it into your hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Her plans may yet bear fruit.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[John Avon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[128]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Lethal damage and effects that say "destroy" won't cause Sapling of Colfenor to be put into the graveyard. However, Sapling of Colfenor will be put into the graveyard if its toughness becomes 0 or less, if it's sacrificed, or if another Sapling of Colfenor is on the battlefield (due to the "legend rule"). <br>8/1/2008 : The triggered ability results in three sequential events: you gain some life (subject to effects that might alter life gain), then lose some life (subject to other effects that might alter life loss), and then put the card into your hand. <br>8/1/2008 : If a creature card has "*" in its power or toughness, the ability that defines "*" works in all zones. Note that the card is in your library when Sapling of Colfenor's ability checks the card's power and toughness. <br>8/1/2008 : If the revealed card is not a creature card, it remains on top of your library.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153438]]></id><name><![CDATA[Savage Conception]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Put a 3/3 green Beast creature token onto the battlefield.<br>Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Some beasts are born not of a mother, but of magic.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[William O'Connor]]></artist><number><![CDATA[75]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Casting a card by using its retrace ability works just like casting any other card, with two exceptions: You're casting the card from your graveyard rather than your hand, and you must discard a land card in addition to any other costs. <br>8/1/2008 : A retrace card cast from your graveyard follows the normal timing rules for its card type. <br>8/1/2008 : When a retrace card you cast from your graveyard resolves or is countered, it's put back into your graveyard. You may use the retrace ability to cast it again. <br>8/1/2008 : If the active player casts a spell that has retrace, that player may cast that card again after it resolves, before another player can remove the card from the graveyard. The active player has priority after the spell resolves, so he or she can immediately cast a new spell. Since casting a card with retrace from the graveyard moves that card onto the stack, no one else would have the chance to affect it while it's still in the graveyard.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157979]]></id><name><![CDATA[Scarecrone]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Scarecrow]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}, Sacrifice a Scarecrow: Draw a card.<br>{4}, {T}: Return target artifact creature card from your graveyard to the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Her poppets bring joy to the truly depraved.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jesper Ejsing]]></artist><number><![CDATA[172]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[152015]]></id><name><![CDATA[Scourge of the Nobilis]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{RW}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>As long as enchanted creature is red, it gets +1/+1 and has "{RW}: This creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn."<br>As long as enchanted creature is white, it gets +1/+1 and has lifelink. (Damage dealt by the creature also causes its controller to gain that much life.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dan Scott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[146]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If the enchanted creature is both of the listed colors, it will get both bonuses. <br>8/1/2008 : The controller of the enchanted creature, not the controller of Scourge of the Nobilis, can activate the +1/+0 ability. <br>8/1/2008 : Once the +1/+0 ability is activated, it exists independently of the creature and Scourge of the Nobilis. It will resolve, and the creature will retain the bonus for the rest of the turn, even if Scourge of the Nobilis stops enchanting that creature.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[159067]]></id><name><![CDATA[Selkie Hedge-Mage]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Merfolk Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{GU}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Selkie Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Forests, you may gain 3 life.<br>When Selkie Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, if you control two or more Islands, you may return target tapped creature to its owner's hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Larry MacDougall]]></artist><number><![CDATA[158]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Each of the triggered abilities has an "intervening 'if' clause." That means (1) the ability won't trigger at all unless you control two or more lands of the appropriate land type when the Hedge-Mage enters the battlefield, and (2) the ability will do nothing if you don't control two or more lands of the appropriate land type by the time it resolves. <br>8/1/2008 : Both abilities trigger at the same time. You can put them on the stack in any order. <br>8/1/2008 : Each of the triggered abilities look at your lands individually. This means that if you only control two dual-lands of the appropriate types, both of the abilities will trigger <br>8/1/2008 : Both abilities are optional; you choose whether to use them when they resolve. If an ability has a target, you must choose a target even if you don't plan to use the ability.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[158297]]></id><name><![CDATA[Shell Skulkin]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Scarecrow]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{3}: Target blue creature gains shroud until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Skulkins confer strange benefits on unsuspecting patrons.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Cole Eastburn]]></artist><number><![CDATA[173]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151147]]></id><name><![CDATA[Shorecrasher Mimic]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Shapeshifter]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{GU}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever you cast a spell that's both green and blue, Shorecrasher Mimic becomes 5/3 and gains trample until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The Aurora replaced the changelings' innocence with malice and their curiosity with hunger.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Franz Vohwinkel]]></artist><number><![CDATA[159]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The ability triggers whenever you cast a spell that's both of its listed colors. It doesn't matter whether that spell also happens to be any other colors. <br>8/1/2008 : If you cast a spell that's the two appropriate colors for the second time in a turn, the ability triggers again. The Mimic will once again become the power and toughness stated in its ability, which could overwrite power- and toughness-setting effects that have been applied to it in the meantime. <br>8/1/2008 : Any other abilities the Mimic may have gained are not affected. <br>10/1/2009 : The effect from the ability overwrites other effects that set power and/or toughness if and only if those effects existed before the ability resolved. It will not overwrite effects that modify power or toughness (whether from a static ability, counters, or a resolved spell or ability), nor will it overwrite effects that set power and toughness which come into existence after the ability resolves. Effects that switch the creature's power and toughness are always applied after any other power or toughness changing effects, including this one, regardless of the order in which they are created.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153486]]></id><name><![CDATA[Shrewd Hatchling]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{UR}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Shrewd Hatchling enters the battlefield with four -1/-1 counters on it.<br>{UR}: Target creature can't block Shrewd Hatchling this turn.<br>Whenever you cast a blue spell, remove a -1/-1 counter from Shrewd Hatchling.<br>Whenever you cast a red spell, remove a -1/-1 counter from Shrewd Hatchling.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Carl Frank]]></artist><number><![CDATA[112]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If you cast a spell that's both of the listed colors, both abilities will trigger. You'll remove a total of two -1/-1 counters from the Hatchling. <br>8/1/2008 : If there are no -1/-1 counters on it when the triggered ability resolves, the ability does nothing. There is no penalty for not being able to remove a counter.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[150999]]></id><name><![CDATA[Slippery Bogle]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Beast]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{GU}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Hexproof (This creature can't be the target of spells or abilities your opponents control.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Bogles are very tasty if you can get the skin off. It's getting a blade on them that's the problem.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Allsop]]></artist><number><![CDATA[160]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157211]]></id><name><![CDATA[Smoldering Butcher]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[A cinder's axe bears no marks from parrying a foe's blade.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Zoltan Boros & Gabor Szikszai]]></artist><number><![CDATA[42]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157401]]></id><name><![CDATA[Snakeform]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{GU}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target creature loses all abilities and becomes a 1/1 green Snake until end of turn.<br>Draw a card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Losing his possessions distressed him, but the lack of limbs was strangely liberating.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jim Nelson]]></artist><number><![CDATA[161]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Snakeform doesn't counter abilities that have already triggered or been activated. In particular, there is no way to cast this to stop a creature's "At the beginning of your upkeep" or "When this creature enters the battlefield" abilities from triggering. <br>8/1/2008 : If the affected creature gains an ability after Snakeform resolves, it will keep that ability. <br>8/1/2008 : If Snakeform affects a creature with changeling, the creature will lose its changeling ability, and will no longer be all creature types. <br>10/1/2009 : The power/toughness-setting effect overwrites other effects that set power and toughness only if those effects existed before this spell resolved. It will not overwrite effects that modify power or toughness (whether from a static ability, counters, or a resolved spell or ability), nor will it overwrite effects that set power and toughness which come into existence after this spell resolves. Effects that switch the creature's power and toughness are always applied after any other power or toughness changing effects, including this one, regardless of the order in which they are created.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[158900]]></id><name><![CDATA[Soot Imp]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Imp]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Whenever a player casts a nonblack spell, that player loses 1 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["If one gets in your chimney, you're going to need a long wick and a barrel of bangstuff to get it out."<br>—Hob Heddil]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jesper Ejsing]]></artist><number><![CDATA[43]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : This ability affects all players, including you. <br>8/1/2008 : A hybrid spell that's black and another color is *not* a nonblack spell. Since it's black, it can't be nonblack!]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151150]]></id><name><![CDATA[Soul Reap]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Destroy target nongreen creature. Its controller loses 3 life if you've cast another black spell this turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Their thoughtweft carried Darial's last thoughts back to his doun. They sorely wished it had not.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Izzy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[44]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : A hybrid creature that's green and another color is *not* a nongreen creature. Since it's green, it can't be nongreen! <br>8/1/2008 : Soul Reap doesn't check whether you've cast another black spell until Soul Reap resolves. If you cast Soul Reap, then cast a black instant in response, the creature's controller will lose the life when Soul Reap resolves. <br>8/1/2008 : Although Soul Reap says it looks for "another black spell," there's no requirement that Soul Reap actually be cast (or be black) for this part of its ability to work. For example, if a spell such as Commandeer causes you to gain control of Soul Reap, it'll still check whether you cast a black spell this turn, even though you didn't cast Soul Reap itself.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[142054]]></id><name><![CDATA[Soul Snuffers]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Soul Snuffers enters the battlefield, put a -1/-1 counter on each creature.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[They once sought to unite with the flame of transcendence. Now they seek only to extinguish the lights of others.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Izzy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[45]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The ability puts a -1/-1 counter on Soul Snuffers, too.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151169]]></id><name><![CDATA[Spirit of the Hearth]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Cat Spirit]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>You have hexproof. (You can't be the target of spells or abilities your opponents control.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Thieves know that a snarl in the night means, "Rob another house."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jason Chan]]></artist><number><![CDATA[14]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[152044]]></id><name><![CDATA[Spitemare]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{RW}{RW}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever Spitemare is dealt damage, it deals that much damage to target creature or player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["I knew a creature carved from a dream of wild freedom. Any attempt to leash or exploit it failed, and at terrible cost."<br>—Ashling]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Matt Cavotta]]></artist><number><![CDATA[147]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Even if the amount of damage dealt to Spitemare is enough to destroy it, Spitemare's ability will trigger and it will deal the full amount of damage to the target.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[154261]]></id><name><![CDATA[Spitting Image]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{GU}{GU}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Put a token that's a copy of target creature onto the battlefield.<br>Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Spitting is the customary greeting between a creature and its magical impostor.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jim Nelson]]></artist><number><![CDATA[162]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Casting a card by using its retrace ability works just like casting any other card, with two exceptions: You're casting the card from your graveyard rather than your hand, and you must discard a land card in addition to any other costs. <br>8/1/2008 : A retrace card cast from your graveyard follows the normal timing rules for its card type. <br>8/1/2008 : When a retrace card you cast from your graveyard resolves or is countered, it's put back into your graveyard. You may use the retrace ability to cast it again. <br>8/1/2008 : If the active player casts a spell that has retrace, that player may cast that card again after it resolves, before another player can remove the card from the graveyard. The active player has priority after the spell resolves, so he or she can immediately cast a new spell. Since casting a card with retrace from the graveyard moves that card onto the stack, no one else would have the chance to affect it while it's still in the graveyard. <br>8/1/2008 : As the token is created, it checks the printed values of the creature it's copying -- or, if that creature is itself a token, the original characteristics of that token as stated by the effect that put it onto the battlefield -- as well as any copy effects that have been applied to it. It won't copy counters on the creature, nor will it copy other effects that have changed the creature's power, toughness, types, color, or so on.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157976]]></id><name><![CDATA[Springjack Pasture]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.<br>{4}, {T}: Put a 0/1 white Goat creature token onto the battlefield.<br>{T}, Sacrifice X Goats: Add X mana of any one color to your mana pool. You gain X life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Terese Nielsen]]></artist><number><![CDATA[179]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Springjack Pasture's last ability is a mana ability. The whole ability -- including the life gain -- doesn't use the stack and therefore can't be responded to. <br>8/1/2008 : If you sacrifice no Goats, you'll add no mana to your mana pool and you'll gain no life. <br>8/1/2008 : You can sacrifice any Goats you control to activate the third ability, not just Goats created by Springjack Pasture.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153032]]></id><name><![CDATA[Springjack Shepherd]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Kithkin Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Chroma — When Springjack Shepherd enters the battlefield, put a 0/1 white Goat creature token onto the battlefield for each white mana symbol in the mana costs of permanents you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Better for a doun to lose its cenn than its springjacks."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Thomas Denmark]]></artist><number><![CDATA[15]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Chroma abilities check only mana costs, which are found in a card's upper right corner. They don't count mana symbols that appear in a card's text box. <br>8/1/2008 : Chroma abilities count hybrid mana symbols of the appropriate color. For example, a card with mana cost {3}{U/R}{U/R} has two red mana symbols in its mana cost. <br>8/1/2008 : The effect counts the mana symbols in this cards mana cost as well.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151120]]></id><name><![CDATA[Stalker Hag]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Hag]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{BG}{BG}{BG}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Swampwalk, forestwalk]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Her hunt is silent until a bone snaps or flesh tears. Her victims never know to scream.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Kendall]]></artist><number><![CDATA[129]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153049]]></id><name><![CDATA[Stigma Lasher]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)<br>Whenever Stigma Lasher deals damage to a player, that player can't gain life for the rest of the game.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The Extinguisher's curse lasted long after her departure.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Aleksi Briclot]]></artist><number><![CDATA[62]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Once the last ability resolves, it will be in effect for the rest of the game. It doesn't matter if Stigma Lasher remains on the battlefield or not. <br>8/1/2008 : If a player has been dealt damage by Stigma Lasher, the following things are true: -- Spells and abilities that would normally cause that player to gain life still resolve, but the life-gain part simply has no effect. -- If a cost includes having that player gain life (like Invigorate's alternative cost does), that cost can't be paid. -- Effects that would replace having that player gain life with some other effect won't be able to do anything because it's impossible for that player to gain life. -- Effects that replace an event with having that player gain life (like Words of Worship's effect does) will end up replacing the event with nothing. -- If an effect says to set that player's life total to a certain number, and that number is higher than the player's current life total, that part of the effect won't do anything. (If the number is lower than that player's current life total, the effect will work as normal.)]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153037]]></id><name><![CDATA[Stillmoon Cavalier]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Zombie Knight]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{WB}{WB}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Protection from white and from black<br>{WB}: Stillmoon Cavalier gains flying until end of turn.<br>{WB}: Stillmoon Cavalier gains first strike until end of turn.<br>{WB}{WB}: Stillmoon Cavalier gets +1/+0 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Christopher Moeller]]></artist><number><![CDATA[95]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151124]]></id><name><![CDATA[Stream Hopper]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Goblin]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{UR}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{UR}: Stream Hopper gains flying until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Like many who dwell in Shadowmoor now, he was robbed of his better half by the Aurora.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Allsop]]></artist><number><![CDATA[113]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153477]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sturdy Hatchling]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{GU}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Sturdy Hatchling enters the battlefield with four -1/-1 counters on it.<br>{GU}: Sturdy Hatchling gains shroud until end of turn.<br>Whenever you cast a green spell, remove a -1/-1 counter from Sturdy Hatchling.<br>Whenever you cast a blue spell, remove a -1/-1 counter from Sturdy Hatchling.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Darrell Riche]]></artist><number><![CDATA[163]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If you cast a spell that's both of the listed colors, both abilities will trigger. You'll remove a total of two -1/-1 counters from the Hatchling. <br>8/1/2008 : If there are no -1/-1 counters on it when the triggered ability resolves, the ability does nothing. There is no penalty for not being able to remove a counter.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153420]]></id><name><![CDATA[Suture Spirit]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Spirit]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>{WB}{WB}{WB}: Regenerate target creature.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Is her need to heal born out of compassion or penance?]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Larry MacDougall]]></artist><number><![CDATA[16]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[154348]]></id><name><![CDATA[Swirling Spriggan]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Goblin Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{GU}{GU}: Target creature you control becomes the color or colors of your choice until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[After its encounter with the spriggan, the patrol was red with anger, green with envy, white with fear, and painfully black and blue.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Thomas M. Baxa]]></artist><number><![CDATA[76]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : You can choose any color or combination of colors. You can't choose colorless.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153447]]></id><name><![CDATA[Syphon Life]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target player loses 2 life and you gain 2 life.<br>Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Leeches never tire of feeding.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dan Seagrave]]></artist><number><![CDATA[46]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Casting a card by using its retrace ability works just like casting any other card, with two exceptions: You're casting the card from your graveyard rather than your hand, and you must discard a land card in addition to any other costs. <br>8/1/2008 : A retrace card cast from your graveyard follows the normal timing rules for its card type. <br>8/1/2008 : When a retrace card you cast from your graveyard resolves or is countered, it's put back into your graveyard. You may use the retrace ability to cast it again. <br>8/1/2008 : If the active player casts a spell that has retrace, that player may cast that card again after it resolves, before another player can remove the card from the graveyard. The active player has priority after the spell resolves, so he or she can immediately cast a new spell. Since casting a card with retrace from the graveyard moves that card onto the stack, no one else would have the chance to affect it while it's still in the graveyard.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151142]]></id><name><![CDATA[Talara's Bane]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target opponent reveals his or her hand. You choose a green or white creature card from it. You gain life equal that creature card's toughness, then that player discards that card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Your thoughts betray you."<br>—Illulia of Nighthearth]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Joshua Hagler]]></artist><number><![CDATA[47]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If the creature card has "*" in its power or toughness, the ability that defines "*" works in all zones. Note that the card is in the opponent's hand when Talara's Bane checks its toughness.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157395]]></id><name><![CDATA[Talara's Battalion]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elf Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample<br>Cast Talara's Battalion only if you've cast another green spell this turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The safewright Talara protects a delicate woodland waterfall. She has vowed to send wave after wave of warriors to slay any who would dare disturb its beauty.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Todd Lockwood]]></artist><number><![CDATA[77]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153430]]></id><name><![CDATA[Talonrend]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>{UR}: Talonrend gets +1/-1 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Change is a denizen of Shadowmoor as much as ouphes and noggles are.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Nils Hamm]]></artist><number><![CDATA[30]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157411]]></id><name><![CDATA[Thunderblust]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[7]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Haste<br>Thunderblust has trample as long as it has a -1/-1 counter on it.<br>Persist (When this creature dies, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dan Scott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[63]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151096]]></id><name><![CDATA[Tilling Treefolk]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Treefolk Druid]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Tilling Treefolk enters the battlefield, you may return up to two target land cards from your graveyard to your hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[He digs his roots into barren ground, searching for old seeds that never had the chance to sprout.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[rk post]]></artist><number><![CDATA[78]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[152140]]></id><name><![CDATA[Trapjaw Kelpie]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Beast]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{GU}{GU}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flash<br>Persist (When this creature dies, if it had no -1/-1 counters on it, return it to the battlefield under its owner's control with a -1/-1 counter on it.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Travelers in these waters leave a bit of themselves behind.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Lars Grant-West]]></artist><number><![CDATA[164]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153425]]></id><name><![CDATA[Twilight Mire]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.<br>{BG}, {T}: Add {B}{B}, {B}{G}, or {G}{G} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[As their roots soaked in a weak tea of bogwater and decay, the trees absorbed the essence of death into their living tissue.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Rob Alexander]]></artist><number><![CDATA[180]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153436]]></id><name><![CDATA[Twinblade Slasher]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elf Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Wither (This deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)<br>{1}{G}: Twinblade Slasher gets +2/+2 until end of turn. Activate this ability only once each turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Righteous anger hones a humble soul.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Trevor Hairsine]]></artist><number><![CDATA[79]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157399]]></id><name><![CDATA[Umbra Stalker]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{B}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[*]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[*]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Chroma — Umbra Stalker's power and toughness are each equal to the number of black mana symbols in the mana costs of cards in your graveyard.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Don't venture into the darkness, lest it decide not to let you leave.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Daarken]]></artist><number><![CDATA[48]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : This is a characteristic-defining ability, which means it functions in all zones. You include the symbols in the Stalker's own mana cost if you need to determine its power and/or toughness while it's in the graveyard. <br>8/1/2008 : Chroma abilities check only mana costs, which are found in a card's upper right corner. They don't count mana symbols that appear in a card's text box. <br>8/1/2008 : Chroma abilities count hybrid mana symbols of the appropriate color. For example, a card with mana cost {3}{U/R}{U/R} has two red mana symbols in its mana cost.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151083]]></id><name><![CDATA[Unmake]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{WB}{WB}{WB}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Exile target creature.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[A gwyllion's favorite trap is the vanity mirror. A bewitched piece of glass traps the looker's soul and does away with the body.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steven Belledin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[96]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157416]]></id><name><![CDATA[Unnerving Assault]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{UR}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Creatures your opponents control get -1/-0 until end of turn if {U} was spent to cast Unnerving Assault, and creatures you control get +1/+0 until end of turn if {R} was spent to cast it. (Do both if {U}{R} was spent.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The scales of battle rarely balance.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ron Spencer]]></artist><number><![CDATA[114]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The spell cares about what mana was spent to pay its total cost, not just what mana was spent to pay the hybrid part of its cost. <br>8/1/2008 : The spell checks on resolution to see if any mana of the stated colors was spent to pay its cost. If so, it doesn't matter how much mana of that color was spent. <br>8/1/2008 : If the spell is copied, the copy will never have had mana of the stated color paid for it, no matter what colors were spent on the original spell. <br>8/1/2008 : Unnerving Assault affects only creatures on the battlefield at the time it resolves. If a creature enters the battlefield later that turn, it won't be affected. <br>8/1/2008 : If a creature changes controllers later in the turn, that won't change how Unnerving Assault affected it.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157202]]></id><name><![CDATA[Unwilling Recruit]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{X}{R}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Gain control of target creature until end of turn. Untap that creature. It gets +X/+0 and gains haste until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Frorn didn't want to be kept, but he didn't want to be thrown back either.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Allsop]]></artist><number><![CDATA[64]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : You may target a creature you already control with Unwilling Recruit. If you do, you'll gain control of that creature (which usually won't have any visible effect), untap it, and it'll get +X/+0 until end of turn.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153444]]></id><name><![CDATA[Voracious Hatchling]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{WB}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Lifelink<br>Voracious Hatchling enters the battlefield with four -1/-1 counters on it.<br>Whenever you cast a white spell, remove a -1/-1 counter from Voracious Hatchling.<br>Whenever you cast a black spell, remove a -1/-1 counter from Voracious Hatchling.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jeremy Enecio]]></artist><number><![CDATA[97]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If you cast a spell that's both of the listed colors, both abilities will trigger. You'll remove a total of two -1/-1 counters from the Hatchling. <br>8/1/2008 : If there are no -1/-1 counters on it when the triggered ability resolves, the ability does nothing. There is no penalty for not being able to remove a counter.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157405]]></id><name><![CDATA[Wake Thrasher]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Merfolk Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever a permanent you control becomes untapped, Wake Thrasher gets +1/+1 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Anyone who thinks merrows have more brains than brawn has never been run over by one.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jesper Ejsing]]></artist><number><![CDATA[31]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : If permanents you control become untapped during your untap step, Wake Thresher's ability will trigger that many times. However, since no player gets priority during the untap step, those abilities wait to be put on the stack until your upkeep starts. At that time, all your "beginning of upkeep" triggers will also trigger. You can put them and Wake Thresher's abilities on the stack in any order.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[157972]]></id><name><![CDATA[Ward of Bones]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{6}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Each opponent who controls more creatures than you can't play creature cards. The same is true for artifacts, enchantments, and lands.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Mages dare not attempt magic in its grotesque presence.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[David Martin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[174]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Spelling this out completely: -- Each opponent who controls more creatures than you can't play creature cards. -- Each opponent who controls more artifacts than you can't play artifact cards. -- Each opponent who controls more enchantments than you can't play enchantment cards. -- Each opponent who controls more lands than you can't play land cards.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[158107]]></id><name><![CDATA[Waves of Aggression]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{RW}{RW}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Untap all creatures that attacked this turn. After this main phase, there is an additional combat phase followed by an additional main phase.<br>Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jim Pavelec]]></artist><number><![CDATA[148]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Casting a card by using its retrace ability works just like casting any other card, with two exceptions: You're casting the card from your graveyard rather than your hand, and you must discard a land card in addition to any other costs. <br>8/1/2008 : A retrace card cast from your graveyard follows the normal timing rules for its card type. <br>8/1/2008 : When a retrace card you cast from your graveyard resolves or is countered, it's put back into your graveyard. You may use the retrace ability to cast it again. <br>8/1/2008 : If the active player casts a spell that has retrace, that player may cast that card again after it resolves, before another player can remove the card from the graveyard. The active player has priority after the spell resolves, so he or she can immediately cast a new spell. Since casting a card with retrace from the graveyard moves that card onto the stack, no one else would have the chance to affect it while it's still in the graveyard. <br>8/1/2008 : Waves of Aggression untaps all creatures that attacked this turn, not just those that attacked during the most recent combat phase. <br>8/1/2008 : If it's somehow not a main phase when Waves of Aggression resolves, all it does is untap all creatures that attacked that turn. No new phases are created.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151097]]></id><name><![CDATA[Wickerbough Elder]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Treefolk Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Wickerbough Elder enters the battlefield with a -1/-1 counter on it.<br>{G}, Remove a -1/-1 counter from Wickerbough Elder: Destroy target artifact or enchantment.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Living scarecrows make a mockery of the natural order. Dead ones make fine hats."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jesper Ejsing]]></artist><number><![CDATA[80]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[153476]]></id><name><![CDATA[Wilderness Hypnotist]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Merfolk Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Target red or green creature gets -2/-0 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["I felt as if I were moving in brackish water, as if I were drowning, even though I knew I stood on dry land."<br>—Dindun of Kulrath Mine]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Rebecca Guay]]></artist><number><![CDATA[32]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151143]]></id><name><![CDATA[Wistful Selkie]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Merfolk Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{GU}{GU}{GU}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Wistful Selkie enters the battlefield, draw a card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Selkies call to a sea they never swam, in a tongue they never spoke, with a song they never learned.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mark Tedin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[165]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[158599]]></id><name><![CDATA[Woodlurker Mimic]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Shapeshifter]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{BG}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever you cast a spell that's both black and green, Woodlurker Mimic becomes 4/5 and gains wither until end of turn. (It deals damage to creatures in the form of -1/-1 counters.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[A mimic's disguise fools its victims just long enough to draw them within range of its venomous tentacles.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Franz Vohwinkel]]></artist><number><![CDATA[130]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : The ability triggers whenever you cast a spell that's both of its listed colors. It doesn't matter whether that spell also happens to be any other colors. <br>8/1/2008 : If you cast a spell that's the two appropriate colors for the second time in a turn, the ability triggers again. The Mimic will once again become the power and toughness stated in its ability, which could overwrite power- and toughness-setting effects that have been applied to it in the meantime. <br>8/1/2008 : Any other abilities the Mimic may have gained are not affected. <br>10/1/2009 : The effect from the ability overwrites other effects that set power and/or toughness if and only if those effects existed before the ability resolved. It will not overwrite effects that modify power or toughness (whether from a static ability, counters, or a resolved spell or ability), nor will it overwrite effects that set power and toughness which come into existence after the ability resolves. Effects that switch the creature's power and toughness are always applied after any other power or toughness changing effects, including this one, regardless of the order in which they are created.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[151135]]></id><name><![CDATA[Worm Harvest]]></name><set><![CDATA[EVE]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{BG}{BG}{BG}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Put a 1/1 black and green Worm creature token onto the battlefield for each land card in your graveyard.<br>Retrace (You may cast this card from your graveyard by discarding a land card in addition to paying its other costs.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chuck Lukacs]]></artist><number><![CDATA[131]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : Casting a card by using its retrace ability works just like casting any other card, with two exceptions: You're casting the card from your graveyard rather than your hand, and you must discard a land card in addition to any other costs. <br>8/1/2008 : A retrace card cast from your graveyard follows the normal timing rules for its card type. <br>8/1/2008 : When a retrace card you cast from your graveyard resolves or is countered, it's put back into your graveyard. You may use the retrace ability to cast it again. <br>8/1/2008 : If the active player casts a spell that has retrace, that player may cast that card again after it resolves, before another player can remove the card from the graveyard. The active player has priority after the spell resolves, so he or she can immediately cast a new spell. Since casting a card with retrace from the graveyard moves that card onto the stack, no one else would have the chance to affect it while it's still in the graveyard. <br>8/1/2008 : If you cast Worm Harvest from your graveyard by using retrace, the land you discard as an additional cost will be counted by Worm Harvest when it resolves.]]></ruling></card></cards></mtg_carddatabase>