<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><mtg_carddatabase><bdd_date><![CDATA[1-5-2013]]></bdd_date><bdd_version><![CDATA[1.00]]></bdd_version><bdd_name>Magic the Gathering® Card Database</bdd_name><bdd_editor>Wizards of the Coast LLC</bdd_editor><sets><set><name><![CDATA[Magic: The Gathering Launch Parties]]></name><code><![CDATA[GLP]]></code><code_magiccards><![CDATA[MLP]]></code_magiccards><date><![CDATA[00/0000]]></date><is_promo><![CDATA[True]]></is_promo></set></sets><cards><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_4]]></id><name><![CDATA[Ajani Vengeant]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Planeswalker — Ajani]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power></power><toughness></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[3]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[+1: Target permanent doesn't untap during its controller's next untap step.<br>-2: Ajani Vengeant deals 3 damage to target creature or player and you gain 3 life.<br>-7: Destroy all lands target player controls.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jason Chan]]></artist><number><![CDATA[4]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2008: You may target any permanent with <u>Ajani Vengeant</u>'s first ability. It doesn't have to be tapped.<br><br>10/1/2008: The first ability tracks the permanent, but not its controller. If the permanent changes controllers before its first controller's next untap step has come around, then it won't untap during its new controller's next untap step.<br><br>10/1/2008: If two or more planeswalkers on the battlefield share a planeswalker subtype, all are put into their owners' graveyards. This means that if both <u>Ajani Vengeant</u> and the _Lorwyn_ card Ajani Goldmane are on the battlefield, both are put into their owners' graveyards.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_11]]></id><name><![CDATA[Ancient Hellkite]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Dragon]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{R}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>{R}: Ancient Hellkite deals 1 damage to target creature defending player controls. Activate this ability only if Ancient Hellkite is attacking.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[When a dragon attacks, there are no bystanders.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Wayne Reynolds]]></artist><number><![CDATA[11]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010: After <u>Ancient Hellkite</u> is declared as an attacker, or is put onto the battlefield attacking, its second ability may be activated. Unless <u>Ancient Hellkite</u> leaves combat, it continues to be attacking (so its ability may still be activated) through the end of combat step.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_7]]></id><name><![CDATA[Ant Queen]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Insect]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}{G}: Put a 1/1 green Insect creature token onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Kill the queen first, or we'll be fighting her drones forever. It is not in a queen's nature to have enough servants."<br>-Borzard, exterminator captain]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ron Spencer]]></artist><number><![CDATA[7]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_20]]></id><name><![CDATA[Deadbridge Goliath]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Insect]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Scavenge {4}{G}{G} ({4}{G}{G}, Exile this card from your graveyard: Put a number of +1/+1 counters equal to this card's power on target creature. Scavenge only as a sorcery.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Some Golgari insects live for centuries—and they never stop growing.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Nils Hamm]]></artist><number><![CDATA[20]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>4/15/2013: Exiling the creature card with scavenge is part of the cost of activating the scavenge ability. Once the ability is activated and the cost is paid, it’s too late to stop the ability from being activated by trying to remove the creature card from the graveyard.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_1]]></id><name><![CDATA[Earwig Squad]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Goblin Rogue]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Prowl {2}{B} (You may cast this for its prowl cost if you dealt combat damage to a player this turn with a Goblin or Rogue.)<br>When Earwig Squad enters the battlefield, if its prowl cost was paid, search target opponent's library for three cards and exile them. Then that player shuffles his or her library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Warren Mahy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[1]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_3]]></id><name><![CDATA[Figure of Destiny]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Kithkin]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{RW}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{R/W}: Figure of Destiny becomes a 2/2 Kithkin Spirit.<br>{R/W}{R/W}{R/W}: If Figure of Destiny is a Spirit, it becomes a 4/4 Kithkin Spirit Warrior.<br>{R/W}{R/W}{R/W}{R/W}{R/W}{R/W}: If Figure of Destiny is a Warrior, it becomes an 8/8 Kithkin Spirit Warrior Avatar with flying and first strike.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Scott M. Fischer]]></artist><number><![CDATA[3]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008: None of these abilities has a duration. If one of them resolves, it will remain in effect until the game ends, <u>Figure of Destiny</u> leaves the battlefield, or some subsequent effect changes its characteristics, whichever comes first.<br><br>8/1/2008: <u>Figure of Destiny</u>'s abilities overwrite its power, toughness, and creature types. Typically, those abilities are activated in the order they appear on the card. However, if <u>Figure of Destiny</u> is an 8/8 Kithkin Spirit Warrior Avatar with flying and first strike, and you activate its first ability, it will become a 2/2 Kithkin Spirit that still has flying and first strike.<br><br>8/1/2008: You can activate <u>Figure of Destiny</u>'s second and third abilities regardless of what creature types it is. Each of those abilities checks <u>Figure of Destiny</u>'s creature types when that ability resolves. If <u>Figure of Destiny</u> isn't the appropriate creature type at that time, the ability does nothing.<br><br>8/1/2008: <u>Figure of Destiny</u>'s second ability checks whether it's a Spirit, and its third ability checks whether it's a Warrior. It doesn't matter how it became the appropriate creature type.<br><br>10/1/2009: The effect from the ability overwrites other effects that set power and/or toughness if and only if those effects existed before the ability resolved. It will not overwrite effects that modify power or toughness (whether from a static ability, counters, or a resolved spell or ability), nor will it overwrite effects that set power and toughness which come into existence after the ability resolves. Effects that switch the creature's power and toughness are always applied after any other power or toughness changing effects, including this one, regardless of the order in which they are created.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_15]]></id><name><![CDATA[Garruk's Horde]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Beast]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[7]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[7]]></toughness><loyalty></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample<br>Play with the top card of your library revealed.<br>You may cast the top card of your library if it's a creature card. (Do this only any time you could cast that creature card. You still pay the spell's costs.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kev Walker]]></artist><number><![CDATA[15]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011: Normally, <u>Garruk's Horde</u> allows you to cast the top card of your library if it's a creature card, it's your main phase, and the stack is empty. If that creature card has flash, you'll be able to cast it at the time you could cast an instant, even on an opponent's turn.<br><br>9/22/2011: You'll still pay all costs for that spell, including additional costs. You may also pay alternative costs.<br><br>9/22/2011: While playing with the top card of your library revealed, if you draw multiple cards, reveal each one before you draw it.<br><br>9/22/2011: If the top card of your library is Dryad Arbor (the only card that's both a creature and a land), you can't play it this way. Dryad Arbor can't be cast as a spell.<br><br>4/15/2013: The top card of your library isn't in your hand, so you can't suspend it, cycle it, discard it, or activate any of its activated abilities.<br><br>4/15/2013: If the top card of your library is a land, you can play it if you could play a land.<br><br>4/15/2013: If the top card of your library changes while you're casting a spell or activating an ability, the new top card won't be revealed until you finish casting that spell or activating that ability.<br><br>4/15/2013: When playing with the top card of your library revealed, if an effect tells you to draw several cards, reveal each one before you draw it.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_9]]></id><name><![CDATA[Joraga Warcaller]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elf Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Multikicker {1}{G} (You may pay an additional {1}{G} any number of times as you cast this spell.)<br>Joraga Warcaller enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it for each time it was kicked.<br>Other Elf creatures you control get +1/+1 for each +1/+1 counter on Joraga Warcaller.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kev Walker]]></artist><number><![CDATA[9]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>3/1/2010: The last ability counts the total number of +1/+1 counters on <u>Joraga Warcaller</u>, not just the ones placed on it as a result of its enters-the-battlefield ability.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_6]]></id><name><![CDATA[Knight of New Alara]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Knight]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Each other multicolored creature you control gets +1/+1 for each of its colors.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["I embrace all of Alara, Grixis as much as Bant. Let my former home call me traitor. I do this not for accolades, but because it is right."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[David Palumbo]]></artist><number><![CDATA[6]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>5/1/2009: For example, a white creature gets no bonus. A white and blue creature gets +2/+2. A white, blue, and black creature gets +3/+3, and so on.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_10]]></id><name><![CDATA[Lord of Shatterskull Pass]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Minotaur Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Level up {1}{R} ({1}{R}: Put a level counter on this. Level up only as a sorcery.)<br>LEVEL 1-5<br>6/6<br>LEVEL 6+<br>6/6<br>Whenever Lord of Shatterskull Pass attacks, it deals 6 damage to each creature defending player controls.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Igor Kieryluk]]></artist><number><![CDATA[10]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/15/2010: The abilities a leveler grants to itself don't overwrite any other abilities it may have. In particular, they don't overwrite the creature's level up ability; it always has that.<br><br>6/15/2010: Effects that set a leveler's power or toughness to a specific value, including the effects from a level symbol's ability, apply in timestamp order. The timestamp of each level symbol's ability is the same as the timestamp of the leveler itself, regardless of when the most recent level counter was put on it.<br><br>6/15/2010: Effects that modify a leveler's power or toughness, such as the effects of Giant Growth or Glorious Anthem, will apply to it no matter when they started to take effect. The same is true for counters that change the creature's power or toughness (such as +1/+1 counters) and effects that switch its power and toughness.<br><br>6/15/2010: If another creature becomes a copy of a leveler, all of the leveler's printed abilities -- including those represented by level symbols -- are copied. The current characteristics of the leveler, and the number of level counters on it, are not. The abilities, power, and toughness of the copy will be determined based on how many level counters are on the copy.<br><br>6/15/2010: A creature's level is based on how many level counters it has on it, not how many times its level up ability has been activated or has resolved. If a leveler gets level counters due to some other effect (such as Clockspinning) or loses level counters for some reason (such as Vampire Hexmage), its level is changed accordingly.<br><br>6/15/2010: The last ability triggers and resolves during the declare attackers step, before blockers are declared.<br><br>6/15/2010: In a multiplayer game, the only player affected by the last ability is the one <u>Lord of Shatterskull Pass</u> is attacking (or the one who controls the planeswalker <u>Lord of Shatterskull Pass</u> is attacking).<br><br>6/15/2010: If a level 6 <u>Lord of Shatterskull Pass</u> attacks in a Two-Headed Giant game, its controller chooses which one of the defending players is affected by its ability. The choice is made as the ability resolves.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_16b]]></id><name><![CDATA[Ludevic's Abomination]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Lizard Horror]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power></power><toughness></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[After several frustrating experiments, the visionary Ludevic realized he needed to create a monster that fed on torch-wielding mobs.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Karl Kopinski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[16b]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011: It's possible (though not advisable) to activate the ability of Ludevic's Test Subject enough times in response to one another that a resolving ability places a fifth hatchling counter on Ludevic's *Abomination*. If that happens, it'll transform back into Ludevic's Test Subject.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_16a]]></id><name><![CDATA[Ludevic's Test Subject]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Lizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Defender<br>{1}{U}: Put a hatchling counter on Ludevic's Test Subject. Then if there are five or more hatchling counters on it, remove all of them and transform it.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Karl Kopinski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[16a]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011: It's possible (though not advisable) to activate the ability of <u>Ludevic's Test Subject</u> enough times in response to one another that a resolving ability places a fifth hatchling counter on Ludevic's *Abomination*. If that happens, it'll transform back into <u>Ludevic's Test Subject</u>.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_17a]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mondronen Shaman]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Werewolf Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[At the beginning of each upkeep, if no spells were cast last turn, transform Mondronen Shaman.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Tovolar, my master. Gather the howlpack, for the Hunter's Moon is nigh and Thraben's walls grow weak."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Anthony Palumbo]]></artist><number><![CDATA[17a]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>1/22/2011: Tovolar's Magehunter's first triggered ability will resolve before the spell that caused it to trigger. If this causes the player who cast that spell to lose the game, that spell won't resolve.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_5]]></id><name><![CDATA[Obelisk of Alara]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{6}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}{W}, {T}: You gain 5 life.<br>{1}{U}, {T}: Draw a card, then discard a card.<br>{1}{B}, {T}: Target creature gets -2/-2 until end of turn.<br>{1}{R}, {T}: Obelisk of Alara deals 3 damage to target player.<br>{1}{G}, {T}: Target creature gets +4/+4 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[John Avon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[5]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_14]]></id><name><![CDATA[Phyrexian Metamorph]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Shapeshifter]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{PU}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[0]]></toughness><loyalty></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[({PU} can be paid with either {U} or 2 life.)<br>You may have Phyrexian Metamorph enter the battlefield as a copy of any artifact or creature on the battlefield, except it's an artifact in addition to its other types.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jung Park]]></artist><number><![CDATA[14]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/1/2011: A card with Phyrexian mana symbols in its mana cost is each color that appears in that mana cost, regardless of how that cost may have been paid.<br><br>6/1/2011: To calculate the converted mana cost of a card with Phyrexian mana symbols in its cost, count each Phyrexian mana symbol as 1.<br><br>6/1/2011: As you cast a spell or activate an activated ability with one or more Phyrexian mana symbols in its cost, you choose how to pay for each Phyrexian mana symbol at the same time you would choose modes or choose a value for X.<br><br>6/1/2011: If you're at 1 life or less, you can't pay 2 life.<br><br>6/1/2011: Phyrexian mana is not a new color. Players can't add Phyrexian mana to their mana pools.<br><br>6/1/2011: Except for also being an artifact, <u>Phyrexian Metamorph</u> copies exactly what was printed on the original permanent and nothing more (unless that creature is itself copying something or is a token; see below). It doesn't copy whether that permanent is tapped or untapped, whether it has any counters on it or Auras attached to it, or any noncopy effects that have changed its power, toughness, types, color, and so on.<br><br>6/1/2011: If <u>Phyrexian Metamorph</u> copies a noncreature artifact, it is no longer a creature.<br><br>6/1/2011: If the chosen permanent has {X} in its mana cost (such as Protean Hydra), X is considered to be zero.<br><br>6/1/2011: If the chosen creature is copying something else (for example, if the chosen creature is a Clone), then your <u>Phyrexian Metamorph</u> enters the battlefield as whatever the chosen creature copied, except it's also an artifact.<br><br>6/1/2011: If the chosen permanent is a token, <u>Phyrexian Metamorph</u> copies the original characteristics of that token as stated by the effect that put the token onto the battlefield, except it's also an artifact. <u>Phyrexian Metamorph</u> is not a token.<br><br>6/1/2011: Any enters-the-battlefield abilities of the copied permanent will trigger when <u>Phyrexian Metamorph</u> enters the battlefield. Any "as [this] enters the battlefield" or "[this] enters the battlefield with" abilities of the chosen permanent will also work.<br><br>6/1/2011: If <u>Phyrexian Metamorph</u> somehow enters the battlefield at the same time as another permanent (due to Mass Polymorph or Liliana Vess's third ability, for example), <u>Phyrexian Metamorph</u> can't become a copy of that permanent. You may only choose a permanent that's already on the battlefield.<br><br>6/1/2011: You can choose not to copy anything. In that case, <u>Phyrexian Metamorph</u> simply enters the battlefield as a 0/0 artifact creature and is put into its owner's graveyard as a state-based action (unless something else is raising its toughness).]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_18]]></id><name><![CDATA[Restoration Angel]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Angel]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flash<br>Flying<br>When Restoration Angel enters the battlefield, you may exile target non-Angel creature you control, then return that card to the battlefield under your control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Wesley Burt]]></artist><number><![CDATA[18]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_21]]></id><name><![CDATA[Skarrg Goliath]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Beast]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{6}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[8]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[9]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[9]]></toughness><loyalty></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample<br>Bloodrush — {5}{G}{G}, Discard Skarrg Goliath: Target attacking creature gets +9/+9 and gains trample until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["They bind us with their laws. We free ourselves with nature's fist."<br>—Nikya of the Old Ways]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Karl Kopinski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[21]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_19]]></id><name><![CDATA[Staff of Nin]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{6}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[At the beginning of your upkeep, draw a card.<br>{T}: Staff of Nin deals 1 damage to target creature or player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["I have attuned the staff to your screams so that only I may benefit from your pain."<br>—Volux, disciple of Nin]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Brad Rigney]]></artist><number><![CDATA[19]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_12]]></id><name><![CDATA[Steel Hellkite]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Dragon]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{6}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>{2}: Steel Hellkite gets +1/+0 until end of turn.<br>{X}: Destroy each nonland permanent with converted mana cost X whose controller was dealt combat damage by Steel Hellkite this turn. Activate this ability only once each turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jaime Jones]]></artist><number><![CDATA[12]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>1/1/2011: <u>Steel Hellkite</u>'s last ability destroys only nonland permanents whose converted mana cost is exactly equal to X, and only those controlled by players who have been dealt combat damage by <u>Steel Hellkite</u> this turn.<br><br>1/1/2011: It doesn't matter who controlled those permanents at the time <u>Steel Hellkite</u> dealt combat damage, or if those permanents were even on the battlefield at that time.<br><br>1/1/2011: You may activate the last ability even if <u>Steel Hellkite</u> hasn't dealt combat damage to any players that turn. If you do, the ability won't do anything.<br><br>1/1/2011: If <u>Steel Hellkite</u>'s third ability is activated with X equal to 0, it will destroy each nonland permanent with converted mana cost 0 the appropriate players control.<br><br>1/1/2011: The converted mana cost of a permanent is determined solely by the mana symbols printed in its upper right corner, unless it's copying something else (see below). The converted mana cost is the total amount of mana in that cost, regardless of color. For example, a card with mana cost {3}{U}{U} has converted mana cost 5.<br><br>1/1/2011: If a permanent is copying something else, its converted mana cost is the converted mana cost of whatever it's copying.<br><br>1/1/2011: In all cases, ignore any alternative costs or additional costs (such as kicker) paid when the permanent was cast.<br><br>1/1/2011: If the mana cost of a permanent includes {X}, X is considered to be 0.<br><br>1/1/2011: If a nonland permanent has no mana symbols in its upper right corner (because it's a token that's not copying of something else, for example), its converted mana cost is 0.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_13]]></id><name><![CDATA[Thopter Assembly]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Thopter]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{6}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>At the beginning of your upkeep, if you control no Thopters other than Thopter Assembly, return Thopter Assembly to its owner's hand and put five 1/1 colorless Thopter artifact creature tokens with flying onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Volkan Baga]]></artist><number><![CDATA[13]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/1/2011: The triggered ability looks for any permanent you control with the creature type Thopter, not just the Thopter tokens previously created by a <u>Thopter Assembly</u>.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_17b]]></id><name><![CDATA[Tovolar's Magehunter]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Werewolf]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power></power><toughness></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever an opponent casts a spell, Tovolar's Magehunter deals 2 damage to that player.<br>At the beginning of each upkeep, if a player cast two or more spells last turn, transform Tovolar's Magehunter.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Tovolar, my master. Gather the howlpack, for the Hunter's Moon is nigh and Thraben's walls grow weak."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Anthony Palumbo]]></artist><number><![CDATA[17b]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>1/22/2011: <u>Tovolar's Magehunter</u>'s first triggered ability will resolve before the spell that caused it to trigger. If this causes the player who cast that spell to lose the game, that spell won't resolve.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_8]]></id><name><![CDATA[Valakut, the Molten Pinnacle]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power></power><toughness></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Valakut, the Molten Pinnacle enters the battlefield tapped.<br>Whenever a Mountain enters the battlefield under your control, if you control at least five other Mountains, you may have Valakut, the Molten Pinnacle deal 3 damage to target creature or player.<br>{T}: Add {R} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[James Paick]]></artist><number><![CDATA[8]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009: <u>Valakut, the Molten Pinnacle</u>'s triggered ability has an "intervening 'if' clause." That means (1) the ability won't trigger at all unless, at the time a Mountain enters the battlefield under your control, you control five or more Mountains other than that new one, and (2) the ability will do nothing if you control fewer than five Mountains other than that new one by the time it resolves.<br><br>10/1/2009: If a Mountain you control leaves the battlefield between the time Valakut's second ability triggers and the time it resolves, be aware if that was the Mountain that caused Valakut's ability to trigger or not. If it was, Valakut's count isn't affected; if it wasn't, Valakut's count goes down by one.<br><br>10/1/2009: If multiple Mountains enter the battlefield under your control at the same time, Valakut's second ability could trigger that many times. Each ability takes into consideration the other Mountains that entered the battlefield at the same time as the one that caused it to trigger.<br><br>10/1/2009: You target a creature or player when the ability triggers. You decide whether to have Valakut deal damage to that creature or player as the ability resolves.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[MLP_2]]></id><name><![CDATA[Vexing Shusher]]></name><set><![CDATA[GLP]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Goblin Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{RG}{RG}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Vexing Shusher can't be countered.<br>{R/G}: Target spell can't be countered by spells or abilities.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The stench of bloodcap mushrooms on the breath is enough to ward off even the most potent magics, especially when combined with a special chant: "Hushhh."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Cyril Van Der Haegen]]></artist><number><![CDATA[2]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>5/1/2008: After <u>Vexing Shusher</u>'s ability resolves, any spells or abilities that would counter the targeted spell will still resolve. They just won't counter that spell.<br><br>5/1/2008: <u>Vexing Shusher</u>'s ability won't prevent the targeted spell from being countered by the game rules (for example, if all its targets are illegal).]]></ruling></card></cards></mtg_carddatabase>