<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><mtg_carddatabase><bdd_date><![CDATA[1-5-2013]]></bdd_date><bdd_version><![CDATA[1.00]]></bdd_version><bdd_name>Magic the Gathering® Card Database</bdd_name><bdd_editor>Wizards of the Coast LLC</bdd_editor><sets><set><name><![CDATA[From the Vault: Legends]]></name><code><![CDATA[LEG]]></code><code_magiccards><![CDATA[FVL]]></code_magiccards><date><![CDATA[08/2011]]></date><is_promo><![CDATA[True]]></is_promo></set></sets><cards><card><id><![CDATA[244670]]></id><name><![CDATA[Cao Cao, Lord of Wei]]></name><set><![CDATA[LEG]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Human Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Target opponent discards two cards. Activate this ability only during your turn, before attackers are declared.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Gao Jianzhang]]></artist><number><![CDATA[1]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244665]]></id><name><![CDATA[Captain Sisay]]></name><set><![CDATA[LEG]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Human Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Search your library for a legendary card, reveal that card, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Her leadership forged the Weatherlight's finest crew.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ray Lago]]></artist><number><![CDATA[2]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/4/2004 : Because the "search" requires you to find a card with certain characteristics, you don't have to find the card if you don't want to.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244674]]></id><name><![CDATA[Doran, the Siege Tower]]></name><set><![CDATA[LEG]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Treefolk Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{B}{G}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Each creature assigns combat damage equal to its toughness rather than its power.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Each year that passes rings you inwardly with memory and might. Wield your heart, and the world will tremble."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mark Zug]]></artist><number><![CDATA[3]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2007 : Doran's ability means, for example, that a 2/3 creature will assign 3 damage in combat instead of 2. <br>10/1/2007 : Doran's ability doesn't actually change creatures' power; it changes only the value of the combat damage they assign. All other rules and effects that check power or toughness use the real values. <br>10/1/2007 : This effect is mandatory and affects all creatures.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244666]]></id><name><![CDATA[Kiki-Jiki, Mirror Breaker]]></name><set><![CDATA[LEG]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Goblin Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Haste<br>{T}: Put a token that's a copy of target nonlegendary creature you control onto the battlefield. That token has haste. Sacrifice it at the beginning of the next end step.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steven Belledin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[4]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244672]]></id><name><![CDATA[Kresh the Bloodbraided]]></name><set><![CDATA[LEG]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Human Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{B}{R}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever another creature dies, you may put X +1/+1 counters on Kresh the Bloodbraided, where X is that creature's power.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Each of his twenty-two braids is bound with bone and leather from a foe.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Argyle]]></artist><number><![CDATA[5]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2008 : X is equal to the power of the creature as it last existed on the battlefield.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[259296]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mikaeus, the Lunarch]]></name><set><![CDATA[LEG]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Human Cleric]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{X}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[0]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Mikaeus, the Lunarch enters the battlefield with X +1/+1 counters on it.<br>{T}: Put a +1/+1 counter on Mikaeus.<br>{T}, Remove a +1/+1 counter from Mikaeus: Put a +1/+1 counter on each other creature you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steven Belledin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[6]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[259295]]></id><name><![CDATA[Omnath, Locus of Mana]]></name><set><![CDATA[LEG]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Green mana doesn't empty from your mana pool as steps and phases end.<br>Omnath, Locus of Mana gets +1/+1 for each green mana in your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It gathers against the coming storm.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mike Bierek]]></artist><number><![CDATA[7]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>3/1/2010 : You can keep green mana in your mana pool indefinitely while Omnath is on the battlefield. That means if you add a green mana to your mana pool during one step or phase, you can spend it during a later step or phase, or even a later turn. Other types of mana will continue to empty from your mana pool as each step and phase ends. <br>3/1/2010 : If a green mana you add to your mana pool has certain restrictions or riders associated with it (for example, if it was produced by Ancient Ziggurat), they'll apply to that mana no matter when you spend it. <br>3/1/2010 : Once Omnath leaves the battlefield, you have until the end of the current step or phase to spend whatever green mana is in your mana pool before it too empties as normal. There is no penalty associated with this other than the loss of the mana.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244668]]></id><name><![CDATA[Oona, Queen of the Fae]]></name><set><![CDATA[LEG]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Faerie Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{UB}{UB}{UB}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>{X}{UB}: Choose a color. Target opponent exiles the top X cards of his or her library. For each card of the chosen color exiled this way, put a 1/1 blue and black Faerie Rogue creature token with flying onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Adam Rex]]></artist><number><![CDATA[8]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>5/1/2008 : You target the opponent when you activate Oona's ability. You don't choose the color until the ability resolves. <br>5/1/2008 : You get the tokens, not your opponent.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244675]]></id><name><![CDATA[Progenitus]]></name><set><![CDATA[LEG]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Hydra Avatar]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{W}{W}{U}{U}{B}{B}{R}{R}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[10]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[10]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[10]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Protection from everything<br>If Progenitus would be put into a graveyard from anywhere, reveal Progenitus and shuffle it into its owner's library instead.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The Soul of the World has returned.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mike Bierek]]></artist><number><![CDATA[9]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : "Protection from everything" means the following:-- Progenitus can't be blocked.-- Progenitus can't be enchanted or equipped.-- Progenitus can't be the target of spells or abilities.-- All damage that would be dealt to Progenitus is prevented. <br>2/1/2009 : Progenitus can still be affected by effects that don't target it or deal damage to it (such as Wrath of God).]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244669]]></id><name><![CDATA[Rafiq of the Many]]></name><set><![CDATA[LEG]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Human Knight]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}{W}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Exalted (Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, that creature gets +1/+1 until end of turn.)<br>Whenever a creature you control attacks alone, it gains double strike until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Many sigils, one purpose.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Wayne Reynolds]]></artist><number><![CDATA[10]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2008 : If you declare exactly one creature as an attacker, each exalted ability on each permanent you control (including, perhaps, the attacking creature itself) will trigger. The bonuses are given to the attacking creature, not to the permanent with exalted. Ultimately, the attacking creature will wind up with +1/+1 for each of your exalted abilities. <br>10/1/2008 : If you attack with multiple creatures, but then all but one are removed from combat, your exalted abilities won't trigger. <br>10/1/2008 : Some effects put creatures onto the battlefield attacking. Since those creatures were never declared as attackers, they're ignored by exalted abilities. They won't cause exalted abilities to trigger. If any exalted abilities have already triggered (because exactly one creature was declared as an attacker), those abilities will resolve as normal even though there may now be multiple attackers. <br>10/1/2008 : Exalted abilities will resolve before blockers are declared. <br>10/1/2008 : Exalted bonuses last until end of turn. If an effect creates an additional combat phase during your turn, a creature that attacked alone during the first combat phase will still have its exalted bonuses in that new phase. If a creature attacks alone during the second combat phase, all your exalted abilities will trigger again. <br>10/1/2008 : In a Two-Headed Giant game, a creature "attacks alone" if it's the only creature declared as an attacker by your entire team. If you control that attacking creature, your exalted abilities will trigger but your teammate's exalted abilities won't.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244664]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sharuum the Hegemon]]></name><set><![CDATA[LEG]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Artifact Creature — Sphinx]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}{U}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>When Sharuum the Hegemon enters the battlefield, you may return target artifact card from your graveyard to the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[To gain audience with the hegemon, one must bring a riddle she has not heard.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Todd Lockwood]]></artist><number><![CDATA[11]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244663]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sun Quan, Lord of Wu]]></name><set><![CDATA[LEG]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Human Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Creatures you control have horsemanship. (They can't be blocked except by creatures with horsemanship.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["One score and four he reigned, the Southland king: / A dragon coiled, a tiger poised below the mighty Yangtze."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Xu Xiaoming]]></artist><number><![CDATA[12]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : Despite the similarities between horsemanship and flying, horsemanship doesn't interact with flying or reach. <br>10/1/2009 : Sun Quan's ability affects Sun Quan itself.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244667]]></id><name><![CDATA[Teferi, Mage of Zhalfir]]></name><set><![CDATA[LEG]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Human Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flash (You may cast this spell any time you could cast an instant.)<br>Creature cards you own that aren't on the battlefield have flash.<br>Each opponent can cast spells only any time he or she could cast a sorcery.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[To save this plane, he must forsake all others.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Volkan Baga]]></artist><number><![CDATA[13]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/25/2006 : The last ability means that in order for an opponent to cast a spell, it must be that opponent's turn, during a main phase, and the stack must be empty. This is true even if the player doesn't have a sorcery he or she is able to cast, or if a rule or effect allows a spell to be cast at another time. <br>9/25/2006 : If you have Teferi on the battlefield, you may exile creature cards in your hand with suspend any time you could cast an instant. <br>9/25/2006 : If an ability lets an opponent cast a spell as part of its effect (such as Isochron Scepter's ability does), that opponent can't cast that spell since the currently resolving ability is still on the stack. <br>9/25/2006 : Your opponents can't cast their suspended cards, no matter what phase it is when the last time counter is removed. Your opponents can't cast cards using the madness ability either, no matter what phase it is when the card is discarded. <br>5/1/2007 : If you have Teferi on the battlefield and there’s a Split Second spell on the stack (such as  Sudden Death), you can’t Suspend creatures until after the Split Second spell resolves.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[261321]]></id><name><![CDATA[Ulamog, the Infinite Gyre]]></name><set><![CDATA[LEG]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Eldrazi]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{11}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[11]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[10]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[10]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When you cast Ulamog, the Infinite Gyre, destroy target permanent.<br>Annihilator 4 (Whenever this creature attacks, defending player sacrifices four permanents.)<br>Ulamog is indestructible.<br>When Ulamog is put into a graveyard from anywhere, its owner shuffles his or her graveyard into his or her library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Aleksi Briclot]]></artist><number><![CDATA[14]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/15/2010 :  Annihilator abilities trigger and resolve during the declare attackers step. The defending player chooses and sacrifices the required number of permanents before he or she declares blockers. Any creatures sacrificed this way won't be able to block. <br>6/15/2010 : If a creature with annihilator is attacking a planeswalker, and the defending player chooses to sacrifice that planeswalker, the attacking creature continues to attack. It may be blocked. If it isn't blocked, it simply won't deal combat damage to anything. <br>6/15/2010 : In a Two-Headed Giant game, the controller of an attacking creature with annihilator chooses which of the defending players is affected by the ability. Only that player sacrifices permanents. The choice is made as the ability resolves; once a player is chosen, it's too late for anyone to respond. <br>6/15/2010 : Lethal damage and effects that say "destroy" won't cause an indestructible creature to be put into the graveyard. However, an indestructible creature can be put into the graveyard for a number of reasons. The most likely reasons are if it's sacrificed, if it's legendary and another legendary creature with the same name is on the battlefield, or if its toughness is 0 or less.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244677]]></id><name><![CDATA[Visara the Dreadful]]></name><set><![CDATA[LEG]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Gorgon]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{B}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>{T}: Destroy target creature. It can't be regenerated.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["My eyes are my strongest feature."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Brad Rigney]]></artist><number><![CDATA[15]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card></cards></mtg_carddatabase>