<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><mtg_carddatabase><bdd_date><![CDATA[1-5-2013]]></bdd_date><bdd_version><![CDATA[1.00]]></bdd_version><bdd_name>Magic the Gathering® Card Database</bdd_name><bdd_editor>Wizards of the Coast LLC</bdd_editor><sets><set><name><![CDATA[Magic 2012]]></name><code><![CDATA[M12]]></code><code_magiccards><![CDATA[M12]]></code_magiccards><date><![CDATA[07/2011]]></date><is_promo><![CDATA[False]]></is_promo></set></sets><cards><card><id><![CDATA[226906]]></id><name><![CDATA[Acidic Slime]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Ooze]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Deathtouch (Any amount of damage this deals to a creature is enough to destroy it.)<br>When Acidic Slime enters the battlefield, destroy target artifact, enchantment, or land.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Karl Kopinski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[161]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[226589]]></id><name><![CDATA[Act of Treason]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Gain control of target creature until end of turn. Untap that creature. It gains haste until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Rage courses in every heart, yearning to betray its rational prison."<br>—Sarkhan Vol]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Eric Deschamps]]></artist><number><![CDATA[121]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : Act of Treason can target any creature, even one that's untapped or one you already control. <br>8/15/2010 : Gaining control of a creature doesn't cause you to gain control of any Auras or Equipment attached to it.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220147]]></id><name><![CDATA[Adaptive Automaton]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Construct]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[As Adaptive Automaton enters the battlefield, choose a creature type.<br>Adaptive Automaton is the chosen type in addition to its other types.<br>Other creatures you control of the chosen type get +1/+1.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Such loyalty can only be made.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Igor Kieryluk]]></artist><number><![CDATA[201]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : The choice of creature type is made as Adaptive Automaton enters the battlefield. Players can't respond to this choice. The bonus starts applying immediately. <br>9/22/2011 : You must choose an existing _Magic_ creature type. <br>9/22/2011 : Even though Adaptive Automaton is a Construct, other Construct creatures you control won't get +1/+1 (unless you chose Construct as Adaptive Automaton entered the battlefield).]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220086]]></id><name><![CDATA[Aegis Angel]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Angel]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>When Aegis Angel enters the battlefield, another target permanent is indestructible for as long as you control Aegis Angel. (Effects that say "destroy" don't destroy that permanent. An indestructible creature can't be destroyed by damage.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Aleksi Briclot]]></artist><number><![CDATA[1]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If Aegis Angel leaves the battlefield, you no longer control it. <br>9/22/2011 : If another player gains control of Aegis Angel, the permanent will no longer be indestructible, even if you regain control of Aegis Angel. <br>9/22/2011 : If Aegis Angel and the permanent would be destroyed simultaneously, only Aegis Angel will be destroyed.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[227222]]></id><name><![CDATA[Æther Adept]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Æther Adept enters the battlefield, return target creature to its owner's hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The universe is my instrument, and the song I play upon it is one you are forbidden to hear."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Eric Deschamps]]></artist><number><![CDATA[41]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : If there are no other creatures on the battlefield when Æther Adept enters the battlefield, it must target itself.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220264]]></id><name><![CDATA[Alabaster Mage]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}{W}: Target creature you control gains lifelink until end of turn. (Damage dealt by the creature also causes its controller to gain that much life.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["We hold sacred the powers of light and life. Truth and honor are our greatest weapons."<br>—Alabaster creed]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Izzy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[2]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : Multiple instances of lifelink on the same creature provide no additional benefit. The creature's controller gains life equal the damage dealt and no more.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[245188]]></id><name><![CDATA[Alluring Siren]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Siren]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Target creature an opponent controls attacks you this turn if able.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[She lures victims with promises of flesh, captures them in a net of deceit, and destroys them in the embrace of the sea.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chippy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[42]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : After the ability resolves, the targeted creature attacks you only if it's able to do so as that turn's declare attackers step begins. If, at that time, the creature is tapped, is affected by a spell or ability that says it can't attack, or is affected by "summoning sickness," it can't attack. If there's a cost associated with having that creature attack, its controller isn't forced to pay that cost, so the creature doesn't have to attack in that case either. <br>10/1/2009 : If the targeted creature would be able to attack either you or a planeswalker you control, it must attack you, not the planeswalker. <br>10/1/2009 : Activating the ability during your opponent's turn after attackers have been declared will have no effect. The same is true if you activate the ability during your own turn. <br>9/22/2011 : If there are multiple combat phases in a turn, the creature must attack only in the first one in which it's able to.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220218]]></id><name><![CDATA[Amphin Cutthroat]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Salamander Rogue]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The amphin have long built their society in secret. While surface dwellers squabbled over trivial borders, they patiently expanded, building their ammonite temple-caves. Now amphin priests eye the shore, and amphin hunters gird for war."<br>—Gor Muldrak, Cryptohistories]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Howard Lyon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[43]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220230]]></id><name><![CDATA[Angelic Destiny]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature gets +4/+4, has flying and first strike, and is an Angel in addition to its other types.<br>When enchanted creature dies, return Angelic Destiny to its owner's hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jana Schirmer & Johannes Voss]]></artist><number><![CDATA[3]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If the creature dies before the Angelic Destiny spell resolves, Angelic Destiny will go to its owner's graveyard. It won't return to its owner's hand. <br>9/22/2011 : If Angelic Destiny is no longer in a graveyard when its triggered ability resolves, it won't be returned to its owner's hand.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221520]]></id><name><![CDATA[Angel's Feather]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever a player casts a white spell, you may gain 1 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The angel represents divine perfection; even the smallest feather is imbued with beauty and benevolence.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Alan Pollack]]></artist><number><![CDATA[202]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : The ability triggers whenever any player, not just you, casts a white spell. <br>10/1/2009 : If a player casts a white spell, Angel's Feather's ability triggers and is put on the stack on top of that spell. Angel's Feather's ability will resolve (causing you to gain 1 life) before the spell does.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[238569]]></id><name><![CDATA[Angel's Mercy]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[You gain 7 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Angels appear before both the blessed and the cursed, though most don't know which they are until they feel either the angel's kiss or her sword.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Andrew Robinson]]></artist><number><![CDATA[4]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220242]]></id><name><![CDATA[Arachnus Spinner]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Spider]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[7]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)<br>Tap an untapped Spider you control: Search your graveyard and/or library for a card named Arachnus Web and put it onto the battlefield attached to target creature. If you search your library this way, shuffle it.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Karl Kopinski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[162]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : You can tap any untapped Spider you control, including one you haven't controlled continuously since the beginning of your most recent turn, to pay the cost of Arachnus Spinner's activated ability. You can even tap Arachnus Spinner itself to pay this cost. <br>9/22/2011 : If you choose to search your library this way, you don't have to find a card named Arachnus Web, even if one is there. You'll still shuffle your library after searching it. <br>9/22/2011 : If you choose to search your graveyard this way, you must find a card named Arachnus Web if one is there. <br>9/22/2011 : You may search both your graveyard and your library, but you can find a maximum of one card named Arachnus Web.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220283]]></id><name><![CDATA[Arachnus Web]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature can't attack or block, and its activated abilities can't be activated.<br>At the beginning of the end step, if enchanted creature's power is 4 or greater, destroy Arachnus Web.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Karl Kopinski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[163]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : The last ability checks at the beginning of each turn's end step, not just your turn's. <br>9/22/2011 : If the enchanted creature's power isn't 4 or greater when the end step begins, the last ability won't trigger at all. <br>9/22/2011 : If the ability triggers, but the enchanted creature's power is reduced to 3 or less before the ability resolves, the ability will have no effect. Arachnus Web won't be destroyed. <br>9/22/2011 : If Arachnus Web enters the battlefield attached to an attacking or blocking creature (due to Arachnus Spinner's ability, for example), that creature will continue to attack or block.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220078]]></id><name><![CDATA[Arbalest Elite]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Archer]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{2}{W}, {T}: Arbalest Elite deals 3 damage to target attacking or blocking creature. Arbalest Elite doesn't untap during your next untap step.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[There are few things as satisfying as a good, healthy thunk.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chris Rahn]]></artist><number><![CDATA[5]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If the creature is an illegal target when Arbalest Elite's ability tries to resolve, the ability will be countered and none of its effects will happen. Arbalest Elite will untap during its controller's next untap step. <br>9/22/2011 : If another player controls Arbalest Elite during your next untap step, the part of the effect that keeps it from untapping does nothing. It won't try to apply during a future untap step.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244828]]></id><name><![CDATA[Archon of Justice]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Archon]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>When Archon of Justice dies, exile target permanent.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[In dark times, Truth bears a blade.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jason Chan]]></artist><number><![CDATA[6]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[222634]]></id><name><![CDATA[Armored Warhorse]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Horse]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["When we of the Northern Verge claim a mount, no peasant's nag will do. It must be as strong as our virtue, and must join us of its own will."<br>—Sarlena, paladin of the Northern Verge]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[rk post]]></artist><number><![CDATA[7]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[236449]]></id><name><![CDATA[Assault Griffin]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Griffin]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Griffins do not serve. They give freely to those they trust."<br>—Amira, skycaptain of Thune]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jesper Ejsing]]></artist><number><![CDATA[8]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[240308]]></id><name><![CDATA[Auramancer]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Auramancer enters the battlefield, you may return target enchantment card from your graveyard to your hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["In memories, we can find our deepest reserves of strength."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Rebecca Guay]]></artist><number><![CDATA[9]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[241990]]></id><name><![CDATA[Autumn's Veil]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Spells you control can't be countered by blue or black spells this turn, and creatures you control can't be the targets of blue or black spells this turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The rustling of leaves and a passing shadow are a dryad's only trace.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kekai Kotaki]]></artist><number><![CDATA[164]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : Autumn's Veil itself may be countered by blue or black spells. Its effect doesn't apply until after it resolves. <br>8/15/2010 : After Autumn's Veil resolves, any spell you control that turn can still be targeted by spells that try to counter it (such as Cancel), regardless of their color. If those spells are blue or black at the time they would resolve, they will resolve, but the part of their effect that would counter the spell you control simply won't do anything. Any other effects those spells have will work as normal. <br>8/15/2010 : If a creature you control is being targeted by a spell when Autumn's Veil resolves, nothing happens right away. When that spell would resolve, its color is checked. If it's blue or black, that creature will be an illegal target for that spell, and will be unable to be affected by it. If all that spell's targets have become illegal by the time it would resolve, it's countered. <br>8/15/2010 : After Autumn's Veil resolves, no new blue or black spell may be cast that turn targeting a creature you control. <br>8/15/2010 : Keep in mind that an Aura spell targets the permanent it will enchant (but an Aura on the battlefield doesn't target the permanent it's attached to). <br>8/15/2010 : Autumn's Veil affects any spells and creatures you happen to control at any point during the rest of the turn, not just spells and creatures you control as it resolves. That's because it doesn't grant an ability to those spells or creatures; rather, it affects the game rules and states something that's now true about those spells and creatures. <br>8/15/2010 : Autumn's Veil has no effect on abilities. After it resolves, spells you control may be countered by abilities from blue or black sources, and creatures you control may be targeted by abilities from blue or black sources.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220145]]></id><name><![CDATA[Aven Fleetwing]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Bird Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Hexproof (This creature can't be the target of spells or abilities your opponents control.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["It was too fast, even for our veteran archers. They might as well have been blowing it kisses."<br>—Vulok, elvish archer]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Wayne Reynolds]]></artist><number><![CDATA[44]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220268]]></id><name><![CDATA[Azure Mage]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{3}{U}: Draw a card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["We draw our power from the infinite ocean of the mind, where all manner of things can be conceived."<br>—Azure creed]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Izzy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[45]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[236457]]></id><name><![CDATA[Belltower Sphinx]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Sphinx]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Whenever a source deals damage to Belltower Sphinx, that source's controller puts that many cards from the top of his or her library into his or her graveyard.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jim Nelson]]></artist><number><![CDATA[46]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[228117]]></id><name><![CDATA[Benalish Veteran]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever Benalish Veteran attacks, it gets +1/+1 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["One day I will rest and join my comrades in the afterlife, but not while scum like you still sully this world."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steven Belledin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[10]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221896]]></id><name><![CDATA[Birds of Paradise]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Bird]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The gods used their feathers to paint all the colors of the world."<br>—Yare-Tiva, warden of Gramur forest]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Marcelo Vignali]]></artist><number><![CDATA[165]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220227]]></id><name><![CDATA[Blood Ogre]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Ogre Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Bloodthirst 1 (If an opponent was dealt damage this turn, this creature enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it.)<br>First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Christopher Moeller]]></artist><number><![CDATA[122]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244252]]></id><name><![CDATA[Blood Seeker]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Vampire Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever a creature enters the battlefield under an opponent's control, you may have that player lose 1 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[A drop now is all he needs to find you later.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Greg Staples]]></artist><number><![CDATA[81]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : Life loss is not the same as damage. Blood Seeker's ability will not cause creatures with bloodthirst to enter the battlefield with +1/+1 counters.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220306]]></id><name><![CDATA[Bloodlord of Vaasgoth]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Vampire Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Bloodthirst 3 (If an opponent was dealt damage this turn, this creature enters the battlefield with three +1/+1 counters on it.)<br>Flying<br>Whenever you cast a Vampire creature spell, it gains bloodthirst 3.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Greg Staples]]></artist><number><![CDATA[82]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : Multiple instances of bloodthirst are cumulative. For example, if you control Bloodlord of Vaasgoth and cast a Vampire creature spell that already has bloodthirst 1, that Vampire will enter the battlefield with four +1/+1 counters on it if an opponent has been dealt damage that turn. <br>9/22/2011 : A creature spell like Phantasmal Image that may enter the battlefield as a copy of a creature is not a Vampire creature spell, even if you intend on copying a Vampire creature when that creature enters the battlefield. <br>9/22/2011 : Vampire creatures you put directly onto the battlefield without casting them and Vampire creature tokens you put onto the battlefield will not gain bloodthirst 3 from Bloodlord of Vaasgoth.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220125]]></id><name><![CDATA[Bloodrage Vampire]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Vampire]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Bloodthirst 1 (If an opponent was dealt damage this turn, this creature enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The most genteel facades hide the most abominable desires.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Prescott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[83]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[226582]]></id><name><![CDATA[Bonebreaker Giant]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Giant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[One thing's for sure—his fists are harder than your skull.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kev Walker]]></artist><number><![CDATA[123]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[226901]]></id><name><![CDATA[Bountiful Harvest]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[You gain 1 life for each land you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["When we fail to see the beauty in every tree, we are no better than humans."<br>—Saelia, elvish scout]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jason Chan]]></artist><number><![CDATA[166]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244824]]></id><name><![CDATA[Brindle Boar]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Boar]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Sacrifice Brindle Boar: You gain 4 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Tell the cooks to prepare the fires. Tonight we feast!"<br>—Tolar Wolfbrother, Krosan tracker]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Allsop]]></artist><number><![CDATA[167]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : If you sacrifice an attacking or blocking Brindle Boar during the declare blockers step, it won't deal combat damage. If you wait until the combat damage step, but Brindle Boar is dealt lethal damage, it'll be destroyed before you get a chance to sacrifice it.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244246]]></id><name><![CDATA[Brink of Disaster]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature or land<br>When enchanted permanent becomes tapped, destroy it.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["When you find yourself teetering on the edge of oblivion, mine will be the hands taking pleasure in giving you the final push."<br>—Liliana Vess]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Alex Horley-Orlandelli]]></artist><number><![CDATA[84]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>3/1/2010 : Brink of Disaster may target and may enchant a permanent that's already tapped. It won't do anything until the enchanted permanent changes from being untapped to being tapped. <br>3/1/2010 : When the enchanted permanent becomes tapped, Brink of Disaster's ability triggers. That permanent will be destroyed when the ability resolves, even if Brink of Disaster has left the battlefield or is somehow enchanting a different permanent by then. <br>3/1/2010 : If the enchanted permanent is tapped as a cost to activate a mana ability, the mana ability resolves immediately, then Brink of Disaster's ability goes on the stack. <br>3/1/2010 : If the enchanted permanent is tapped as a cost to activate an ability that's not a mana ability, Brink of Disaster's ability will go on the stack on top of that activated ability. Brink of Disaster's ability resolves first (destroying that permanent), then the permanent's activated ability resolves.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220302]]></id><name><![CDATA[Buried Ruin]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.<br>{2}, {T}, Sacrifice Buried Ruin: Return target artifact card from your graveyard to your hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[History has buried its treasures deep.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Franz Vohwinkel]]></artist><number><![CDATA[224]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[236460]]></id><name><![CDATA[Call to the Grave]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[At the beginning of each player's upkeep, that player sacrifices a non-Zombie creature.<br>At the beginning of the end step, if no creatures are on the battlefield, sacrifice Call to the Grave.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Daarken]]></artist><number><![CDATA[85]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If a player controls no creatures, or each creature he or she controls is a Zombie, that player does nothing when the first ability resolves. <br>9/22/2011 : If there is at least one creature on the battlefield at the beginning of the end step, the last ability won't trigger. If it does trigger, but a creature enters the battlefield before it resolves, the ability won't do anything when it resolves. Call to the Grave's controller won't sacrifice it. <br>9/22/2011 : In a Two-Headed Giant game, Call to the Grave will trigger twice during each team's upkeep, once for each player. Each of the two players will sacrifice a non-Zombie creature when the ability referring to that player resolves.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[227225]]></id><name><![CDATA[Cancel]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Counter target spell.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[David Palumbo]]></artist><number><![CDATA[47]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220220]]></id><name><![CDATA[Carnage Wurm]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Wurm]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{6}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Bloodthirst 3 (If an opponent was dealt damage this turn, this creature enters the battlefield with three +1/+1 counters on it.)<br>Trample (If this creature would assign enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it assign the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Kendall]]></artist><number><![CDATA[168]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220195]]></id><name><![CDATA[Celestial Purge]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Exile target black or red permanent.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["A world without evil? Boring. Give me vile fiends to smite and banish any day."<br>—Sarlena, paladin of the Northern Verge]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[David Palumbo]]></artist><number><![CDATA[11]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : Lands are colorless (even if their frames have some colored elements to them). You can't target a Swamp, a Mountain, or any other land with Celestial Purge (unless some other effect has turned that land black or red).]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[234070]]></id><name><![CDATA[Cemetery Reaper]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Zombie]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Other Zombie creatures you control get +1/+1.<br>{2}{B}, {T}: Exile target creature card from a graveyard. Put a 2/2 black Zombie creature token onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Every grave cradles a recruit.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Allsop]]></artist><number><![CDATA[86]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : Cemetery Reaper grants +1/+1 to all other Zombie creatures you control, not just the ones its ability puts onto the battlefield. <br>10/1/2009 : The creature card in a graveyard is exiled as part of the activated ability's effect, not as a cost. If that card has left the graveyard by the time the ability would resolve, the ability is countered and you don't get a Zombie token.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220146]]></id><name><![CDATA[Chandra, the Firebrand]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Planeswalker — Chandra]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[3]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[+1: Chandra, the Firebrand deals 1 damage to target creature or player.<br>-2: When you cast your next instant or sorcery spell this turn, copy that spell. You may choose new targets for the copy.<br>-6: Chandra, the Firebrand deals 6 damage to each of up to six target creatures and/or players.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[D. Alexander Gregory]]></artist><number><![CDATA[124]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : Chandra's second ability creates a delayed triggered ability that will copy the next instant or sorcery spell you cast that turn, regardless of whether that spell has targets. <br>9/22/2011 : When the delayed trigger resolves, it creates a copy of a spell. You control the copy. That copy is created on the stack, so it's not "cast." Abilities that trigger when a player casts a spell won't trigger. The copy will then resolve like a normal spell, after players get a chance to cast spells and activate abilities. <br>9/22/2011 : The copy will have the same targets as the spell it's copying unless you choose new ones. You may change any number of the targets, including all of them or none of them. If, for one of the targets, you can't choose a new legal target, then it remains unchanged (even if the current target is illegal). <br>9/22/2011 : If the spell Chandra copies is modal (that is, it says "Choose one --" or the like), the copy will have the same mode. You can't choose a different one. <br>9/22/2011 : If the spell Chandra copies has an X whose value was determined as it was cast (like Consume Spirit does), the copy has the same value of X. <br>9/22/2011 : You can't choose to pay any additional costs for the copy. However, effects based on any additional costs that were paid for the original spell are copied as though those same costs were paid for the copy too. For example, if you sacrifice a 3/3 creature to cast Fling after activating Chandra's second ability, the copy of Fling will also deal 3 damage. <br>9/22/2011 : When you activate Chandra's last ability, you choose up to six target creatures and/or players. No damage is divided, and Chandra can't deal more than 6 damage to any one target. Chandra deals 6 damage to each target that is still legal when the ability resolves.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[226585]]></id><name><![CDATA[Chandra's Outrage]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Chandra's Outrage deals 4 damage to target creature and 2 damage to that creature's controller.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Chandra never believed in using her "inside voice."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Christopher Moeller]]></artist><number><![CDATA[125]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : The player who's dealt damage is the player who controls the targeted creature at the time Chandra's Outrage resolves. <br>8/15/2010 : If the targeted creature is an illegal target by the time Chandra's Outrage resolves, the entire spell is countered. No player is dealt damage.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220298]]></id><name><![CDATA[Chandra's Phoenix]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Phoenix]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Haste (This creature can attack and {T} as soon as it comes under your control.)<br>Whenever an opponent is dealt damage by a red instant or sorcery spell you control or by a red planeswalker you control, return Chandra's Phoenix from your graveyard to your hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Aleksi Briclot]]></artist><number><![CDATA[126]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220225]]></id><name><![CDATA[Chasm Drake]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Drake]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Whenever Chasm Drake attacks, target creature you control gains flying until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Once he's got you, hold on. Fall from a drake and you'll suffer much worse than a bruise."<br>—Garl, drake trainer]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Anthony Francisco]]></artist><number><![CDATA[48]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[234560]]></id><name><![CDATA[Child of Night]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Vampire]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Lifelink (Damage dealt by this creature also causes you to gain that much life.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Sins that would be too gruesome in the light of day are made more pleasing in the dark of night.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ash Wood]]></artist><number><![CDATA[87]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220273]]></id><name><![CDATA[Circle of Flame]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever a creature without flying attacks you or a planeswalker you control, Circle of Flame deals 1 damage to that creature.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Which do you think is a better deterrent: a moat of water or one of fire?"<br>—Chandra Nalaar]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jaime Jones]]></artist><number><![CDATA[127]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[226591]]></id><name><![CDATA[Combust]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Combust can't be countered by spells or abilities.<br>Combust deals 5 damage to target white or blue creature. The damage can't be prevented.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jaime Jones]]></artist><number><![CDATA[128]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : Combust can be targeted by spells and abilities that try to counter it (such as Cancel). Those spells and abilities will resolve, but the part of their effect that would counter Combust won't do anything. Any other effects those spells and abilities have will work as normal. <br>8/15/2010 : If the targeted creature is an illegal target by the time Combust would resolve, Combust will be countered by the game rules. <br>8/15/2010 : Spells that create prevention effects affecting the targeted creature can still be cast, and abilities that create prevention effects affecting the targeted creature can still be activated. However, damage prevention shields (including those created before Combust was cast) don't have any effect on the damage dealt by Combust. If such a prevention effect has an additional effect, the additional effect will still work (if possible). <br>8/15/2010 : If a static ability would prevent damage from being dealt to the targeted creature, it fails to prevent the damage dealt by Combust. If that ability has an additional effect that doesn't depend on the amount of damage prevented, that additional effect will still work. It's applied just once as Combust resolves. <br>8/15/2010 : Effects that replace or redirect damage without using the word "prevent" aren't affected by Combust; they'll work as normal. <br>8/15/2010 : If a creature is dealt lethal damage by Combust, it can still regenerate. If it does, the damage marked on it will be removed from it.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244249]]></id><name><![CDATA[Consume Spirit]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{X}{1}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Spend only black mana on X.<br>Consume Spirit deals X damage to target creature or player and you gain X life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["You clerics brag about your strength of spirit, yet I take away the tiniest fragment, and you crumple like a rag doll."<br>—Sorin Markov]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Justin Sweet]]></artist><number><![CDATA[88]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : The amount of life you gain is equal to the number chosen for X, not the amount of damage Consume Spirit deals (in case some of it is prevented). <br>10/1/2009 : If the targeted creature or player is an illegal target by the time Consume Spirit would resolve, the entire spell is countered. You won't gain any life.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[227223]]></id><name><![CDATA[Coral Merfolk]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Merfolk]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Merfolk are best known for their subtle magic. But those who try to fight them in their own territory quickly realize that merfolk are hardly defenseless on the field of battle.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[rk post]]></artist><number><![CDATA[49]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220069]]></id><name><![CDATA[Crimson Mage]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{R}: Target creature you control gains haste until end of turn. (It can attack and {T} this turn.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["We wield the fires of rage. War is our blood and destruction our birthright."<br>—Crimson creed]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Izzy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[129]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220297]]></id><name><![CDATA[Crown of Empires]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{3}, {T}: Tap target creature. Gain control of that creature instead if you control artifacts named Scepter of Empires and Throne of Empires.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["With this crown, assert your authority."<br>—Crown inscription]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[John Avon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[203]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : Whether or not you control the correct artifacts is determined when the ability resolves. <br>9/22/2011 : If any of the named cards stops being an artifact, it won't be considered by these abilities. <br>9/22/2011 : If you control artifacts named Scepter of Empires and Throne of Empires, the targeted creature won't be tapped. You'll just gain control of it.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220113]]></id><name><![CDATA[Crumbling Colossus]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Golem]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[7]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample (If this creature would assign enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it assign the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)<br>When Crumbling Colossus attacks, sacrifice it at end of combat.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Michael C. Hayes]]></artist><number><![CDATA[204]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If another player controls Crumbling Colossus when its ability tries to resolve, you'll be unable to sacrifice it. It will simply remain on the battlefield.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221895]]></id><name><![CDATA[Cudgel Troll]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Troll]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{G}: Regenerate Cudgel Troll. (The next time this creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jesper Ejsing]]></artist><number><![CDATA[169]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : Activating Cudgel Troll's ability causes a "regeneration shield" to be created for it. The next time Cudgel Troll would be destroyed that turn, the regeneration shield is used up instead. This works only if Cudgel Troll is dealt lethal damage, dealt damage from a source with deathtouch, or affected by a spell or ability that says to "destroy" it. Other effects that cause Cudgel Troll to be put into the graveyard (such as reducing its toughness to 0 or sacrificing it) don't destroy it, so regeneration won't save it. If it hasn't been used, the regeneration shield goes away as the turn ends. <br>8/15/2010 : To work, the regeneration shield must be created before Cudgel Troll is destroyed. This usually means activating its ability during the declare blockers step, or in response to a spell or ability that would destroy it. <br>8/15/2010 : If Cudgel Troll is dealt lethal damage and is dealt damage by a source with deathtouch during the same combat damage step, a single regeneration shield will save it.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220293]]></id><name><![CDATA[Dark Favor]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>When Dark Favor enters the battlefield, you lose 1 life.<br>Enchanted creature gets +3/+1.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[When he began to curse what he held holy, his strength grew unrivaled.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Allen Williams]]></artist><number><![CDATA[89]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If the creature targeted by Dark Favor is an illegal target when Dark Favor tries to resolve, Dark Favor will be countered. It won't enter the battlefield and its enters-the-battlefield ability won't trigger.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220139]]></id><name><![CDATA[Day of Judgment]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Destroy all creatures.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Vincent Proce]]></artist><number><![CDATA[12]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221516]]></id><name><![CDATA[Deathmark]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Destroy target green or white creature.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Let the final vision of doom be etched upon their unblinking eyes."<br>—Zul Ashur, lich lord]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steven Belledin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[90]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221522]]></id><name><![CDATA[Demon's Horn]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever a player casts a black spell, you may gain 1 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Its curve mimics the twists of life and death.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Alan Pollack]]></artist><number><![CDATA[205]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : The ability triggers whenever any player, not just you, casts a black spell. <br>10/1/2009 : If a player casts a black spell, Demon's Horn's ability triggers and is put on the stack on top of that spell. Demon's Horn's ability will resolve (causing you to gain 1 life) before the spell does.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[238328]]></id><name><![CDATA[Demystify]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Destroy target enchantment.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Behind every mage is a trail of shattered lies.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Véronique Meignaud]]></artist><number><![CDATA[13]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[226563]]></id><name><![CDATA[Devouring Swarm]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Insect]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Sacrifice a creature: Devouring Swarm gets +1/+1 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Their arrival is heralded by the deafening hum of ten thousand wings. Their departure is marked by the silence of the dead.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Wayne England]]></artist><number><![CDATA[91]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221519]]></id><name><![CDATA[Diabolic Tutor]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Search your library for a card and put that card into your hand. Then shuffle your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The wise always keep an ear open to the whispers of power.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Greg Staples]]></artist><number><![CDATA[92]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244245]]></id><name><![CDATA[Disentomb]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Stop complaining. You can rest when you're dead. Oh—sorry."<br>—Liliana Vess]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Alex Horley-Orlandelli]]></artist><number><![CDATA[93]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : A "creature card" is any card with the type Creature, even if it has other types such as Artifact, Enchantment, or Land. Older cards of type Summon are also Creature cards. ]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[236908]]></id><name><![CDATA[Distress]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target player reveals his or her hand. You choose a nonland card from it. That player discards that card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Of course I'm sure I've gone mad. The little man who crawled out of my eye was quite clear on this."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Michael C. Hayes]]></artist><number><![CDATA[94]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220194]]></id><name><![CDATA[Divination]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Draw two cards.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The key to unlocking this puzzle is within you."<br>—Doriel, mentor of Mistral Isle]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Howard Lyon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[50]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220219]]></id><name><![CDATA[Divine Favor]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>When Divine Favor enters the battlefield, you gain 3 life.<br>Enchanted creature gets +1/+3.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[With an armory of light, even the squire may champion her people.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Allen Williams]]></artist><number><![CDATA[14]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If the creature targeted by Divine Favor is an illegal target when Divine Favor tries to resolve, Divine Favor will be countered. It won't enter the battlefield and its enters-the-battlefield ability won't trigger.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[227305]]></id><name><![CDATA[Djinn of Wishes]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Djinn]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Djinn of Wishes enters the battlefield with three wish counters on it.<br>{2}{U}{U}, Remove a wish counter from Djinn of Wishes: Reveal the top card of your library. You may play that card without paying its mana cost. If you don't, exile it.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kev Walker]]></artist><number><![CDATA[51]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : You play the revealed card as part of the resolution of Djinn of Wishes's ability. Timing restrictions based on the card's type (such as creature or sorcery) are ignored. Other play restrictions are not (such as "Cast [this card] only during combat"). <br>10/1/2009 : If the revealed card is a spell, you may cast it only if you can choose legal targets for it. If you cast it, it's put on the stack, then Djinn of Wishes's ability finishes resolving. The spell will then resolve as normal, after players get a chance to cast spells and activate abilities. <br>10/1/2009 : If the revealed card is a land, you can play it only if it's your turn and you haven't yet played a land this turn. <br>10/1/2009 : If you play a card "without paying its mana cost," you can't pay any alternative costs. You can pay additional costs, such as conspire costs and kicker costs.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[226560]]></id><name><![CDATA[Doom Blade]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Destroy target nonblack creature.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chippy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[95]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220152]]></id><name><![CDATA[Doubling Chant]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[For each creature you control, you may search your library for a creature card with the same name as that creature. Put those cards onto the battlefield, then shuffle your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[What's scarier than one of every beast in the forest?]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Wayne England]]></artist><number><![CDATA[170]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : The cards you find in your library must be creature cards. For example, you can't put a land card onto the battlefield even if it has the same name as a land you control that's also a creature (perhaps because of an ability of that land). <br>9/22/2011 : If you control a creature whose name has been changed by an effect (for example, a Clone that's copying another creature), you'll search for a card with the new name, not one with the original name. <br>9/22/2011 : If you control no creatures when Doubling Chant resolves, you may still search your library and you must shuffle your library.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221523]]></id><name><![CDATA[Dragon's Claw]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever a player casts a red spell, you may gain 1 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["If there is a fire that never ceases to burn, it surely lies in the maw of a dragon."<br>—Sarkhan Vol]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Alan Pollack]]></artist><number><![CDATA[206]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : The ability triggers whenever any player, not just you, casts a red spell. <br>10/1/2009 : If a player casts a red spell, Dragon's Claw's ability triggers and is put on the stack on top of that spell. Dragon's Claw's ability will resolve (causing you to gain 1 life) before the spell does.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221921]]></id><name><![CDATA[Dragonskull Summit]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Dragonskull Summit enters the battlefield tapped unless you control a Swamp or a Mountain.<br>{T}: Add {B} or {R} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jon Foster]]></artist><number><![CDATA[225]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : This checks for lands you control with the land type Swamp or Mountain, not for lands named Swamp or Mountain. The lands it checks for don't have to be basic lands. For example, if you control Stomping Ground (a nonbasic land with the land types Mountain and Forest), Dragonskull Summit will enter the battlefield untapped. <br>10/1/2009 : As This is entering the battlefield, it checks for lands that are already on the battlefield. It won't see lands that are entering the battlefield at the same time (due to Warp World, for example).]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220088]]></id><name><![CDATA[Drifting Shade]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Shade]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>{B}: Drifting Shade gets +1/+1 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It stalks the fens by the light of the full moon, gathering shadows as it floats among them.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Tomasz Jedruszek]]></artist><number><![CDATA[96]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221920]]></id><name><![CDATA[Drowned Catacomb]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Drowned Catacomb enters the battlefield tapped unless you control an Island or a Swamp.<br>{T}: Add {U} or {B} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Kendall]]></artist><number><![CDATA[226]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : This checks for lands you control with the land type Island or Swamp, not for lands named Island or Swamp. The lands it checks for don't have to be basic lands. For example, if you control Blood Crypt (a nonbasic land with the land types Swamp and Mountain), Drowned Catacomb will enter the battlefield untapped. <br>10/1/2009 : As This is entering the battlefield, it checks for lands that are already on the battlefield. It won't see lands that are entering the battlefield at the same time (due to Warp World, for example).]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220098]]></id><name><![CDATA[Druidic Satchel]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{2}, {T}: Reveal the top card of your library. If it's a creature card, put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield. If it's a land card, put that card onto the battlefield under your control. If it's a noncreature, nonland card, you gain 2 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Matt Stewart]]></artist><number><![CDATA[207]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If the revealed card is both a creature and a land (such as Dryad Arbor), you'll put a Saproling creature token and that card onto the battlefield. <br>9/22/2011 : If the card is not a land card, it will remain on top of your library.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220210]]></id><name><![CDATA[Dungrove Elder]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Treefolk]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[*]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[*]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Hexproof (This creature can't be the target of spells or abilities your opponents control.)<br>Dungrove Elder's power and toughness are each equal to the number of Forests you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[All the trees of the forest are his army, and every leaf his shield.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Matt Stewart]]></artist><number><![CDATA[171]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : Dungrove Elder's power and toughness are each equal to the number of lands you control with the land type Forest, not necessarily lands named Forest. <br>9/22/2011 : Dungrove Elder's power and toughness will change as the number of Forests you control changes. <br>9/22/2011 : Dungrove Elder's ability sets its power and toughness in all zones, not just the battlefield.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220259]]></id><name><![CDATA[Duskhunter Bat]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Bat]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Bloodthirst 1 (If an opponent was dealt damage this turn, this creature enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it.)<br>Flying]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The swamps go silent at its approach, but it still hears the heartbeat of the prey within.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jesper Ejsing]]></artist><number><![CDATA[97]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[240315]]></id><name><![CDATA[Elite Vanguard]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The vanguard is skilled at waging war alone. The enemy is often defeated before its reinforcements reach the front.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mark Tedin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[15]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221525]]></id><name><![CDATA[Elixir of Immortality]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{2}, {T}: You gain 5 life. Shuffle Elixir of Immortality and your graveyard into their owner's library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Bottled life. Not as tasty as I'm used to, rather stale, but it has the same effect."<br>—Baron Sengir]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Zoltan Boros & Gabor Szikszai]]></artist><number><![CDATA[208]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : Paying the activation cost of Elixir of Immortality's ability doesn't cause it to leave the battlefield. If you have a way to untap it, you can activate the ability multiple times in response to itself. <br>9/22/2011 : As the ability resolves, you'll shuffle Elixir of Immortality into its owner's library directly from the battlefield, if it's still there. <br>9/22/2011 : If Elixir of Immortality is in your graveyard at the time the ability resolves, you'll still wind up shuffling it into your library because you shuffle your entire graveyard into your library. If it's anywhere else by that time, including in another player's graveyard, it remains where it is and you shuffle just your graveyard into your library. <br>9/22/2011 : If you gain control of another player's Elixir of Immortality and activate it, the Elixir of Immortality will be shuffled into its owner's library and the cards in your graveyard will be shuffled into your library. You are considered to have shuffled each affected library (even if, as a shortcut, each player physically shuffles his or her own library).]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[237007]]></id><name><![CDATA[Elvish Archdruid]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elf Druid]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Other Elf creatures you control get +1/+1.<br>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool for each Elf you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[He knows the name of every elf born in the last four centuries. More importantly, they all know his.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Karl Kopinski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[172]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : Elvish Archdruid's first ability affects only other Elves you control. However, Elvish Archdruid's second ability counts all Elves you control -- including itself. <br>9/22/2011 : Elvish Archdruid's activated ability is a mana ability. It doesn't use the stack and players can't respond to it.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[238331]]></id><name><![CDATA[Fiery Hellhound]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental Hound]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{R}: Fiery Hellhound gets +1/+0 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[There's nothing more exciting than a game of fetch the still-beating heart.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ted Galaday]]></artist><number><![CDATA[130]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221550]]></id><name><![CDATA[Fireball]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{X}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Fireball deals X damage divided evenly, rounded down, among any number of target creatures and/or players.<br>Fireball costs {1} more to cast for each target beyond the first.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Dorman]]></artist><number><![CDATA[131]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>12/1/2004 : The additional cost is paid when you pay the rest of Fireball's costs, even though that text appears second on the card (to make the card easier to read). The additional cost doesn't count toward Fireball's converted mana cost. <br>12/1/2004 : If, for example, X is 5 and you choose three target creatures, Fireball has a total cost of {7}{R} (even though its mana cost is just {5}{R}). If those creatures are all still legal targets as Fireball resolves, it deals 1 damage to each of them. <br>5/1/2009 : You may cast Fireball with zero targets, regardless of the value chosen for X. If you do so, it will not be a targeted spell, and no damage will actually be dealt when it resolves. <br>10/1/2009 : Fireball's damage is divided as Fireball resolves, not as it's cast, because there are no choices involved. The division involves only targets that are still legal at that time. <br>10/1/2009 : You can target more than X creatures. However, if the number of legal targets at the time Fireball resolves is greater than X, none of them will be dealt any damage.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[226588]]></id><name><![CDATA[Firebreathing]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>{R}: Enchanted creature gets +1/+0 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The mage breathed in life-giving air and breathed out death-bringing fire.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Aleksi Briclot]]></artist><number><![CDATA[132]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : This ability can be activated by Firebreathing's controller, not the enchanted creature's controller (in case they're different players). <br>10/1/2009 : The ability affects whichever creature is enchanted by Firebreathing at the time the ability resolves. The bonus remains even if Firebreathing stops enchanting that creature.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244720]]></id><name><![CDATA[Flameblast Dragon]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Dragon]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Whenever Flameblast Dragon attacks, you may pay {X}{R}. If you do, Flameblast Dragon deals X damage to target creature or player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[He marks his territory with fire and wrath, etching the mountainside with his charring breath.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jaime Jones]]></artist><number><![CDATA[133]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2008 : You choose the target when the ability triggers. When the ability resolves, you choose a value for X and decide whether to pay {X}{R}. If you do decide to pay {X}{R}, it's too late for any player to respond since the ability is already in the midst of resolving.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220249]]></id><name><![CDATA[Flashfreeze]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Counter target red or green spell.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Is cold merely the absence of heat, or a force unto itself? Would a display of its power help you decide?"<br>—Zubarek, Icewinder Magus]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Brian Despain]]></artist><number><![CDATA[52]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[237366]]></id><name><![CDATA[Flight]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature has flying.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Those who claim to know the world in its entirety rarely have the requisite perspective."<br>—Ulmarus the Wise]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mark Zug]]></artist><number><![CDATA[53]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[241858]]></id><name><![CDATA[Fling]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[As an additional cost to cast Fling, sacrifice a creature.<br>Fling deals damage equal to the sacrificed creature's power to target creature or player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[About halfway to the target, Snukk vowed that he had been tricked for the last time.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Parente]]></artist><number><![CDATA[134]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : The sacrificed creature's last known existence on the battlefield is checked to determine its power. <br>8/15/2010 : If you sacrifice an attacking or blocking creature during the declare blockers step, it won't deal combat damage. If you wait until the combat damage step, but that creature is dealt lethal damage, it'll be destroyed before you get a chance to sacrifice it. <br>4/15/2013 : You must sacrifice exactly one creature to cast this spell; you cannot cast it without sacrificing a creature, and you cannot sacrifice additional creatures. <br>4/15/2013 : Players can only respond once this spell has been cast and all its costs have been paid. No one can try to destroy the creature you sacrificed to prevent you from casting this spell.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[226900]]></id><name><![CDATA[Fog]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt this turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It's hard enough to find your way through uncharted wilderness when you can see the tip of your nose.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jaime Jones]]></artist><number><![CDATA[173]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : Fog has no effect on damage that's already been dealt.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244319]]></id><name><![CDATA[Forest]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Forest]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{G}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Volkan Baga]]></artist><number><![CDATA[247]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220284]]></id><name><![CDATA[Frost Breath]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Tap up to two target creatures. Those creatures don't untap during their controller's next untap step.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[If you have to be stuck somewhere for a while, it's better to be stuck there with a friend.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mike Bierek]]></artist><number><![CDATA[54]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If a creature affected by Frost Breath changes controllers before its old controller's next untap step, Frost Breath will prevent it from becoming untapped during its new controller's next untap step. <br>4/15/2013 : This spell can target tapped creatures. If a targeted creature is already tapped when the spell resolves, that creature just remains tapped and doesn't untap during its controller's next untap step.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[235191]]></id><name><![CDATA[Frost Titan]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Giant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever Frost Titan becomes the target of a spell or ability an opponent controls, counter that spell or ability unless its controller pays {2}.<br>Whenever Frost Titan enters the battlefield or attacks, tap target permanent. It doesn't untap during its controller's next untap step.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mike Bierek]]></artist><number><![CDATA[55]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : Frost Titan's first ability affects each spell (including Aura spells), activated ability, and triggered ability that's controlled by an opponent and that Frost Titan becomes a target of. <br>8/15/2010 : You may target any permanent with Frost Titan's second ability. It's okay if that permanent is already tapped. <br>8/15/2010 : If the permanent affected by Frost Titan's second ability is untapped at the time that permanent's controller's next untap step begins, the last part of Frost Titan's second ability has no effect. <br>8/15/2010 : If the permanent affected by Frost Titan's second ability changes controllers before its old controller's next untap step, Frost Titan's second ability will prevent it from being untapped during its new controller's next untap step.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220103]]></id><name><![CDATA[Furyborn Hellkite]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Dragon]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{R}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Bloodthirst 6 (If an opponent was dealt damage this turn, this creature enters the battlefield with six +1/+1 counters on it.)<br>Flying]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Careful. A drop of blood here means death for us all."<br>—Kalek, mountain guide]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Brad Rigney]]></artist><number><![CDATA[135]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220100]]></id><name><![CDATA[Garruk, Primal Hunter]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Planeswalker — Garruk]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[3]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[+1: Put a 3/3 green Beast creature token onto the battlefield.<br>-3: Draw cards equal to the greatest power among creatures you control.<br>-6: Put a 6/6 green Wurm creature token onto the battlefield for each land you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[D. Alexander Gregory]]></artist><number><![CDATA[174]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : For Garruk's second ability, the greatest power among creatures you control is determined when that ability begins resolving. <br>9/22/2011 : If the greatest power among creatures you control is 0 or less, you'll draw no cards. You won't discard any cards this way. <br>9/22/2011 : For Garruk's third ability, the number of Wurm tokens you put onto the battlefield is determined when that ability begins resolving.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[226896]]></id><name><![CDATA[Garruk's Companion]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Beast]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample (If this creature would assign enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it assign the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Efrem Palacios]]></artist><number><![CDATA[175]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220077]]></id><name><![CDATA[Garruk's Horde]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Beast]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[7]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[7]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample <br>Play with the top card of your library revealed.<br>You may cast the top card of your library if it's a creature card. (Do this only any time you could cast that creature card. You still pay the spell's costs.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Prescott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[176]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : Normally, Garruk's Horde allows you to cast the top card of your library if it's a creature card, it's your main phase, and the stack is empty. If that creature card has flash, you'll be able to cast it at the time you could cast an instant, even on an opponent's turn. <br>9/22/2011 : You'll still pay all costs for that spell, including additional costs. You may also pay alternative costs. <br>9/22/2011 : While playing with the top card of your library revealed, if you draw multiple cards, reveal each one before you draw it. <br>9/22/2011 : If the top card of your library is Dryad Arbor (the only card that's both a creature and a land), you can't play it this way. Dryad Arbor can't be cast as a spell. <br>4/15/2013 : The top card of your library isn't in your hand, so you can't suspend it, cycle it, discard it, or activate any of its activated abilities. <br>4/15/2013 : If the top card of your library is a land, you can play it if you could play a land. <br>4/15/2013 : If the top card of your library changes while you're casting a spell or activating an ability, the new top card won't be revealed until you finish casting that spell or activating that ability. <br>4/15/2013 : When playing with the top card of your library revealed, if an effect tells you to draw several cards, reveal each one before you draw it.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[233232]]></id><name><![CDATA[Giant Spider]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Spider]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The wild is always changing, but it does have a few constants."<br>—Garruk Wildspeaker]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Randy Gallegos]]></artist><number><![CDATA[177]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>4/1/2008 : This card now uses the Reach keyword ability to enable the blocking of flying creatures. This works because a creature with flying can only be blocked by creatures with flying or reach.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[238329]]></id><name><![CDATA[Gideon Jura]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Planeswalker — Gideon]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[6]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[+2: During target opponent's next turn, creatures that player controls attack Gideon Jura if able.<br>-2: Destroy target tapped creature.<br>0: Until end of turn, Gideon Jura becomes a 6/6 Human Soldier creature that's still a planeswalker. Prevent all damage that would be dealt to him this turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Aleksi Briclot]]></artist><number><![CDATA[16]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/15/2010 : Gideon Jura's first ability doesn't lock in what it applies to. That's because the effect states a true thing about a set of creatures, but doesn't actually change the characteristics of those creatures. As a result, whatever creatures the targeted opponent controls during the declare attackers step of his or her next turn must attack Gideon Jura if able. This includes creatures that come under that player's control after the ability has resolved and creatures that have lost all abilities. <br>6/15/2010 : Gideon Jura's first ability causes creatures to attack him if able. If, during the affected player's declare attackers step, a creature he or she controls is tapped, is affected by a spell or ability that says it can't attack, or is affected by "summoning sickness," then that creature doesn't attack. If there's a cost associated with having a creature attack, the player isn't forced to pay that cost, so the creature doesn't have to attack in that case either. <br>6/15/2010 : If a creature controlled by the affected player can't attack Gideon Jura (because he's no longer on the battlefield, for example), that player may have it attack you, another one of your planeswalkers, or nothing at all. <br>6/15/2010 : Gideon Jura's first ability applies during each combat phase of the affected player's next turn (as opposed to applying during the affected player's next combat phase). The distinction is relevant if there are no combat phases during that turn (due to Fatespinner's effect, for example) or there are multiples (due to World at War, for example). <br>6/15/2010 : If Gideon Jura becomes a creature due to his third ability, that doesn't count as having a creature enter the battlefield. Gideon Jura was already on the battlefield; he only changed his types. Abilities that trigger whenever a creature enters the battlefield won't trigger. <br>6/15/2010 : If Gideon Jura becomes a creature, he may be affected by "summoning sickness." You can't attack with him or use any of his {T} abilities (if he gains any) unless he began your most recent turn on the battlefield under your control. Note that summoning sickness cares about when Gideon Jura came under your control, not when he became a creature. <br>6/15/2010 : Gideon Jura's third ability causes him to become a creature with the creature types Human Soldier. He remains a planeswalker with the planeswalker type Gideon. (He also retains any other card types or subtypes he may have had.) Each subtype is correlated to the proper card type: Gideon is just a planeswalker type (not a creature type), and Human and Soldier are just creature types (not planeswalker types). <br>6/15/2010 : If you activate Gideon Jura's third ability and then unpreventable damage is dealt to him (due to Unstable Footing, for example), that damage has all applicable results: specifically, the damage is marked on Gideon Jura (since he's a creature) and that damage causes that many loyalty counters to be removed from him (since he's a planeswalker). If the total amount of damage marked on Gideon Jura is lethal damage, he's destroyed as a state-based action. If Gideon Jura has no loyalty counters on him, he's put into his owner's graveyard as a state-based action. <br>6/15/2010 : If you activate Gideon Jura's third ability and then a creature enters the battlefield as a copy of him, that copy will be just a planeswalker, not a creature. (The effect of Gideon's third ability isn't copied, just as the effect of a Giant Growth, for example, wouldn't be copied.) Since both permanents will be planeswalkers with the planeswalker type Gideon, each one will be put into his owner's graveyard as a state-based action due to the "planeswalker uniqueness rule." <br>6/15/2010 : If you activate Gideon Jura's third ability and then a permanent that's already on the battlefield becomes a copy of him, that copy will be just a planeswalker, not a creature. If the original Gideon Jura is still on the battlefield by the time the copy effect happens, each of those permanents will be put into his owner's graveyard as a state-based action due to the "planeswalker uniqueness rule." If the original Gideon Jura is gone by this time, the other permanent will be put into his owner's graveyard as a state-based action for having no loyalty counters on him (unless, for some odd reason, he already had loyalty counters on him). <br>6/15/2010 : Say you activate Gideon Jura's third ability, then an opponent gains control of him before combat. You may have any of your creatures attack Gideon Jura (since he's still a planeswalker). Then Gideon Jura may block (since he's a creature). He may block any eligible attacking creature, including one that's attacking him! During combat, he behaves as an attacked planeswalker and/or a blocking creature, as appropriate. For example, he deals combat damage to any creatures he's blocking, but he doesn't deal combat damage to any unblocked creatures that are attacking him. <br>1/22/2011 : The first ability only affects the declaration of attackers. If a creature is put onto the battlefield attacking (thanks to Hero of Bladehold, Preeminent Captain, or the Ninjutsu ability, for example), that creature's controller may choose the defending player or planeswalker that it will be attacking in the normal way.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220239]]></id><name><![CDATA[Gideon's Avenger]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever a creature an opponent controls becomes tapped, put a +1/+1 counter on Gideon's Avenger.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The good don't sit and wait for the evil to act. They prepare to defend. They prepare to punish."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Randy Gallegos]]></artist><number><![CDATA[17]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If an opponent's creature enters the battlefield tapped, Gideon's Avenger's ability doesn't trigger.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[228122]]></id><name><![CDATA[Gideon's Lawkeeper]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{W}, {T}: Tap target creature.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The essence of a lawful society is swift deterrence."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Prescott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[18]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221919]]></id><name><![CDATA[Glacial Fortress]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Glacial Fortress enters the battlefield tapped unless you control a Plains or an Island.<br>{T}: Add {W} or {U} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Franz Vohwinkel]]></artist><number><![CDATA[227]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : This checks for lands you control with the land type Plains or Island, not for lands named Plains or Island. The lands it checks for don't have to be basic lands. For example, if you control Watery Grave (a nonbasic land with the land types Island and Swamp), Glacial Fortress will enter the battlefield untapped. <br>10/1/2009 : As This is entering the battlefield, it checks for lands that are already on the battlefield. It won't see lands that are entering the battlefield at the same time (due to Warp World, for example).]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220082]]></id><name><![CDATA[Gladecover Scout]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elf Scout]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Hexproof (This creature can't be the target of spells or abilities your opponents control.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The forest is my cover and I hold it close. In such a tight embrace, there is no room for wickedness."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Allen Williams]]></artist><number><![CDATA[178]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[242485]]></id><name><![CDATA[Goblin Arsonist]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Goblin Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Goblin Arsonist dies, you may have it deal 1 damage to target creature or player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[With great power comes great risk of getting yourself killed.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Wayne Reynolds]]></artist><number><![CDATA[136]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[229952]]></id><name><![CDATA[Goblin Bangchuckers]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Goblin Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Flip a coin. If you win the flip, Goblin Bangchuckers deals 2 damage to target creature or player. If you lose the flip, Goblin Bangchuckers deals 2 damage to itself.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Wayne Reynolds]]></artist><number><![CDATA[137]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : You choose the target creature or player when you activate the ability. You don't flip the coin until the ability resolves. Players may respond to the ability, but they won't know the results of the coin flip. <br>9/22/2011 : If the creature or player is an illegal target when Goblin Bangchuckers' ability tries to resolve, it will be countered and none of its effects will happen. You won't flip a coin and no damage will be dealt.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221201]]></id><name><![CDATA[Goblin Chieftain]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Goblin]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Haste (This creature can attack and {T} as soon as it comes under your control.)<br>Other Goblin creatures you control get +1/+1 and have haste.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["It's time for the ‘Smash, Smash' song!"]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Sam Wood]]></artist><number><![CDATA[138]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[228959]]></id><name><![CDATA[Goblin Fireslinger]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Goblin Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Goblin Fireslinger deals 1 damage to target player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[A rock between your eyes hurts. A burning rock between your eyes ruins your whole day.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Pete Venters]]></artist><number><![CDATA[139]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220435]]></id><name><![CDATA[Goblin Grenade]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[As an additional cost to cast Goblin Grenade, sacrifice a Goblin.<br>Goblin Grenade deals 5 damage to target creature or player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Don't underestimate the aerodynamic qualities of the common goblin.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kev Walker]]></artist><number><![CDATA[140]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/4/2004 : You can't sacrifice more than one Goblin to get a greater effect.  <br>9/22/2011 : Players can only respond once Goblin Grenade has been cast and all its costs have been paid. No one can try and destroy the Goblin to prevent you from casting Goblin Grenade. <br>9/22/2011 : The Goblin you sacrifice to cast Goblin Grenade doesn't have to be a creature. For example, you could sacrifice Boggart Shenanigans (a tribal enchantment with the subtype Goblin).]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221199]]></id><name><![CDATA[Goblin Piker]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Goblin Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Once he'd worked out which end of the thing was sharp, he was promoted to guard duty.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[DiTerlizzi]]></artist><number><![CDATA[141]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[245185]]></id><name><![CDATA[Goblin Tunneler]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Goblin Rogue]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Target creature with power 2 or less is unblockable this turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The best way over the mountain is through."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jesper Ejsing]]></artist><number><![CDATA[142]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/15/2010 : The power of the targeted creature is checked both as you target it and as the ability resolves. After the ability resolves, the creature will remain unblockable even if its power becomes greater than 2. <br>6/15/2010 : The ability doesn't grant an ability to the targeted creature. Rather, it affects the game rules and states something that's now true about that creature. After the ability resolves, the creature will remain unblockable for the rest of the turn even if it loses all abilities.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[236461]]></id><name><![CDATA[Goblin War Paint]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 and has haste. (It can attack and {T} no matter when it came under its controller's control.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The secret to our war paint is hot peppers and stinkbugs. Lots of stinkbugs."<br>—Skab, goblin secretkeeper]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Austin Hsu]]></artist><number><![CDATA[143]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220294]]></id><name><![CDATA[Gorehorn Minotaurs]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Minotaur Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Bloodthirst 2 (If an opponent was dealt damage this turn, this creature enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Some of the eleven minotaur clans of Mirtiin are expert crafters and learned philosophers. Others just like to hit stuff.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Wayne Reynolds]]></artist><number><![CDATA[144]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221898]]></id><name><![CDATA[Grand Abolisher]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Cleric]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[During your turn, your opponents can't cast spells or activate abilities of artifacts, creatures, or enchantments.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Your superstitions and mumblings are useless chaff before my righteousness."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Eric Deschamps]]></artist><number><![CDATA[19]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : Grand Abolisher doesn't stop your opponents from activating abilities of artifact, creature, or enchantment cards in zones other than the battlefield (like cycling abilities, for example). <br>9/22/2011 : Grand Abolisher doesn't affect triggered abilities or static abilities.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[241830]]></id><name><![CDATA[Grave Titan]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Giant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Deathtouch<br>Whenever Grave Titan enters the battlefield or attacks, put two 2/2 black Zombie creature tokens onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Death in form and function.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Nils Hamm]]></artist><number><![CDATA[98]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221526]]></id><name><![CDATA[Gravedigger]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Zombie]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Gravedigger enters the battlefield, you may return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[His grim ritual ushers the dead to their new life.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dermot Power]]></artist><number><![CDATA[99]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : A "creature card" is any card with the type Creature, even if it has other types such as Artifact, Enchantment, or Land. Older cards of type Summon are also Creature cards. ]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[233233]]></id><name><![CDATA[Greater Basilisk]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Basilisk]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Deathtouch (Any amount of damage this deals to a creature is enough to destroy it.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Bone, stone . . . both taste the same to a hungry basilisk.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[James Ryman]]></artist><number><![CDATA[179]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220296]]></id><name><![CDATA[Greatsword]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact — Equipment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Equipped creature gets +3/+0.<br>Equip {3} ({3}: Attach to target creature you control. Equip only as a sorcery.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The only blow that matters is the killing blow.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Nic Klein]]></artist><number><![CDATA[209]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220282]]></id><name><![CDATA[Griffin Rider]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Knight]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[As long as you control a Griffin creature, Griffin Rider gets +3/+3 and has flying.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[After fighting alongside the griffin riders, older knights of Thune learned to admire a mount that could rip an enemy to shreds in seconds.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Prescott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[20]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[222650]]></id><name><![CDATA[Griffin Sentinel]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Griffin]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Vigilance (Attacking doesn't cause this creature to tap.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Once a griffin sentinel adopts a territory as its own, only death can force it to betray its post.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Warren Mahy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[21]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[234428]]></id><name><![CDATA[Grim Lavamancer]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{R}, {T}, Exile two cards from your graveyard: Grim Lavamancer deals 2 damage to target creature or player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Fools dig for water, corpses, or gold. The earth's real treasure is far deeper."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Michael Sutfin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[145]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : The two cards are exiled as the cost of Grim Lavamancer's ability is paid. Players can't respond to the paying of costs by trying to move those cards to another zone.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220095]]></id><name><![CDATA[Guardians' Pledge]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[White creatures you control get +2/+2 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[A dozen fighting for each other are worth a thousand fighting for themselves.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Christopher Moeller]]></artist><number><![CDATA[22]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : Guardians' Pledge only gives a bonus to white creatures you control when it resolves. Creatures that enter the battlefield later in the turn and nonwhite creatures that become white later in the turn will not get the bonus. <br>9/22/2011 : If a white creature that gets the bonus stops being white later in the turn, it will continue to get +2/+2 until end of turn.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[230756]]></id><name><![CDATA[Harbor Serpent]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Serpent]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Islandwalk (This creature is unblockable as long as defending player controls an Island.)<br>Harbor Serpent can't attack unless there are five or more Islands on the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Like most giant monsters villagers worship as gods, it proves a fickle master.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Daarken]]></artist><number><![CDATA[56]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : Harbor Serpent's abilities care about lands with the land type Island, not necessarily lands named Island. <br>8/15/2010 : The second ability checks how many Islands are on the battlefield (regardless of who controls them) only as attackers are declared. Once Harbor Serpent is declared as an attacker, it will continue to attack even if the number of Islands on the battlefield falls below five.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220304]]></id><name><![CDATA[Hideous Visage]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Creatures you control gain intimidate until end of turn. (Each of those creatures can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or creatures that share a color with it.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Seeing you cower before me is its own reward."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Nils Hamm]]></artist><number><![CDATA[100]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If an attacking creature has intimidate, what colors it is matters only as the defending player declares blockers. Once it's blocked, changing its colors won't change that. <br>9/22/2011 : A multicolored creature with intimidate can be blocked by any creature that shares a color with it, in addition to artifact creatures. For example, a white-blue creature with intimidate can be blocked by white creatures and/or blue creatures, no matter what other colors they are.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[233237]]></id><name><![CDATA[Honor of the Pure]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[White creatures you control get +1/+1.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Together the soldiers were like a golden blade, cutting down their enemies and scarring the darkness.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Greg Staples]]></artist><number><![CDATA[23]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220291]]></id><name><![CDATA[Hunter's Insight]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Choose target creature you control. Whenever that creature deals combat damage to a player or planeswalker this turn, draw that many cards.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The predator knows the true way of the world. Life is conflict. Only the strong survive."<br>—Garruk Wildspeaker]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Terese Nielsen]]></artist><number><![CDATA[180]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[245283]]></id><name><![CDATA[Ice Cage]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature can't attack or block, and its activated abilities can't be activated.<br>When enchanted creature becomes the target of a spell or ability, destroy Ice Cage.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mike Bierek]]></artist><number><![CDATA[57]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : If the enchanted creature becomes the target of a spell or ability, Ice Cage's ability triggers and is put on the stack on top of that spell or ability. Ice Cage's ability will resolve (causing Ice Cage to be destroyed) first.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[234075]]></id><name><![CDATA[Incinerate]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Incinerate deals 3 damage to target creature or player. A creature dealt damage this way can't be regenerated this turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Spontaneous combustion is a myth. If you burst into flame, someone wanted you to."<br>—Chandra Nalaar]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Zoltan Boros & Gabor Szikszai]]></artist><number><![CDATA[146]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>7/15/2007 : Regeneration abilities that would affect that creature can still be activated; they just won't do anything. The creature can't be regenerated for any reason, even if an effect other than Incinerate would deal lethal damage to it or otherwise destroy it.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[235192]]></id><name><![CDATA[Inferno Titan]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Giant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{R}: Inferno Titan gets +1/+0 until end of turn.<br>Whenever Inferno Titan enters the battlefield or attacks, it deals 3 damage divided as you choose among one, two, or three target creatures and/or players.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kev Walker]]></artist><number><![CDATA[147]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : You divide the damage as you put Inferno Titan's triggered ability on the stack, not as it resolves. Each target must be assigned at least 1 damage. (In other words, as you put the ability on the stack, you choose whether to have it deal 3 damage to a single target, 2 damage to one target and 1 damage to another target, or 1 damage to each of three targets.)]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244323]]></id><name><![CDATA[Island]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Island]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{U}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Cliff Childs]]></artist><number><![CDATA[235]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[238263]]></id><name><![CDATA[Jace, Memory Adept]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Planeswalker — Jace]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[4]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[+1: Draw a card. Target player puts the top card of his or her library into his or her graveyard.<br>0: Target player puts the top ten cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard.<br>-7: Any number of target players each draw twenty cards.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[D. Alexander Gregory]]></artist><number><![CDATA[58]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If you target yourself with Jace's first ability, you'll draw a card first, then put the top card of your library into your graveyard. <br>9/22/2011 : If you activate Jace's first ability, and the player is an illegal target when the ability tries to resolve, it will be countered and none of its effects will happen. You won't draw a card. <br>9/22/2011 : If Jace's third ability causes a player to draw more cards than are left in his or her library, that player loses the game as a state-based action. If this ability causes all players to do this, the game is a draw.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220244]]></id><name><![CDATA[Jace's Archivist]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Vedalken Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{U}, {T}: Each player discards his or her hand, then draws cards equal to the greatest number of cards a player discarded this way.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["This is a sacred duty. Master Beleren's trust has bought an eternity of my loyalty."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[James Ryman]]></artist><number><![CDATA[59]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If this ability causes a player to draw more cards than are left in his or her library, that player loses the game as a state-based action. If this ability causes all players to do this, the game is a draw.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[227227]]></id><name><![CDATA[Jace's Erasure]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever you draw a card, you may have target player put the top card of his or her library into his or her graveyard.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["You should try to clear your mind of idle thoughts. And if you can't, I will."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jason Chan]]></artist><number><![CDATA[60]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : If a spell or ability causes you to draw multiple cards, Jace's Erasure's ability triggers that many times. (The spell or ability finishes resolving before you put Jace's Erasure's abilities on the stack.) <br>8/15/2010 : If a spell or ability causes you to put cards in your hand without specifically using the word "draw," Jace's Erasure's ability won't trigger.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220279]]></id><name><![CDATA[Jade Mage]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{2}{G}: Put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["We are one with the wild things. Life blooms from our fingertips and nature responds to our summons."<br>—Jade creed]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Izzy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[181]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244250]]></id><name><![CDATA[Kite Shield]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact — Equipment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{0}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Equipped creature gets +0/+3.<br>Equip {3} ({3}: Attach to target creature you control. Equip only as a sorcery.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["To my sword I owe my glory, but to my shield I owe my life."<br>—Sarlena, paladin of the Northern Verge]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jim Pavelec]]></artist><number><![CDATA[210]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221521]]></id><name><![CDATA[Kraken's Eye]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever a player casts a blue spell, you may gain 1 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It's seen the wonders of entire worlds trapped in the depths of a bottomless ocean.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Alan Pollack]]></artist><number><![CDATA[211]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : The ability triggers whenever any player, not just you, casts a blue spell. <br>10/1/2009 : If a player casts a blue spell, Kraken's Eye's ability triggers and is put on the stack on top of that spell. Kraken's Eye's ability will resolve (causing you to gain 1 life) before the spell does.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221891]]></id><name><![CDATA[Lava Axe]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Lava Axe deals 5 damage to target player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It can chop down a redwood in a single stroke. Your sternum isn't going to fare any better.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Brian Snoddy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[148]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[233728]]></id><name><![CDATA[Levitation]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Creatures you control have flying.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Why fight over scraps of land when there's so much sky waiting to be claimed?"]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jim Murray]]></artist><number><![CDATA[61]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220182]]></id><name><![CDATA[Lifelink]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature has lifelink. (Damage dealt by the creature also causes its controller to gain that much life.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The spoils of war are not measured only in gold and silver.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Terese Nielsen]]></artist><number><![CDATA[24]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : The controller of the enchanted creature, not the controller of Lifelink, gains the life (in case they're different players).]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220240]]></id><name><![CDATA[Lightning Elemental]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Haste (This creature can attack and {T} as soon as it comes under your control.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Oh, it's easy enough to kill, but I'm not going anywhere near it."<br>—Norin the Wary]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kev Walker]]></artist><number><![CDATA[149]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221892]]></id><name><![CDATA[Llanowar Elves]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elf Druid]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[One bone broken for every twig snapped underfoot.<br>—Llanowar penalty for trespassing]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kev Walker]]></artist><number><![CDATA[182]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220131]]></id><name><![CDATA[Lord of the Unreal]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Illusion creatures you control get +1/+1 and have hexproof. (They can't be the targets of spells or abilities your opponents control.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The dream does not end until I say so."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jason Chan]]></artist><number><![CDATA[62]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[226905]]></id><name><![CDATA[Lure]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>All creatures able to block enchanted creature do so.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It makes the insignificant conspicuous, the repulsive alluring, and the deadly irresistible.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[D. Alexander Gregory]]></artist><number><![CDATA[183]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/4/2004 : Lure does not give a creature the ability to block the Lured creature, it just forces those creatures which are already able to block the Lured creature to do so.  <br>10/4/2004 : If a Lured creature is in a band, only blockers able to block the Lured creature are affected by the Lure.  <br>10/4/2004 : The opponent does not have to activate any abilities in an attempt to make his or her creatures block. More specifically, a cost to block of zero mana is an optional cost you can choose not to pay. ]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220199]]></id><name><![CDATA[Lurking Crocodile]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Crocodile]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Bloodthirst 1 (If an opponent was dealt damage this turn, this creature enters the battlefield with a +1/+1 counter on it.)<br>Islandwalk (This creature is unblockable as long as defending player controls an Island.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Donato Giancola]]></artist><number><![CDATA[184]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[241831]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mana Leak]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Counter target spell unless its controller pays {3}.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The fatal flaw in every plan is the assumption that you know more than your enemy.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Howard Lyon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[63]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[235193]]></id><name><![CDATA[Manabarbs]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever a player taps a land for mana, Manabarbs deals 1 damage to that player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["I don't know why people say a double-edged sword is bad. It's a sword. With two edges."<br>—Kamahl, pit fighter]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jeff Miracola]]></artist><number><![CDATA[150]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/4/2004 : This card has a triggered ability that causes a separate effect for 1 point of damage each time a land is tapped for mana.  <br>10/1/2009 : This ability is not a mana ability. It goes on the stack and can be responded to. <br>10/1/2009 : The ability will trigger each time a land is tapped for mana. Each ability is separate. <br>10/1/2009 : If any lands are tapped for mana while a player is casting a spell or activating an ability, Manabarbs's ability will trigger that many times and wait. When the player finishes casting that spell or activating that ability, it's put on the stack, then Manabarbs's triggered abilities are put on the stack on top of it. The Manabarbs abilities will resolve first. <br>10/1/2009 : On the other hand, a player can tap lands for mana, let the Manabarbs triggered abilities be put on the stack, and then respond to those abilities by casting an instant or activating an ability using that mana. In that case, the spell or ability will resolve first.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220162]]></id><name><![CDATA[Manalith]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Planeswalkers seek out great monuments throughout the Multiverse, knowing that their builders were unknowingly drawn by the convergence of mana in the area.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Charles Urbach]]></artist><number><![CDATA[212]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[230764]]></id><name><![CDATA[Manic Vandal]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Manic Vandal enters the battlefield, destroy target artifact.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It's fun. He doesn't need another reason.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Christopher Moeller]]></artist><number><![CDATA[151]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : Manic Vandal's ability is mandatory. If you're the only player who controls an artifact, you must target one of them.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[228119]]></id><name><![CDATA[Master Thief]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Rogue]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Master Thief enters the battlefield, gain control of target artifact for as long as you control Master Thief.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Possession is ten-tenths of the law.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Christopher Moeller]]></artist><number><![CDATA[64]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If Master Thief leaves the battlefield, you no longer control it, and its control-change effect ends. <br>9/22/2011 : If Master Thief ceases to be under your control before its ability resolves, you won't gain control of the targeted artifact at all. <br>9/22/2011 : If another player gains control of Master Thief, its control-change effect ends. Regaining control of Master Thief won't cause you to regain control of the artifact.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220179]]></id><name><![CDATA[Merfolk Looter]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Merfolk Rogue]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Draw a card, then discard a card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Merfolk don't always know what they're looking for, but they're certain once they find it.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Austin Hsu]]></artist><number><![CDATA[65]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220106]]></id><name><![CDATA[Merfolk Mesmerist]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Merfolk Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{U}, {T}: Target player puts the top two cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Don't you think if I saw a half-woman, half-fish with three glowing eyes, I'd have remembered?"<br>—Drugo, town guard]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jana Schirmer & Johannes Voss]]></artist><number><![CDATA[66]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220116]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mesa Enchantress]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Druid]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever you cast an enchantment spell, you may draw a card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Scholars seek to understand the way the world is. I wish to shape the world into what it should be."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Randy Gallegos]]></artist><number><![CDATA[25]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2005 : This does not trigger on the moving of an Aura from one permanent to another.  <br>2/1/2007 : This is the timeshifted version of Verduran Enchantress. <br>2/1/2007 : If an effect changes the targets of this ability, the second target can be changed to any creature the chosen opponent controls. The choice of opponent can't be changed. <br>2/1/2007 : Tapped creatures can be targeted. Tapping them again will do nothing, but they'll still deal damage. <br>10/1/2009 : If you cast an enchantment spell, Mesa Enchantress's ability triggers and is put on the stack on top of that spell. Mesa Enchantress's ability will resolve before the spell does.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[241989]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mighty Leap]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target creature gets +2/+2 and gains flying until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The southern fortress taken by invaders? Heh, sure . . . when elephants fly."<br>—Brezard Skeinbow, captain of the guard]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[rk post]]></artist><number><![CDATA[26]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : You may target any creature with Mighty Leap. It's okay if that creature already has flying. <br>8/15/2010 : For flying to work as an evasion ability, Mighty Leap must be cast before the declare blockers step begins. Once a creature has become blocked, giving it flying won't change that.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[238572]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mind Control]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>You control enchanted creature.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Every primitive mind has a motive. Easy to find, and eminently exploitable."<br>—Noyan Dar, Tazeem lullmage]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ryan Pancoast]]></artist><number><![CDATA[67]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : Gaining control of a creature doesn't cause you gain control of any Auras or Equipment attached to it.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[234561]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mind Rot]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target player discards two cards.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Not every thought is a good one.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Luke]]></artist><number><![CDATA[101]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[236459]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mind Unbound]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[At the beginning of your upkeep, put a lore counter on Mind Unbound, then draw a card for each lore counter on Mind Unbound.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The creations of the hand are confined by reality. The creations of the mind know no such limits.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jason Felix]]></artist><number><![CDATA[68]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : The ability is mandatory. You can't choose to draw fewer cards than the number of lore counters on Mind Unbound.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220143]]></id><name><![CDATA[Monomania]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target player chooses a card in his or her hand and discards the rest.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["What do vermin cling to when all hope is lost?"<br>—Sorin Markov]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[James Ryman]]></artist><number><![CDATA[102]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If there are one or zero cards in the player's hand, he or she will discard no cards.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244330]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mountain]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Mountain]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Karl Kopinski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[243]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221894]]></id><name><![CDATA[Naturalize]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Destroy target artifact or enchantment.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["When your cities and trinkets crumble, only nature will remain."<br>—Garruk Wildspeaker]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Tim Hildebrandt]]></artist><number><![CDATA[185]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[230757]]></id><name><![CDATA[Negate]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Counter target noncreature spell.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Masters of the arcane savor a delicious irony. Their study of deep and complex arcana leads to such a simple end: the ability to say merely yes or no.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jeremy Jarvis]]></artist><number><![CDATA[69]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : A "creature spell" is any spell with the type Creature, even if it has other types such as Artifact or Enchantment. Older cards of type Summon are also Creature spells. ]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[234567]]></id><name><![CDATA[Oblivion Ring]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Oblivion Ring enters the battlefield, exile another target nonland permanent.<br>When Oblivion Ring leaves the battlefield, return the exiled card to the battlefield under its owner's control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Franz Vohwinkel]]></artist><number><![CDATA[27]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2007 : If Oblivion Ring leaves the battlefield before its first ability has resolved, its second ability will trigger and do nothing. Then its first ability will resolve and exile the targeted nonland permanent forever. <br>10/1/2007 : If there are no nonland permanents on the battlefield other than an Oblivion Ring, and the card it exiled was another Oblivion Ring, casting a third Oblivion Ring will result in an involuntary infinite loop that will end the game in a draw (unless someone chooses to break it by putting another nonland permanent onto the battlefield or destroying one of the Oblivion Rings, for example). <br>10/1/2008 : If the exiled card is an Aura, that card's owner chooses what it will enchant as it comes back onto the battlefield. An Aura put onto the battlefield this way doesn't target anything, but the Aura's enchant ability restricts what it can be attached to. If the Aura can't legally be attached to anything, it remains exiled forever. <br>7/1/2012 : Auras attached to the exiled permanent will be put into their owners' graveyards. Equipment attached to the exiled permanent will become unattached and remain on the battlefield. Any counters on the exiled permanent will cease to exist.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220072]]></id><name><![CDATA[Onyx Mage]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}{B}: Target creature you control gains deathtouch until end of turn. (Any amount of damage it deals to a creature is enough to destroy it.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["We wield death and darkness, powers that make lesser mages tremble in fear."<br>—Onyx creed]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Izzy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[103]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : Multiple instances of deathtouch on the same creature provide no additional benefit. A creature dealt damage by a creature with multiple instances of deathtouch is destroyed only once.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[238574]]></id><name><![CDATA[Overrun]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Creatures you control get +3/+3 and gain trample until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Carl Critchlow]]></artist><number><![CDATA[186]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : Overrun affects only creatures you control at the time it resolves. It won't affect creatures that come under your control later in the turn.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[228956]]></id><name><![CDATA[Pacifism]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature can't attack or block.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[For the first time in his life, Grakk felt a little warm and fuzzy inside.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Robert Bliss]]></artist><number><![CDATA[28]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244251]]></id><name><![CDATA[Pentavus]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Construct]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{7}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[0]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Pentavus enters the battlefield with five +1/+1 counters on it.<br>{1}, Remove a +1/+1 counter from Pentavus: Put a 1/1 colorless Pentavite artifact creature token with flying onto the battlefield.<br>{1}, Sacrifice a Pentavite: Put a +1/+1 counter on Pentavus.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Greg Staples]]></artist><number><![CDATA[213]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : You can remove any +1/+1 counter on Pentavus to activate its first activated ability, not just ones created by Pentavus's other abilities. <br>9/22/2011 : You can sacrifice any Pentavite creature you control (such as an Adaptive Automaton with Pentavite as its chosen type) to activate Pentavus's second activated ability, not just ones created by Pentavus's other abilities.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[238327]]></id><name><![CDATA[Peregrine Griffin]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Griffin]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>First strike (This creature deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[A griffin is not just an eagle's wings and a lion's claws. It is also the fiercest of hearts.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Prescott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[29]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220235]]></id><name><![CDATA[Personal Sanctuary]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[During your turn, prevent all damage that would be dealt to you.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["There is a place deep within my soul where no foe can intrude and no tyrant can conquer."<br>—Sarlena, paladin of the Northern Verge]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Howard Lyon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[30]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220251]]></id><name><![CDATA[Phantasmal Bear]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Bear Illusion]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Phantasmal Bear becomes the target of a spell or ability, sacrifice it.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["You know it to be false, but when its claws find you, what you know won't matter much at all."<br>—Pol Jamaar, illusionist]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ryan Yee]]></artist><number><![CDATA[70]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220068]]></id><name><![CDATA[Phantasmal Dragon]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Dragon Illusion]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>When Phantasmal Dragon becomes the target of a spell or ability, sacrifice it.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Its hunger and ire are no less for being wrought of lies and mist.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Wayne Reynolds]]></artist><number><![CDATA[71]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220099]]></id><name><![CDATA[Phantasmal Image]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Illusion]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[0]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[You may have Phantasmal Image enter the battlefield as a copy of any creature on the battlefield, except it's an Illusion in addition to its other types and it gains "When this creature becomes the target of a spell or ability, sacrifice it."]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Nils Hamm]]></artist><number><![CDATA[72]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : Phantasmal Image's ability doesn't target the chosen creature. <br>9/22/2011 : Phantasmal Image copies exactly what was printed on the original creature and nothing more (unless that creature is copying something else or is a token; see below). It doesn't copy whether that creature is tapped or untapped, whether it has any counters on it or Auras attached to it, or any non-copy effects that have changed its power, toughness, types, color, or so on. <br>9/22/2011 : If the chosen creature has {X} in its mana cost (such as Primordial Hydra), X is considered to be zero. <br>9/22/2011 : If the chosen creature is copying something else (for example, if the chosen creature is another Phantasmal Image), then Phantasmal Image enters the battlefield as whatever the chosen creature copied. <br>9/22/2011 : If the chosen creature is a token, Phantasmal Image copies the original characteristics of that token as stated by the effect that put the token onto the battlefield. Phantasmal Image is not a token. <br>9/22/2011 : Any enters-the-battlefield abilities of the copied creature will trigger when Phantasmal Image enters the battlefield. Any "as [this creature] enters the battlefield" or "[this creature] enters the battlefield with" abilities of the chosen creature will also work. <br>9/22/2011 : If Phantasmal Image somehow enters the battlefield at the same time as another creature, Phantasmal Image can't become a copy of that creature. You may only choose a creature that's already on the battlefield. <br>9/22/2011 : You can choose not to copy anything. In that case, Phantasmal Image enters the battlefield as a 0/0 Illusion creature, and is probably put into the graveyard immediately. It doesn't have the ability "When this creature becomes the target of a spell or ability, sacrifice it."]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244331]]></id><name><![CDATA[Plains]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Plains]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{W}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[D. J. Cleland-Hura]]></artist><number><![CDATA[231]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[233235]]></id><name><![CDATA[Plummet]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Destroy target creature with flying.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Let nothing own the skies but the wind."<br>—Dejara, Giltwood druid]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Pete Venters]]></artist><number><![CDATA[187]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244313]]></id><name><![CDATA[Ponder]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Look at the top three cards of your library, then put them back in any order. You may shuffle your library.<br>Draw a card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Tomorrow belongs to those who prepare for it today.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dan Scott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[73]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2007 : If you choose to shuffle your library, that includes the three cards you just looked at and put back on top of it.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220073]]></id><name><![CDATA[Pride Guardian]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Cat Monk]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Defender (This creature can't attack.)<br>Whenever Pride Guardian blocks, you gain 3 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Any hotheaded cub can raise a sword in anger."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chris Rahn]]></artist><number><![CDATA[31]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If Pride Guardian gains the ability to block additional creatures and does so, you'll still gain only 3 life.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[241832]]></id><name><![CDATA[Primeval Titan]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Giant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample<br>Whenever Primeval Titan enters the battlefield or attacks, you may search your library for up to two land cards, put them onto the battlefield tapped, then shuffle your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[When nature calls, run.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Aleksi Briclot]]></artist><number><![CDATA[188]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : You may find any land cards, not just basic land cards.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220172]]></id><name><![CDATA[Primordial Hydra]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Hydra]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{X}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[0]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Primordial Hydra enters the battlefield with X +1/+1 counters on it.<br>At the beginning of your upkeep, double the number of +1/+1 counters on Primordial Hydra.<br>Primordial Hydra has trample as long as it has ten or more +1/+1 counters on it.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Aleksi Briclot]]></artist><number><![CDATA[189]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : Consider only the number of +1/+1 counters on Primordial Hydra when determining if it has trample, not its power and toughness. For example, a Primordial Hydra with six +1/+1 counters on it that's been the target of Titanic Growth (giving it +4/+4) would not have trample.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[237006]]></id><name><![CDATA[Quicksilver Amulet]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{4}, {T}: You may put a creature card from your hand onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Those who examine the amulet too closely have been known to become part of its ornate carvings.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Brad Rigney]]></artist><number><![CDATA[214]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/4/2004 : Any 'X' in the creature's cost is treated as zero.  <br>5/1/2007 : Putting the card onto the battlefield is optional.  When the ability resolves, you can choose not to. <br>4/1/2008 : A "creature card" is any card with the type Creature, even if it has other types such as Artifact, Enchantment, or Land. Older cards of type Summon are also Creature cards.  <br>9/22/2011 : You don't pay any costs of that creature card, including additional costs.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[233231]]></id><name><![CDATA[Rampant Growth]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Search your library for a basic land card and put that card onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Nature grows solutions to its problems.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steven Belledin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[190]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/4/2004 : The land does not count toward your one per turn limit because it was put onto the battlefield by an effect.  <br>10/4/2004 : Because the "search" requires you to find a card with certain characteristics, you don't have to find the card if you don't want to.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[226565]]></id><name><![CDATA[Reassembling Skeleton]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Skeleton Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}{B}: Return Reassembling Skeleton from your graveyard to the battlefield tapped.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["They may show up with the wrong thigh bone or mandible, but they always show up."<br>—Zul Ashur, lich lord]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Austin Hsu]]></artist><number><![CDATA[104]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[226903]]></id><name><![CDATA[Reclaim]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Put target card from your graveyard on top of your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The wise pay as much attention to what they throw away as to what they keep.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Andrew Robinson]]></artist><number><![CDATA[191]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221484]]></id><name><![CDATA[Redirect]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[You may choose new targets for target spell.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["It's actually quite simple, but since you've only recently begun to walk upright, it may take some time to explain."<br>—Jace Beleren, to Garruk Wildspeaker]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Izzy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[74]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : You may change any number of the targets, including all of them or none of them. If, for one of the targets, you can't choose a new legal target, then it remains unchanged (even if the current target is illegal). <br>8/15/2010 : If the targeted spell is modal (that is, it says "Choose one --" or the like), you can't choose a different mode. <br>8/15/2010 : If you cast Redirect targeting a spell that targets a spell on the stack (like Cancel does, for example), you can't change that spell's target to itself. You can, however, change that spell's target to Redirect. If you do, that spell will be countered when it tries to resolve because Redirect will have left the stack by then. <br>8/15/2010 : Redirect can target any spell, not just an instant or sorcery spell. For example, you could use it to change the target of an Aura spell. However, if the targeted spell has no targets (for example, if it's an instant or sorcery spell that doesn't specifically use the word "target," or if it's a creature spell), Redirect won't have any effect on it.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[233722]]></id><name><![CDATA[Reverberate]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Copy target instant or sorcery spell. You may choose new targets for the copy.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[For every action, there is a swifter and more violent reaction.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[jD]]></artist><number><![CDATA[152]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : Reverberate can target (and copy) any instant or sorcery spell, not just one with targets. It doesn't matter who controls it. <br>8/15/2010 : When Reverberate resolves, it creates a copy of a spell. You control the copy. That copy is created on the stack, so it's not "cast." Abilities that trigger when a player casts a spell won't trigger. The copy will then resolve like a normal spell, after players get a chance to cast spells and activate abilities. <br>8/15/2010 : The copy will have the same targets as the spell it's copying unless you choose new ones. You may change any number of the targets, including all of them or none of them. If, for one of the targets, you can't choose a new legal target, then it remains unchanged (even if the current target is illegal). <br>8/15/2010 : If the spell Reverberate copies is modal (that is, it says "Choose one --" or the like), the copy will have the same mode. You can't choose a different one. <br>8/15/2010 : If the spell Reverberate copies has an X whose value was determined as it was cast (like Earthquake does), the copy has the same value of X. <br>8/15/2010 : You can't choose to pay any additional costs for the copy. However, effects based on any additional costs that were paid for the original spell are copied as though those same costs were paid for the copy too. For example, if a player sacrifices a 3/3 creature to cast Fling, and you copy it with Reverberate, the copy of Fling will also deal 3 damage to its target. <br>8/15/2010 : If the copy says that it affects "you," it affects the controller of the copy, not the controller of the original spell. Similarly, if the copy says that it affects an "opponent," it affects an opponent of the copy's controller, not an opponent of the original spell's controller.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[235188]]></id><name><![CDATA[Rites of Flourishing]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[At the beginning of each player's draw step, that player draws an additional card.<br>Each player may play an additional land on each of his or her turns.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Dance, and bring forth the coil! It is an umbilical to Gaea herself, fattening us with the earth's rich bounty."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Brandon Kitkouski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[192]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>4/15/2013 : The triggered ability is put onto the stack after you have already drawn your card for the turn.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[238570]]></id><name><![CDATA[Roc Egg]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Bird]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Defender (This creature can't attack.)<br>When Roc Egg dies, put a 3/3 white Bird creature token with flying onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[A thin shell lies between the roc and a world of bite-sized treats.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Paul Bonner]]></artist><number><![CDATA[32]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221922]]></id><name><![CDATA[Rootbound Crag]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Rootbound Crag enters the battlefield tapped unless you control a Mountain or a Forest.<br>{T}: Add {R} or {G} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Matt Stewart]]></artist><number><![CDATA[228]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : This checks for lands you control with the land type Mountain or Forest, not for lands named Mountain or Forest. The lands it checks for don't have to be basic lands. For example, if you control Temple Garden (a nonbasic land with the land types Forest and Plains), Rootbound Crag will enter the battlefield untapped. <br>10/1/2009 : As This is entering the battlefield, it checks for lands that are already on the battlefield. It won't see lands that are entering the battlefield at the same time (due to Warp World, for example).]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[236464]]></id><name><![CDATA[Royal Assassin]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Assassin]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Destroy target tapped creature.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[An assassin is a king's most trusted courier, ensuring his messages are heard by even the most unwilling recipients.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mark Zug]]></artist><number><![CDATA[105]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/4/2004 : Can't target itself because you choose the target before you tap him. At that time he is not yet a legal target.  <br>10/4/2004 : If the creature is no longer tapped when the Assassin's ability resolves, then the ability is countered. ]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221893]]></id><name><![CDATA[Runeclaw Bear]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Bear]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The only honey it wants is the sweet nectar flowing through your veins.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jesper Ejsing]]></artist><number><![CDATA[193]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220130]]></id><name><![CDATA[Rune-Scarred Demon]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Demon]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>When Rune-Scarred Demon enters the battlefield, search your library for a card, put it into your hand, then shuffle your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The litany of the infernal on his flesh pulses to the beating of his dark heart.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Michael Komarck]]></artist><number><![CDATA[106]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220241]]></id><name><![CDATA[Rusted Sentinel]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Golem]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Rusted Sentinel enters the battlefield tapped.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It has to deliberate a moment on the best way to break your face.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jason Felix]]></artist><number><![CDATA[215]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[241859]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sacred Wolf]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Wolf]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Hexproof (This creature can't be the target of spells or abilities your opponents control.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["I raised my bow, and the wolf stared at me. Under its gaze, my finger would not release the string."<br>—Aref the Hunter]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Matt Stewart]]></artist><number><![CDATA[194]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220209]]></id><name><![CDATA[Scepter of Empires]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Scepter of Empires deals 1 damage to target player. It deals 3 damage to that player instead if you control artifacts named Crown of Empires and Throne of Empires.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["With this scepter, smite your enemies."<br>—Scepter inscription]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[John Avon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[216]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : Whether or not you control the correct artifacts is determined when the ability resolves. <br>9/22/2011 : If any of the named cards stops being an artifact, it won't be considered by these abilities.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220300]]></id><name><![CDATA[Scrambleverse]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{6}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[8]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[For each nonland permanent, choose a player at random. Then each player gains control of each permanent for which he or she was chosen. Untap those permanents.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Sometimes a little chaos is in order.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dan Scott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[153]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : Once Scrambleverse starts to resolve, no player may respond until it has finished resolving. For example, you can't wait to see who will control a creature before deciding whether or not to activate one of its abilities. <br>9/22/2011 : For each nonland permanent, any player may be randomly chosen, including the permanent's current controller. <br>9/22/2011 : All of the control-change effects happen at the same time. <br>9/22/2011 : Each nonland permanent will untap, no matter which player was randomly chosen to gain control of it.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244253]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sengir Vampire]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Vampire]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Whenever a creature dealt damage by Sengir Vampire this turn dies, put a +1/+1 counter on Sengir Vampire.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Empires rise and fall, but evil is eternal.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kev Walker]]></artist><number><![CDATA[107]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>7/15/2007 : If Sengir Vampire deals nonlethal damage to a creature and then a different effect or damage source causes that creature to be put into a graveyard later in the turn, Sengir Vampire's ability will trigger and it will get a +1/+1 counter. <br>9/22/2011 : Each time a creature is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, check whether Sengir Vampire had dealt any damage to it at any time during that turn. If so, Sengir Vampire's ability will trigger. It doesn't matter who controlled the creature or whose graveyard it was put into. <br>9/22/2011 : If Sengir Vampire and a creature it dealt damage to are both put into a graveyard at the same time, Sengir Vampire's ability will trigger, but it will do nothing when it resolves.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220176]]></id><name><![CDATA[Serra Angel]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Angel]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Vigilance (Attacking doesn't cause this creature to tap.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Follow the light. In its absence, follow her.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Greg Staples]]></artist><number><![CDATA[33]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[245184]]></id><name><![CDATA[Shock]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Shock deals 2 damage to target creature or player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The beauty of it is they never see it coming. Ever."<br>—Razzix, sparkmage]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jon Foster]]></artist><number><![CDATA[154]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[222635]]></id><name><![CDATA[Siege Mastodon]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elephant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The walls of the wicked will fall before us. Ready the siege engines. We proceed to war!"<br>—General Avitora]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Matt Cavotta]]></artist><number><![CDATA[34]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220151]]></id><name><![CDATA[Skinshifter]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{G}: Choose one — Until end of turn, Skinshifter becomes a 4/4 Rhino and gains trample; or until end of turn, Skinshifter becomes a 2/2 Bird and gains flying; or until end of turn, Skinshifter becomes a 0/8 Plant. Activate this ability only once each turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Matt Stewart]]></artist><number><![CDATA[195]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : You choose the ability's mode when you activate it. <br>9/22/2011 : No matter which mode you choose, Skinshifter will cease to have any creature types it previously had. If you activate its ability choosing the first mode, it will become only a Rhino; it's no longer a Human or a Shaman. <br>9/22/2011 : No matter which mode you choose, Skinshifter will retain any other card types it may have. For example, if an effect causes Skinshifter to be an artifact in addition to its other types and you activate its ability choosing the first mode, it will be both an artifact and a Rhino creature. <br>9/22/2011 : Skinshifter's ability doesn't cause it to lose any other abilities it may have. <br>9/22/2011 : Skinshifter's ability doesn't affect its copiable values. Creatures that enter the battlefield as a copy of Skinshifter will enter as 1/1 Human Shaman creatures. <br>9/22/2011 : You can activate Skinshifter's ability during any player's turn, but only once on each turn.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220153]]></id><name><![CDATA[Skywinder Drake]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Drake]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Skywinder Drake can block only creatures with flying.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It's so light and fragile that it can glide where the air is thinnest.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dan Scott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[75]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[230762]]></id><name><![CDATA[Slaughter Cry]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target creature gets +3/+0 and gains first strike until end of turn. (It deals combat damage before creatures without first strike.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It's rather embarrassing to end up with your head mounted over his hearth.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Matt Cavotta]]></artist><number><![CDATA[155]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : If a creature doesn't have first strike, granting it first strike after combat damage has been dealt in the first combat damage step won't prevent it from dealing combat damage. It will still assign and deal its combat damage in the second combat damage step.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[237010]]></id><name><![CDATA[Smallpox]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Each player loses 1 life, discards a card, sacrifices a creature, then sacrifices a land.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Take away a few things, and a rebellion may ensue. Take away everything, and the oppression will be accepted as fate.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ryan Pancoast]]></artist><number><![CDATA[108]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/25/2006 : Each player loses 1 life. Then, starting with the active player and proceeding in turn order, each player chooses a card to discard (normally without seeing what other players have chosen) and all discards happen simultaneously. Then, starting with the active player and proceeding in turn order, each player chooses a creature to sacrifice (this time players can see what other players have chosen) and all sacrifices happen simultaneously. Then the process that happened for creatures is repeated for lands.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[236907]]></id><name><![CDATA[Solemn Simulacrum]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Golem]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Solemn Simulacrum enters the battlefield, you may search your library for a basic land card, put that card onto the battlefield tapped, then shuffle your library.<br>When Solemn Simulacrum dies, you may draw a card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dan Scott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[217]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[238330]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sorin Markov]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Planeswalker — Sorin]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{B}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[4]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[+2: Sorin Markov deals 2 damage to target creature or player and you gain 2 life.<br>-3: Target opponent's life total becomes 10.<br>-7: You control target player during that player's next turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Michael Komarck]]></artist><number><![CDATA[109]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : If the targeted creature or player is an illegal target by the time Sorin's first ability resolves, the entire ability is countered. You won't gain life. <br>10/1/2009 : For a player's life total to become 10, what actually happens is that the player gains or loses the appropriate amount of life. For example, if the targeted opponent's life total is 4 when this ability resolves, it will cause that player to gain 6 life; alternately, if the targeted player's life total is 17 when this ability resolves, it will cause that player to lose 7 life. Other cards that interact with life gain or life loss will interact with this effect accordingly. <br>10/1/2009 : Sorin's third ability allows you to control another player. This effect applies to the next turn that the affected player actually takes. <br>10/1/2009 : The player who is being controlled is still the active player. <br>10/1/2009 : While controlling another player, you also continue to make your own choices and decisions. <br>10/1/2009 : While controlling another player, you make all choices and decisions that player is allowed to make or is told to make during that turn. For example:-- You choose which lands the other player plays.-- You choose which spells the other player casts, and make all decisions as those spells are cast and as they resolve. For example, you choose the value of X for that player's Earthquake, the target for that player's Lightning Bolt, what mana that player spends to cast Day of Judgment, and what card that player gets with Diabolic Tutor.-- You choose which activated abilities the other player activates, and make all decisions as those abilities are activated and as they resolve. For example, you can have your opponent sacrifice his or her creatures to his or her Vampire Aristocrat or have your opponent's Caller of Gales give one of your creatures flying.-- You make all decisions for the other player's triggered abilities, including what they target and any decisions made when they resolve.-- You choose which creatures controlled by the other player attack, who or what they attack, and how they assign their combat damage.-- You make any choices and decisions that player would make for any other reason. For example, you could cast Fact or Fiction, choose that player to divide the revealed cards into piles, and thus divide those cards into piles yourself. <br>10/1/2009 : You can't make the affected player concede. That player may choose to concede at any time, even while you're controlling his or her turn. <br>10/1/2009 : You can't make any illegal decisions or illegal choices -- you can't do anything that player couldn't do. You can't make choices or decisions for that player that aren't called for by the game rules or by any cards, permanents, spells, abilities, and so on. If an effect causes another player to make decisions that the affected player would normally make (such as Master Warcraft does), that effect takes precedence. (In other words, if the affected player wouldn't make a decision, you wouldn't make that decision on his or her behalf.) You also can't make any choices or decisions for the player that would be called for by the tournament rules (such as whether to take an intentional draw or whether to call a judge). <br>10/1/2009 : You can use only the affected player's resources (cards, mana, and so on) to pay costs for that player; you can't use your own. Similarly, you can use the affected player's resources only to pay that player's costs; you can't spend them on your costs. <br>10/1/2009 : You only control the player. You don't control any of the other player's permanents, spells, or abilities. <br>10/1/2009 : If the player affected by Sorin's third ability skips his or her next turn, the ability will wait. You'll control the next turn the affected player actually takes. <br>10/1/2009 : Multiple player-controlling effects that affect the same player overwrite each other. The last one to be created is the one that works. <br>10/1/2009 : You could gain control of yourself using Sorin's third ability, but unless you do so to overwrite someone else's player-controlling effect, this doesn't do anything. <br>6/15/2010 : In a Two-Headed Giant game, Sorin's second ability causes the targeted opponent's team's life-total to become 10. Only the targeted player is actually considered to have actually gained or lost life. <br>7/1/2012 : While controlling another player, you can see all cards that player can see. This includes cards in that player's hand, face-down cards that player controls, his or her sideboard, and any cards in his or her library that he or she looks at.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[241994]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sorin's Thirst]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Sorin's Thirst deals 2 damage to target creature and you gain 2 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["All your steel won't protect you if your will is weak."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Karl Kopinski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[110]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If the creature is an illegal target when Sorin's Thirst tries to resolve, Sorin's Thirst will be countered and none of its effects will happen. You won't gain life.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[234436]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sorin's Vengeance]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{B}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Sorin's Vengeance deals 10 damage to target player and you gain 10 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Cherish these last moments. Though your miserable life has come to nothing, I have given it a magnificent end."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jana Schirmer & Johannes Voss]]></artist><number><![CDATA[111]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If the player is an illegal target when Sorin's Vengeance tries to resolve, Sorin's Vengeance will be countered and none of its effects will happen. You won't gain life.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220090]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sphinx of Uthuun]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Sphinx]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>When Sphinx of Uthuun enters the battlefield, reveal the top five cards of your library. An opponent separates those cards into two piles. Put one pile into your hand and the other into your graveyard.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kekai Kotaki]]></artist><number><![CDATA[76]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : You (not your opponent) choose which pile to put into your hand and which to put into your graveyard. <br>9/22/2011 : A pile can have no cards in it. In this case, you'll choose whether to put all the revealed cards into your hand or into your graveyard. <br>9/22/2011 : If your library has fewer than five cards, you reveal all the cards in it, then your opponent separates them into two piles. <br>9/22/2011 : In multiplayer games, you choose an opponent to separate the cards when the ability resolves. This doesn't target that opponent. Because the cards are revealed, all players may see the cards and offer opinions.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220154]]></id><name><![CDATA[Spirit Mantle]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 and has protection from creatures.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The shield of unimpeachable purity is as strong as any wrought on the anvil.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Izzy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[35]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244825]]></id><name><![CDATA[Stampeding Rhino]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Rhino]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample (If this creature would assign enough damage to its blockers to destroy them, you may have it assign the rest of its damage to defending player or planeswalker.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The quickest way to get through the jungle is to agitate a rhino and run in its wake.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steven Belledin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[196]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220295]]></id><name><![CDATA[Stave Off]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target creature gains protection from the color of your choice until end of turn. (It can't be blocked, targeted, dealt damage, or enchanted by anything of that color.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mark Zug]]></artist><number><![CDATA[36]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : You choose the target as part of casting the spell. You choose what color the target gains protection from when the spell resolves.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220075]]></id><name><![CDATA[Stingerfling Spider]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Spider]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Reach (This creature can block creatures with flying.)<br>When Stingerfling Spider enters the battlefield, you may destroy target creature with flying.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The juiciest prey is that which grows lazy, thinking itself beyond the reach of danger.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Allsop]]></artist><number><![CDATA[197]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : You choose the target creature with flying when the ability goes on the stack. When it resolves, you choose whether or not to destroy the creature.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220160]]></id><name><![CDATA[Stonehorn Dignitary]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Rhino Soldier]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Stonehorn Dignitary enters the battlefield, target opponent skips his or her next combat phase.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It did not escape the ambassador's notice that the sound of war drums could also marshal the city to attention.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Kendall]]></artist><number><![CDATA[37]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If more than one Stonehorn Dignitary enters the battlefield during the same turn, and you target the same opponent with each ability, that opponent will skip that many combat phases (over multiple turns if necessary). <br>9/22/2011 : In a Two-Headed Giant game, the targeted opponent's team skips its next combat phase.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220277]]></id><name><![CDATA[Stormblood Berserker]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Berserker]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Bloodthirst 2 (If an opponent was dealt damage this turn, this creature enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it.)<br>Stormblood Berserker can't be blocked except by two or more creatures.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Blood is holy to those whose god is War.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Min Yum]]></artist><number><![CDATA[156]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[222633]]></id><name><![CDATA[Stormfront Pegasus]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Pegasus]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Its hooves touch the earth only when a hero must rise.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[rk post]]></artist><number><![CDATA[38]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[241833]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sun Titan]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Giant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Vigilance<br>Whenever Sun Titan enters the battlefield or attacks, you may return target permanent card with converted mana cost 3 or less from your graveyard to the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[A blazing sun that never sets.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Todd Lockwood]]></artist><number><![CDATA[39]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : A permanent card is an artifact, creature, enchantment, land, or planeswalker card. <br>8/15/2010 : The converted mana cost of a card in your graveyard is determined solely by the mana symbols printed in its upper right corner. The converted mana cost is the total amount of mana in that cost, regardless of color. For example, a card with mana cost {3}{U}{U} has converted mana cost 5. <br>8/15/2010 : If the mana cost of a card in your graveyard includes {X}, X is considered to be 0. <br>8/15/2010 : If a card in your graveyard has no mana symbols in its upper right corner (because it's a land card, for example), its converted mana cost is 0.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[228118]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sundial of the Infinite]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}, {T}: End the turn. Activate this ability only during your turn. (Exile all spells and abilities on the stack. Discard down to your maximum hand size. Damage wears off, and "this turn" and "until end of turn" effects end.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Vincent Proce]]></artist><number><![CDATA[218]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : Ending the turn this way means the following things happen in order:1) All spells and abilities on the stack are exiled. This includes spells and abilities that can't be countered.2) All attacking and blocking creatures are removed from combat.3) State-based actions are checked. No player gets priority, and no triggered abilities are put onto the stack.4) The current phase and/or step ends. The game skips straight to the cleanup step. The cleanup step happens in its entirety. <br>9/22/2011 : If any triggered abilities do trigger during this process, they're put onto the stack during the cleanup step. If this happens, players will have a chance to cast spells and activate abilities, then there will be another cleanup step before the turn finally ends. <br>9/22/2011 : Though spells and abilities that are exiled won't get a chance to resolve, they don't count as being "countered." <br>9/22/2011 : If Sundial of the Infinite's ability is activated before the end step, any "at the beginning of the end step"-triggered abilities won't get the chance to trigger that turn because the end step is skipped. Those abilities will trigger at the beginning of the end step of the next turn. The same is true of abilities that trigger at the beginning of other phases or steps (except upkeep). <br>9/22/2011 : The earliest that you can activate Sundial of the Infinite's ability is during your upkeep step, after abilities that trigger "at the beginning of your upkeep" have been put onto the stack but before they resolve.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221923]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sunpetal Grove]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Sunpetal Grove enters the battlefield tapped unless you control a Forest or a Plains.<br>{T}: Add {G} or {W} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jason Chan]]></artist><number><![CDATA[229]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : This checks for lands you control with the land type Forest or Plains, not for lands named Forest or Plains. The lands it checks for don't have to be basic lands. For example, if you control Hallowed Fountain (a nonbasic land with the land types Plains and Island), Sunpetal Grove will enter the battlefield untapped. <br>10/1/2009 : As This is entering the battlefield, it checks for lands that are already on the battlefield. It won't see lands that are entering the battlefield at the same time (due to Warp World, for example).]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220157]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sutured Ghoul]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Zombie]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{B}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[*]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[*]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample<br>As Sutured Ghoul enters the battlefield, exile any number of creature cards from your graveyard.<br>Sutured Ghoul's power is equal to the total power of the exiled cards and its toughness is equal to their total toughness.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Carl Critchlow]]></artist><number><![CDATA[112]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If any of the creature cards you exile has a characteristic-defining ability that defines its power and/or toughness, that ability will apply. For example, if Dungrove Elder is exiled this way, its power and toughness while it's in exile are equal to the number of Forests you control, and Sutured Ghoul's power and toughness will change as the number of Forests you control changes. If the characteristic-defining ability can't be applied (for instance, it relies on a choice made as the card enters the battlefield), then use 0. <br>9/22/2011 : In zones other than the battlefield, Sutured Ghoul's power and toughness are each 0. <br>9/22/2011 : You can't have Sutured Ghoul exile itself, even if it's entering the battlefield from your graveyard.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244337]]></id><name><![CDATA[Swamp]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Swamp]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{B}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chippy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[239]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220261]]></id><name><![CDATA[Swiftfoot Boots]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact — Equipment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Equipped creature has hexproof and haste. (It can't be the target of spells or abilities your opponents control, and it can attack and {T} as soon as it comes under your control.)<br>Equip {1} ({1}: Attach to target creature you control. Equip only as a sorcery.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Svetlin Velinov]]></artist><number><![CDATA[219]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If an opponent gains control of a creature equipped by your Swiftfoot Boots, that creature can't be the target of spells and abilities you control.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[226561]]></id><name><![CDATA[Taste of Blood]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Taste of Blood deals 1 damage to target player and you gain 1 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["How blessed are some people, whose lives have no fears, no dreads, to whom sleep is a blessing that comes nightly, and brings nothing but sweet dreams."<br>—Bram Stoker, Dracula]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Howard Lyon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[113]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If the player is an illegal target when Taste of Blood tries to resolve, Taste of Blood will be countered and none of its effects will happen. You won't gain life.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[234568]]></id><name><![CDATA[Tectonic Rift]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Destroy target land. Creatures without flying can't block this turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["You will kneel before me, even if I have to split the earth under your feet!"<br>—Ash Kronor, Keldon warlord]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[John Avon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[157]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : If the land is an illegal target when Tectonic Rift tries to resolve, Tectonic Rift will be countered and none of its effects will happen. Creatures without flying will be able to block as normal. <br>9/22/2011 : The set of affected creatures isn't locked in when Tectonic Rift resolves. Creatures without flying that enter the battlefield later that turn or creatures that lose flying later that turn won't be able to block.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[234072]]></id><name><![CDATA[Thran Golem]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Golem]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[As long as Thran Golem is enchanted, it gets +2/+2 and has flying, first strike, and trample.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The golems of the ancient Thran still draw power in ways that baffle the artificers of today.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ron Spears]]></artist><number><![CDATA[220]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220232]]></id><name><![CDATA[Throne of Empires]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}, {T}: Put a 1/1 white Soldier creature token onto the battlefield. Put five of those tokens onto the battlefield instead if you control artifacts named Crown of Empires and Scepter of Empires.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["With this throne, unite your nation."<br>—Throne inscription]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[John Avon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[221]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : Whether or not you control the correct artifacts is determined when the ability resolves. <br>9/22/2011 : If any of the named cards stops being an artifact, it won't be considered by these abilities.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[245187]]></id><name><![CDATA[Time Reversal]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Each player shuffles his or her hand and graveyard into his or her library, then draws seven cards. Exile Time Reversal.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Any oaf can conquer a kingdom. It takes true power to conquer time."<br>—Shai Fusan, archmage]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Howard Lyon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[77]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220074]]></id><name><![CDATA[Timely Reinforcements]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[If you have less life than an opponent, you gain 6 life. If you control fewer creatures than an opponent, put three 1/1 white Soldier creature tokens onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The gods are not always kind, but they do have a soft spot for plucky underdogs.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Tomasz Jedruszek]]></artist><number><![CDATA[40]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : You compare life totals with each of your opponents when Timely Reinforcements resolves. At that time, if you have less life than an opponent, you'll gain 6 life. Similarly, you compare the number of creatures you control with the number of creatures each opponent controls when Timely Reinforcements resolves. <br>9/22/2011 : In a multiplayer game, you consider each opponent. If you have less life than one of your opponents and fewer creatures than one of your opponents (although this may be a different opponent), you'll get both bonuses. <br>9/22/2011 : In a Two-Headed Giant game, you'll compare your team's life total with the opposing team's life total. You'll then compare the number of creatures you control (ignoring creatures your teammate controls) to the number of creatures each opponent controls separately.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221203]]></id><name><![CDATA[Titanic Growth]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target creature gets +4/+4 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The pup looked over the treetops, eyeing the man who just yesterday had kicked her. Suddenly, her hunger was infused with pure delight.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ryan Pancoast]]></artist><number><![CDATA[198]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220122]]></id><name><![CDATA[Tormented Soul]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Spirit]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Tormented Soul can't block and is unblockable.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Those who raged most bitterly at the world in life are cursed to roam the nether realms in death.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Karl Kopinski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[114]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220190]]></id><name><![CDATA[Trollhide]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature gets +2/+2 and has "{1}{G}: Regenerate this creature." (The next time the creature would be destroyed this turn, it isn't. Instead tap it, remove all damage from it, and remove it from combat.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steven Belledin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[199]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : Activating the ability granted to the enchanted creature causes a "regeneration shield" to be created for it. The next time that creature would be destroyed that turn, the regeneration shield is used up instead. This works only if the creature is dealt lethal damage, dealt damage from a source with deathtouch, or affected by a spell or ability that says to "destroy" it. Other effects that cause the creature to be put into the graveyard (such as reducing its toughness to 0 or sacrificing it) don't destroy it, so regeneration won't save it. If it hasn't been used, the regeneration shield goes away as the turn ends. <br>9/22/2011 : To work, the regeneration shield must be created before the enchanted creature is destroyed. This usually means activating its ability during the declare blockers step, or in response to a spell or ability that would destroy it. <br>9/22/2011 : If the enchanted creature is dealt lethal damage and is dealt damage by a source with deathtouch during the same combat damage step, a single regeneration shield will save it.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220265]]></id><name><![CDATA[Turn to Frog]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target creature loses all abilities and becomes a 1/1 blue Frog until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Ribbit."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Warren Mahy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[78]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : The creature will lose all other colors and creature types, but it will retain any other card types (such as artifact) it may have. <br>9/22/2011 : Turn to Frog overwrites all previous effects that set the targeted creature's power and toughness to specific values. Other effects that set its power or toughness to specific values that start to apply after Turn to Frog resolves will overwrite this effect. <br>9/22/2011 : Turn to Frog doesn't counter abilities that have already triggered or been activated. In particular, there is no way to cast this to stop a creature's "At the beginning of your upkeep" or "When this creature enters the battlefield" abilities from triggering. <br>9/22/2011 : If the affected creature gains an ability after Turn to Frog resolves, it will keep that ability. <br>1/22/2011 : Effects that modify the targeted creature's power or toughness, such as the effects of Titanic Growth or Glorious Anthem, will apply to it no matter when they started to take effect. The same is true for counters that change the creature's power or toughness (such as +1/+1 counters) and effects that switch its power and toughness.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220301]]></id><name><![CDATA[Unsummon]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Return target creature to its owner's hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["It's nothing personal. I'd just prefer if you weren't."<br>—Ashurel, voidmage]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Izzy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[79]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220127]]></id><name><![CDATA[Vampire Outcasts]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Vampire]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Bloodthirst 2 (If an opponent was dealt damage this turn, this creature enters the battlefield with two +1/+1 counters on it.)<br>Lifelink (Damage dealt by this creature also causes you to gain that much life.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Clint Cearley]]></artist><number><![CDATA[115]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244827]]></id><name><![CDATA[Vastwood Gorger]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Wurm]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The gorger's insect-like eyes pick up the slightest movement in any direction. Its body then whips toward its prey with startling speed, swallowing it in one engulfing gulp.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kieran Yanner]]></artist><number><![CDATA[200]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220170]]></id><name><![CDATA[Vengeful Pharaoh]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Zombie]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{B}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Deathtouch (Any amount of damage this deals to a creature is enough to destroy it.)<br>Whenever combat damage is dealt to you or a planeswalker you control, if Vengeful Pharaoh is in your graveyard, destroy target attacking creature, then put Vengeful Pharaoh on top of your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Igor Kieryluk]]></artist><number><![CDATA[116]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : Vengeful Pharaoh must be in your graveyard when combat damage is dealt to you or a planeswalker you control in order for its ability to trigger. That is, it can't die and trigger from your graveyard during the same combat damage step. <br>9/22/2011 : If Vengeful Pharaoh is no longer in your graveyard when the triggered ability would resolve, the triggered ability won't do anything. <br>9/22/2011 : If the attacking creature is an illegal target when the triggered ability tries to resolve, it will be countered and none of its effects will happen. Vengeful Pharaoh will remain in your graveyard. <br>9/22/2011 : If multiple creatures deal combat damage to you simultaneously, Vengeful Pharaoh will only trigger once. <br>9/22/2011 : If multiple creatures deal combat damage to you and to a planeswalker you control simultaneously, Vengeful Pharaoh will trigger twice. The first trigger will cause Vengeful Pharaoh to be put on top of your library. The second trigger will then do nothing, as Vengeful Pharaoh is no longer in your graveyard when it tries to resolve. Note that the second trigger will do nothing even if Vengeful Pharaoh is put back into your graveyard before it tries to resolve, as it's a different Vengeful Pharaoh than the one that was there before. <br>9/22/2011 : If your own attacking creatures deal combat damage to you or a planeswalker you control (perhaps because combat damage was redirected), Vengeful Pharaoh will still trigger. You must target and destroy one of your own attacking creatures.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220226]]></id><name><![CDATA[Visions of Beyond]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Draw a card. If a graveyard has twenty or more cards in it, draw three cards instead.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The past is the foundation for all that exists in the present. We merely reconstruct what our ancestors have already discovered."<br>—Sachimir, Sage of Memories]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Terese Nielsen]]></artist><number><![CDATA[80]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : The number of cards in each player's graveyard is counted when Visions of Beyond resolves. Visions of Beyond won't count itself as it will still be on the stack at this time.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244719]]></id><name><![CDATA[Volcanic Dragon]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Dragon]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Haste (This creature can attack and {T} as soon as it comes under your control.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Sometimes an eruption in Shiv produces something more dangerous than a mere river of molten rock.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chris Rahn]]></artist><number><![CDATA[158]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[220189]]></id><name><![CDATA[Wall of Torches]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Wall]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Defender (This creature can't attack.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The foolish try to leap through the unlit spaces. The arrogant believe the fires harmless. The wise find a different door.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mike Bierek]]></artist><number><![CDATA[159]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[241995]]></id><name><![CDATA[Warpath Ghoul]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Zombie]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Ghouls are often found skulking on the fringes of great battles, showing themselves only to snatch the wounded and weak, dragging their victims screaming into the shadows.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[rk post]]></artist><number><![CDATA[117]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[228796]]></id><name><![CDATA[Warstorm Surge]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever a creature enters the battlefield under your control, it deals damage equal to its power to target creature or player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Listen to the roar! Feel the thunder! The Immersturm shouts its approval with every bolt of lightning!"]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Raymond Swanland]]></artist><number><![CDATA[160]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : The creature that entered the battlefield deals damage equal to its current power to the targeted creature or player. If it's no longer on the battlefield, its last known existence on the battlefield is checked to determine its power. <br>9/22/2011 : Warstorm Surge is the source of the ability, but the creature is the source of the damage. The ability couldn't target a creature with protection from red, for example. It could target a creature with protection from creatures, but all the damage would be prevented. Since damage is dealt by the creature, abilities like lifelink, deathtouch and infect are taken into account, even if the creature has left the battlefield by the time it deals damage.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[227302]]></id><name><![CDATA[Worldslayer]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact — Equipment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever equipped creature deals combat damage to a player, destroy all permanents other than Worldslayer.<br>Equip {5} ({5}: Attach to target creature you control. Equip only as a sorcery.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["If that is what you seek, try looking in craters."<br>—Fodrus, mastersmith]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Greg Staples]]></artist><number><![CDATA[222]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : The equipped creature is also destroyed.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[230758]]></id><name><![CDATA[Wring Flesh]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target creature gets -3/-1 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Don't blame me. You're the one walking around with skin."<br>—Zul Ashur, lich lord]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Izzy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[118]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[221524]]></id><name><![CDATA[Wurm's Tooth]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever a player casts a green spell, you may gain 1 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Jevna Nor lugged it around, bragging of his triumph over the wurm. Luckily, the tavern regulars didn't notice it was only a baby tooth.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Alan Pollack]]></artist><number><![CDATA[223]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : The ability triggers whenever any player, not just you, casts a green spell. <br>10/1/2009 : If a player casts a green spell, Wurm's Tooth's ability triggers and is put on the stack on top of that spell. Wurm's Tooth's ability will resolve (causing you to gain 1 life) before the spell does.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[226558]]></id><name><![CDATA[Zombie Goliath]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Zombie Giant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Removing the encumbrance of useless brain tissue grants several advantages: a slight increase in mobility, a response of revulsion and horror from the enemy, and, in the case of large specimens, room for passengers."<br>—Zul Ashur, lich lord]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[E. M. Gist]]></artist><number><![CDATA[119]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[241860]]></id><name><![CDATA[Zombie Infestation]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Discard two cards: Put a 2/2 black Zombie creature token onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The nomads' funeral pyres are more practical than ceremonial.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Thomas M. Baxa]]></artist><number><![CDATA[120]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244320]]></id><name><![CDATA[Forest]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Forest]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{G}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Glen Angus]]></artist><number><![CDATA[246]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244321]]></id><name><![CDATA[Forest]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Forest]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{G}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jim Nelson]]></artist><number><![CDATA[248]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244322]]></id><name><![CDATA[Forest]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Forest]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{G}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ryan Pancoast]]></artist><number><![CDATA[249]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244325]]></id><name><![CDATA[Island]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Island]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{U}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Rob Alexander]]></artist><number><![CDATA[234]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244326]]></id><name><![CDATA[Island]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Island]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{U}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Peter Mohrbacher]]></artist><number><![CDATA[237]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244324]]></id><name><![CDATA[Island]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Island]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{U}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Michael Komarck]]></artist><number><![CDATA[236]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244328]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mountain]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Mountain]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Cliff Childs]]></artist><number><![CDATA[242]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244329]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mountain]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Mountain]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Robh Ruppel]]></artist><number><![CDATA[244]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244327]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mountain]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Mountain]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Sam Wood]]></artist><number><![CDATA[245]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244333]]></id><name><![CDATA[Plains]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Plains]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{W}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Rob Alexander]]></artist><number><![CDATA[230]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244334]]></id><name><![CDATA[Plains]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Plains]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{W}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Howard Lyon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[232]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244332]]></id><name><![CDATA[Plains]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Plains]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{W}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Charles Urbach]]></artist><number><![CDATA[233]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244335]]></id><name><![CDATA[Swamp]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Swamp]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{B}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jung Park]]></artist><number><![CDATA[240]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244338]]></id><name><![CDATA[Swamp]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Swamp]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{B}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Cliff Childs]]></artist><number><![CDATA[238]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[244336]]></id><name><![CDATA[Swamp]]></name><set><![CDATA[M12]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Swamp]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{B}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Alan Pollack]]></artist><number><![CDATA[241]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card></cards></mtg_carddatabase>