<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><mtg_carddatabase><bdd_date><![CDATA[1-5-2013]]></bdd_date><bdd_version><![CDATA[1.00]]></bdd_version><bdd_name>Magic the Gathering® Card Database</bdd_name><bdd_editor>Wizards of the Coast LLC</bdd_editor><sets><set><name><![CDATA[Planechase 2012 Edition]]></name><code><![CDATA[PC2]]></code><code_magiccards><![CDATA[PC2]]></code_magiccards><date><![CDATA[06/2012]]></date><is_promo><![CDATA[True]]></is_promo></set></sets><cards><card><id><![CDATA[275254]]></id><name><![CDATA[Arc Trail]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Arc Trail deals 2 damage to target creature or player and 1 damage to another target creature or player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Don't try to hit your enemies. Concentrate on the space between them, and fill the air with doom."<br>—Spear-Tribe teaching]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Marc Simonetti]]></artist><number><![CDATA[39]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271137]]></id><name><![CDATA[Armillary Sphere]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{2}, {T}, Sacrifice Armillary Sphere: Search your library for up to two basic land cards, reveal them, and put them into your hand. Then shuffle your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The mysterious purpose of two of the rings had eluded Esper mages—until now.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Franz Vohwinkel]]></artist><number><![CDATA[108]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271234]]></id><name><![CDATA[Armored Griffin]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Griffin]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying, vigilance]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[When an order for griffin barding comes in, blacksmiths prepare their forges for months of exacting work. They know griffins always detect imperfections and never haggle.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Brad Rigney]]></artist><number><![CDATA[1]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271218]]></id><name><![CDATA[Assassinate]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Destroy target tapped creature.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["This is how wars are won—not with armies of soldiers but with a single knife blade, artfully placed."<br>—Yurin, royal assassin]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kev Walker]]></artist><number><![CDATA[30]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271192]]></id><name><![CDATA[Augury Owl]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Bird]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>When Augury Owl enters the battlefield, scry 3. (To scry 3, look at the top three cards of your library, then put any number of them on the bottom of your library and the rest on top in any order.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jim Nelson]]></artist><number><![CDATA[14]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271147]]></id><name><![CDATA[Aura Gnarlid]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Beast]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Creatures with power less than Aura Gnarlid's power can't block it.<br>Aura Gnarlid gets +1/+1 for each Aura on the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Kill a gnarlid with your first blow, or it'll cheerfully show you how it's done.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Lars Grant-West]]></artist><number><![CDATA[55]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/15/2010 : The power of each potential blocking creature is checked against Aura Gnarlid's power only as blockers are declared. Once a creature blocks Aura Gnarlid, increasing the Gnarlid's power or decreasing the blocking creature's power won't undo that block. <br>6/15/2010 : Aura Gnarlid's second ability counts each Aura regardless of who controls it.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271171]]></id><name><![CDATA[Auramancer]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Auramancer enters the battlefield, you may return target enchantment card from your graveyard to your hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["In memories, we can find our deepest reserves of strength."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Rebecca Guay]]></artist><number><![CDATA[2]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271207]]></id><name><![CDATA[Auratouched Mage]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Auratouched Mage enters the battlefield, search your library for an Aura card that could enchant it. If Auratouched Mage is still on the battlefield, put that Aura card onto the battlefield attached to it. Otherwise, reveal the Aura card and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jeff Miracola]]></artist><number><![CDATA[3]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2005 : Any Aura card you find must be able to enchant Auratouched Mage as it currently exists, or as it most recently existed on the battlefield if it's no longer on the battlefield. If an effect has made the Mage an artifact, for example, you could search for an Aura with "enchant artifact."]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271156]]></id><name><![CDATA[Awakening Zone]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[At the beginning of your upkeep, you may put a 0/1 colorless Eldrazi Spawn creature token onto the battlefield. It has "Sacrifice this creature: Add {1} to your mana pool."]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The ground erupted in time with the hedron's thrum, a dirge of the last days.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Johann Bodin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[56]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[265156]]></id><name><![CDATA[Baleful Strix]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Bird]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{U}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying, deathtouch<br>When Baleful Strix enters the battlefield, draw a card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Its beak rends flesh and bone, exposing the tender marrow of dream.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Nils Hamm]]></artist><number><![CDATA[82]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[275255]]></id><name><![CDATA[Beast Within]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Destroy target permanent. Its controller puts a 3/3 green Beast creature token onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Kill the weak so they can't drag the strong down to their level. This is true compassion."<br>—Benzir, archdruid of Temple Might]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Allsop]]></artist><number><![CDATA[57]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/1/2011 : If the permanent is an illegal target when Beast Within tries to resolve, the spell will be countered and none of its effects will happen. The permanent's controller won't get a Beast token. <br>6/1/2011 : If the permanent is still a legal target but is not destroyed (perhaps because it regenerated or is indestructible), its controller still gets the Beast token.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[265145]]></id><name><![CDATA[Beetleback Chief]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Goblin Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Beetleback Chief enters the battlefield, put two 1/1 red Goblin creature tokens onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Whether trained, ridden, or eaten, few goblin military innovations have rivaled the bug.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Wayne England]]></artist><number><![CDATA[40]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271166]]></id><name><![CDATA[Bituminous Blast]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{B}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Cascade (When you cast this spell, exile cards from the top of your library until you exile a nonland card that costs less. You may cast it without paying its mana cost. Put the exiled cards on the bottom in a random order.)<br>Bituminous Blast deals 4 damage to target creature.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Raymond Swanland]]></artist><number><![CDATA[83]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>5/1/2009 : Cascade triggers when you cast the spell, meaning that it resolves before that spell. If you end up casting the exiled card, it will go on the stack above the spell with Cascade. <br>5/1/2009 : When the Cascade ability resolves, you must exile cards. The only optional part of the ability is whether or not your cast the last card exiled. <br>5/1/2009 : If a spell with Cascade is countered, the Cascade ability will still resolve normally. <br>5/1/2009 : You exile  the cards face-up. All players will be able to see them. <br>5/1/2009 : If you exile a split card with Cascade, check if at least one half of that split card has a converted mana cost that's less than the converted mana cost of the spell with cascade. If so, you can cast either half of that split card. <br>5/1/2009 : If you cast the last exiled card, you're casting it as a spell. It can be countered. If that card has cascade, the new spell's cascade ability will trigger, and you'll repeat the process for the new spell. <br>5/1/2009 : After you're done exiling cards and casting the last one if you chose to do so, the remaining exiled cards are randomly placed on the bottom of your library. Neither you nor any other player is allowed to know the order of those cards.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271167]]></id><name><![CDATA[Bloodbraid Elf]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elf Berserker]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Haste<br>Cascade (When you cast this spell, exile cards from the top of your library until you exile a nonland card that costs less. You may cast it without paying its mana cost. Put the exiled cards on the bottom in a random order.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Argyle]]></artist><number><![CDATA[84]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>5/1/2009 : Cascade triggers when you cast the spell, meaning that it resolves before that spell. If you end up casting the exiled card, it will go on the stack above the spell with Cascade. <br>5/1/2009 : When the Cascade ability resolves, you must exile cards. The only optional part of the ability is whether or not your cast the last card exiled. <br>5/1/2009 : If a spell with Cascade is countered, the Cascade ability will still resolve normally. <br>5/1/2009 : You exile  the cards face-up. All players will be able to see them. <br>5/1/2009 : If you exile a split card with Cascade, check if at least one half of that split card has a converted mana cost that's less than the converted mana cost of the spell with cascade. If so, you can cast either half of that split card. <br>5/1/2009 : If you cast the last exiled card, you're casting it as a spell. It can be countered. If that card has cascade, the new spell's cascade ability will trigger, and you'll repeat the process for the new spell. <br>5/1/2009 : After you're done exiling cards and casting the last one if you chose to do so, the remaining exiled cards are randomly placed on the bottom of your library. Neither you nor any other player is allowed to know the order of those cards.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271148]]></id><name><![CDATA[Boar Umbra]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature gets +3/+3.<br>Totem armor (If enchanted creature would be destroyed, instead remove all damage from it and destroy this Aura.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["From in here, everything looks like dinner."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Christopher Moeller]]></artist><number><![CDATA[58]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/15/2010 :  Totem armor's effect is mandatory. If the enchanted permanent would be destroyed, you must remove all damage from it and destroy the Aura that has totem armor instead. <br>6/15/2010 :  Totem armor's effect is applied no matter why the enchanted permanent would be destroyed: because it's been dealt lethal damage, or because it's being affected by an effect that says to "destroy" it (such as Doom Blade). In either case, all damage is removed from the permanent and the Aura is destroyed instead. <br>6/15/2010 : Totem armor has no effect if the enchanted permanent is put into a graveyard for any other reason, such as if it's sacrificed, if it's legendary and another legendary permanent with the same name is on the battlefield, or if its toughness is 0 or less. <br>6/15/2010 : If a permanent you control is enchanted with multiple Auras that have totem armor, and the enchanted permanent would be destroyed, one of those Auras is destroyed instead -- but only one of them. You choose which one because you control the enchanted permanent. <br>6/15/2010 : If a creature enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor is indestructible, lethal damage and effects that try to destroy it simply have no effect. Totem armor won't do anything because it won't have to. <br>6/15/2010 : If a creature enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor would be destroyed by multiple state-based actions at the same time the totem armor's effect will replace all of them and save the creature. <br>6/15/2010 : If a spell or ability (such as Planar Cleansing) would destroy both an Aura with totem armor and the permanent it's enchanting at the same time, totem armor's effect will save the enchanted permanent from being destroyed. Instead, the spell or ability will destroy the Aura in two different ways at the same time, but the result is the same as destroying it once. <br>6/15/2010 : Totem armor's effect is not regeneration. Specifically, if totem armor's effect is applied, the enchanted permanent does not become tapped and is not removed from combat as a result. Effects that say the enchanted permanent can't be regenerated (as Vendetta does) won't prevent totem armor's effect from being applied. <br>6/15/2010 : Say you control a permanent enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor, and the enchanted permanent has gained a regeneration shield. The next time it would be destroyed, you choose whether to apply the regeneration effect or the totem armor effect. The other effect is unused and remains, in case the permanent would be destroyed again. <br>6/15/2010 : Say you control a permanent enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor, and that Aura has gained a regeneration shield. The next time the enchanted permanent would be destroyed, the Aura would be destroyed instead -- but it regenerates, so nothing is destroyed at all. Alternately, if that Aura somehow becomes indestructible, the enchanted permanent is effectively indestructible as well. <br>6/15/2010 : If a spell or ability says that it would "destroy" a permanent enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor, that spell or ability causes the Aura to be destroyed instead. (This matters for cards such as Karmic Justice.) Totem armor doesn't destroy the Aura; rather, it changes the effects of the spell or ability. On the other hand, if a spell or ability deals lethal damage to a creature enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor, the game rules regarding lethal damage cause the Aura to be destroyed, not that spell or ability.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271208]]></id><name><![CDATA[Bramble Elemental]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever an Aura becomes attached to Bramble Elemental, put two 1/1 green Saproling creature tokens onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[In abandoned corners of Ravnica, nature has begun to reclaim what it once owned.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Tomas Giorello]]></artist><number><![CDATA[59]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[265141]]></id><name><![CDATA[Brindle Shoat]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Boar]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Brindle Shoat dies, put a 3/3 green Boar creature token onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Hunters lure the stripling boar into the open, hoping to trap greater prey.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steven Belledin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[60]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[275256]]></id><name><![CDATA[Brutalizer Exarch]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Cleric]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Brutalizer Exarch enters the battlefield, choose one — Search your library for a creature card, reveal it, then shuffle your library and put that card on top of it; or put target noncreature permanent on the bottom of its owner's library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mark Zug]]></artist><number><![CDATA[61]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271157]]></id><name><![CDATA[Cadaver Imp]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Imp]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>When Cadaver Imp enters the battlefield, you may return target creature card from your graveyard to your hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The mouth must be pried open before rigor mortis sets in. Otherwise the returning soul can find no ingress.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dave Kendall]]></artist><number><![CDATA[31]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271205]]></id><name><![CDATA[Cage of Hands]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature can't attack or block.<br>{1}{W}: Return Cage of Hands to its owner's hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mark Tedin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[4]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271172]]></id><name><![CDATA[Cancel]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Counter target spell.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["What you are attempting is not against the law. It is, however, extremely foolish."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[David Palumbo]]></artist><number><![CDATA[15]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271236]]></id><name><![CDATA[Celestial Ancient]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Whenever you cast an enchantment spell, put a +1/+1 counter on each creature you control.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["We thought the clouds had moved from the night sky. Then the night sky moved, and the horizon grew wings."<br>—Josuri]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mark Tedin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[5]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271220]]></id><name><![CDATA[Concentrate]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Draw three cards.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The treasure in my mind is greater than any worldly glory."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[rk post]]></artist><number><![CDATA[16]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271193]]></id><name><![CDATA[Cultivate]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Search your library for up to two basic land cards, reveal those cards, and put one onto the battlefield tapped and the other into your hand. Then shuffle your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[All seeds share a common bond, calling to each other across infinity.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Anthony Palumbo]]></artist><number><![CDATA[62]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : If you choose to find only one basic land card, you put it onto the battlefield tapped.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271217]]></id><name><![CDATA[Dark Hatchling]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Horror]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>When Dark Hatchling enters the battlefield, destroy target nonblack creature. It can't be regenerated.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Brad Rigney]]></artist><number><![CDATA[32]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271168]]></id><name><![CDATA[Deny Reality]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Cascade (When you cast this spell, exile cards from the top of your library until you exile a nonland card that costs less. You may cast it without paying its mana cost. Put the exiled cards on the bottom in a random order.)<br>Return target permanent to its owner's hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jean-Sébastien Rossbach]]></artist><number><![CDATA[85]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>5/1/2009 : Cascade triggers when you cast the spell, meaning that it resolves before that spell. If you end up casting the exiled card, it will go on the stack above the spell with Cascade. <br>5/1/2009 : When the Cascade ability resolves, you must exile cards. The only optional part of the ability is whether or not your cast the last card exiled. <br>5/1/2009 : If a spell with Cascade is countered, the Cascade ability will still resolve normally. <br>5/1/2009 : You exile  the cards face-up. All players will be able to see them. <br>5/1/2009 : If you exile a split card with Cascade, check if at least one half of that split card has a converted mana cost that's less than the converted mana cost of the spell with cascade. If so, you can cast either half of that split card. <br>5/1/2009 : If you cast the last exiled card, you're casting it as a spell. It can be countered. If that card has cascade, the new spell's cascade ability will trigger, and you'll repeat the process for the new spell. <br>5/1/2009 : After you're done exiling cards and casting the last one if you chose to do so, the remaining exiled cards are randomly placed on the bottom of your library. Neither you nor any other player is allowed to know the order of those cards.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271209]]></id><name><![CDATA[Dimir Aqueduct]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Dimir Aqueduct enters the battlefield tapped.<br>When Dimir Aqueduct enters the battlefield, return a land you control to its owner's hand.<br>{T}: Add {U}{B} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[John Avon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[116]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>4/15/2013 : If this land enters the battlefield and you control no other lands, its ability will force you to return it to your hand.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271214]]></id><name><![CDATA[Dimir Infiltrator]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Spirit]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{U}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Dimir Infiltrator is unblockable.<br>Transmute {1}{U}{B} ({1}{U}{B}, Discard this card: Search your library for a card with the same converted mana cost as this card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library. Transmute only as a sorcery.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jim Nelson]]></artist><number><![CDATA[86]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271210]]></id><name><![CDATA[Dowsing Shaman]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Centaur Shaman]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{2}{G}, {T}: Return target enchantment card from your graveyard to your hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[He combs the streets looking for the lost light, the discarded enigmas of the city.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Wayne Reynolds]]></artist><number><![CDATA[63]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[270726]]></id><name><![CDATA[Dragonlair Spider]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Spider]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}{R}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Reach<br>Whenever an opponent casts a spell, put a 1/1 green Insect creature token onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Swarms thrive in its nest, feeding on leathery bits of discarded wing.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Carl Critchlow]]></artist><number><![CDATA[87]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/1/2012 : The triggered ability will resolve and the Insect will be created before the spell that caused it to trigger resolves. <br>6/1/2012 : The triggered ability won't be affected if the spell that caused it to trigger is countered.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[270742]]></id><name><![CDATA[Dreampod Druid]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Druid]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[At the beginning of each upkeep, if Dreampod Druid is enchanted, put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Don't mistake my creations for mere vegetation. They are my children, loyal and fierce."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Wayne Reynolds]]></artist><number><![CDATA[64]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/1/2012 : Dreampod Druid's ability checks to see if it's enchanted at the beginning of each upkeep. If it's not, the ability won't trigger. If the ability triggers but Dreampod Druid isn't enchanted when that ability resolves, the ability will do nothing. <br>6/1/2012 : Notably, if Dreampod Druid leaves the battlefield while its ability is on the stack, that ability will use Dreampod Druid's last known information to determine whether or not it was enchanted. If it was enchanted when it left the battlefield, the ability will resolve and create a Saproling.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[270725]]></id><name><![CDATA[Elderwood Scion]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{G}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Trample, lifelink<br>Spells you cast that target Elderwood Scion cost {2} less to cast.<br>Spells your opponents cast that target Elderwood Scion cost {2} more to cast.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The Sunbriar druids believe that every life begins in its heart and ends under its hooves.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Nils Hamm]]></artist><number><![CDATA[88]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/1/2012 : None of Elderwood Scion's abilities affect abilities that target it. <br>6/1/2012 : Aura spells require a target when they are cast. Elderwood Scion's cost-reduction ability will affect Aura spells cast targeting it. <br>6/1/2012 : Spells you cast that target Elderwood Scion will cost {2} less to cast even if those spells have additional targets. The same is true for spells your opponents cast costing {2} more. <br>6/1/2012 : Elderwood Scion's cost-reduction ability can't reduce the colored mana requirement of a spell. <br>6/1/2012 : Elderwood Scion's cost-reduction ability can apply to any cost of a spell, including additional or alternative costs.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271169]]></id><name><![CDATA[Enigma Sphinx]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Sphinx]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{W}{U}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>When Enigma Sphinx is put into your graveyard from the battlefield, put it into your library third from the top.<br>Cascade (When you cast this spell, exile cards from the top of your library until you exile a nonland card that costs less. You may cast it without paying its mana cost. Put the exiled cards on the bottom in a random order.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Chris Rahn]]></artist><number><![CDATA[89]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>5/1/2009 : Cascade triggers when you cast the spell, meaning that it resolves before that spell. If you end up casting the exiled card, it will go on the stack above the spell with Cascade. <br>5/1/2009 : When the Cascade ability resolves, you must exile cards. The only optional part of the ability is whether or not your cast the last card exiled. <br>5/1/2009 : If a spell with Cascade is countered, the Cascade ability will still resolve normally. <br>5/1/2009 : You exile  the cards face-up. All players will be able to see them. <br>5/1/2009 : If you exile a split card with Cascade, check if at least one half of that split card has a converted mana cost that's less than the converted mana cost of the spell with cascade. If so, you can cast either half of that split card. <br>5/1/2009 : If you cast the last exiled card, you're casting it as a spell. It can be countered. If that card has cascade, the new spell's cascade ability will trigger, and you'll repeat the process for the new spell. <br>5/1/2009 : After you're done exiling cards and casting the last one if you chose to do so, the remaining exiled cards are randomly placed on the bottom of your library. Neither you nor any other player is allowed to know the order of those cards. <br>5/1/2009 : After Enigma Sphinx's middle ability triggers, if Enigma Sphinx is removed from your graveyard in response, it won't be put into your library. <br>5/1/2009 : If you have zero or one card left in your library when Enigma Sphinx's middle ability resolves, Enigma Sphinx is put on the bottom of your library. <br>5/1/2009 : If you control an Enigma Sphinx that's owned by another player, it's put into that player's graveyard from the battlefield, so Enigma Sphinx's middle ability won't trigger.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271170]]></id><name><![CDATA[Enlisted Wurm]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Wurm]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{G}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Cascade (When you cast this spell, exile cards from the top of your library until you exile a nonland card that costs less. You may cast it without paying its mana cost. Put the exiled cards on the bottom in a random order.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[A match for any army—even its own.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Prescott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[90]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>5/1/2009 : Cascade triggers when you cast the spell, meaning that it resolves before that spell. If you end up casting the exiled card, it will go on the stack above the spell with Cascade. <br>5/1/2009 : When the Cascade ability resolves, you must exile cards. The only optional part of the ability is whether or not your cast the last card exiled. <br>5/1/2009 : If a spell with Cascade is countered, the Cascade ability will still resolve normally. <br>5/1/2009 : You exile  the cards face-up. All players will be able to see them. <br>5/1/2009 : If you exile a split card with Cascade, check if at least one half of that split card has a converted mana cost that's less than the converted mana cost of the spell with cascade. If so, you can cast either half of that split card. <br>5/1/2009 : If you cast the last exiled card, you're casting it as a spell. It can be countered. If that card has cascade, the new spell's cascade ability will trigger, and you'll repeat the process for the new spell. <br>5/1/2009 : After you're done exiling cards and casting the last one if you chose to do so, the remaining exiled cards are randomly placed on the bottom of your library. Neither you nor any other player is allowed to know the order of those cards.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271191]]></id><name><![CDATA[Erratic Explosion]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Choose target creature or player. Reveal cards from the top of your library until you reveal a nonland card. Erratic Explosion deals damage equal to that card's converted mana cost to that creature or player. Put the revealed cards on the bottom of your library in any order.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Gary Ruddell]]></artist><number><![CDATA[41]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/4/2004 : If all your cards are lands, no damage is dealt. ]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[265144]]></id><name><![CDATA[Etherium-Horn Sorcerer]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Minotaur Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{U}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{1}{U}{R}: Return Etherium-Horn Sorcerer to its owner's hand.<br>Cascade (When you cast this spell, exile cards from the top of your library until you exile a nonland card that costs less. You may cast it without paying its mana cost. Put the exiled cards on the bottom in a random order.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Franz Vohwinkel]]></artist><number><![CDATA[91]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/1/2012 : Etherium-Horn Sorcerer's first ability can only be activated when it is on the battlefield. If Etherium-Horn Sorcerer isn't on the battlefield when the ability resolves, the ability won't do anything.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[275257]]></id><name><![CDATA[Exotic Orchard]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Add to your mana pool one mana of any color that a land an opponent controls could produce.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["It was a strange morning. When we awoke, we found our trees transformed. We didn't know whether to water them or polish them."<br>—Pulan, Bant orchardist]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steven Belledin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[117]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : The colors of mana are white, blue, black, red, and green. Exotic Orchard can't be tapped for colorless mana, even if a land an opponent controls could produce colorless mana. <br>2/1/2009 : Exotic Orchard checks the effects of all mana-producing abilities of lands your opponents control, but it doesn't check their costs. For example, Vivid Crag has the ability "{T}, Remove a charge counter from Vivid Crag: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool." If an opponent controls Vivid Crag and you control Exotic Orchard, you can tap Exotic Orchard for any color of mana. It doesn't matter whether Vivid Crag has a charge counter on it, and it doesn't matter whether it's untapped. <br>2/1/2009 : When determining what colors of mana your opponents' lands could produce, Exotic Orchard takes into account any applicable replacement effects that would apply to those lands' mana abilities (such as Contamination's effect, for example). If there are more than one, consider them in any possible order. <br>2/1/2009 : Exotic Orchard doesn't care about any restrictions or riders your opponents' lands (such as Ancient Ziggurat or Hall of the Bandit Lord) put on the mana they produce. It just cares about colors of mana. <br>2/1/2009 : Lands that produce mana based only on what other lands "could produce" won't help each other unless some other land allows one of them to actually produce some type of mana. For example, if you control an Exotic Orchard and your opponent controls an Exotic Orchard and a Reflecting Pool, none of those lands would produce mana if their mana abilities were activated. On the other hand, if you control a Forest and an Exotic Orchard, and your opponent controls an Exotic Orchard and a Reflecting Pool, then each of those lands can be tapped to produce {G}. Your opponent's Exotic Orchard can produce {G} because you control a Forest. Your Exotic Orchard and your opponent's Reflecting Pool can each produce {G} because your opponent's Exotic Orchard can produce {G}.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[275263]]></id><name><![CDATA[Farsight Mask]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever a source an opponent controls deals damage to you, if Farsight Mask is untapped, you may draw a card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It turns the adversity of the moment into the knowledge of a lifetime.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ben Thompson]]></artist><number><![CDATA[109]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>12/1/2004 : This triggers each time a source an opponent controls deals damage to you. If the same source deals damage more than once in a turn, it triggers for each of those times. <br>12/1/2004 : You draw no more than one card each time a source an opponent controls damages you, no matter how much damage the source deals. <br>12/1/2004 : Farsight Mask must be untapped both when the damage is dealt and when you would draw the card. <br>12/1/2004 : Each instance of each creature's combat damage is counted separately. If three creatures with double strike attack you and all of them are unblocked, you may draw up to six cards.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[270736]]></id><name><![CDATA[Felidar Umbra]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature has lifelink.<br>{1}{W}: Attach Felidar Umbra to target creature you control.<br>Totem armor (If enchanted creature would be destroyed, instead remove all damage from it and destroy this Aura.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Christopher Moeller]]></artist><number><![CDATA[6]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/1/2012 : If Felidar Umbra is enchanting a creature with first strike, you can activate its ability and attach it to a creature without first strike during the first combat damage step. Each of those creatures will have lifelink when dealing combat damage and you'll gain life accordingly. <br>6/1/2012 : It's not possible for Felidar Umbra to save two creatures that are being destroyed simultaneously.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[275259]]></id><name><![CDATA[Fiery Conclusion]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[As an additional cost to cast Fiery Conclusion, sacrifice a creature.<br>Fiery Conclusion deals 5 damage to target creature.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The Boros legionnaire saw a noble sacrifice, the Rakdos thug a blazing suicide, and the Izzet alchemist an experiment gone awry.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Parente]]></artist><number><![CDATA[42]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>4/15/2013 : You must sacrifice exactly one creature to cast this spell; you cannot cast it without sacrificing a creature, and you cannot sacrifice additional creatures. <br>4/15/2013 : Players can only respond once this spell has been cast and all its costs have been paid. No one can try to destroy the creature you sacrificed to prevent you from casting this spell.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271138]]></id><name><![CDATA[Fiery Fall]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Fiery Fall deals 5 damage to target creature.<br>Basic landcycling {1}{R} ({1}{R}, Discard this card: Search your library for a basic land card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. Then shuffle your library.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Jund feasts on the unprepared.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Daarken]]></artist><number><![CDATA[43]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Unlike the normal cycling ability, basic landcycling doesn't allow you to draw a card. Instead, it lets you search your library for a basic land card. You don't choose the type of basic land card you'll find until you're performing the search. After you choose a basic land card in your library, you reveal it, put it into your hand, then shuffle your library. <br>2/1/2009 : Basic landcycling is a form of cycling. Any ability that triggers on a card being cycled also triggers on a card being basic landcycled. Any ability that stops a cycling ability from being activated also stops a basic landcycling ability from being activated. <br>2/1/2009 : Basic landcycling is an activated ability. Effects that interact with activated abilities (such as Stifle or Rings of Brighthearth) will interact with basic landcycling. Effects that interact with spells (such as Remove Soul or Faerie Tauntings) will not. <br>2/1/2009 : You can choose not to find a basic land card, even if there is one in your library.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276068]]></id><name><![CDATA[Fires of Yavimaya]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Creatures you control have haste.<br>Sacrifice Fires of Yavimaya: Target creature gets +2/+2 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Val Mayerik]]></artist><number><![CDATA[92]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271145]]></id><name><![CDATA[Flayer Husk]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact — Equipment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Living weapon (When this Equipment enters the battlefield, put a 0/0 black Germ creature token onto the battlefield, then attach this to it.)<br>Equipped creature gets +1/+1.<br>Equip {2}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Igor Kieryluk]]></artist><number><![CDATA[110]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271225]]></id><name><![CDATA[Fling]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Instant]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[As an additional cost to cast Fling, sacrifice a creature.<br>Fling deals damage equal to the sacrificed creature's power to target creature or player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[About halfway to the target, Snukk vowed that he had been tricked for the last time.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Parente]]></artist><number><![CDATA[44]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/15/2010 : The sacrificed creature's last known existence on the battlefield is checked to determine its power. <br>8/15/2010 : If you sacrifice an attacking or blocking creature during the declare blockers step, it won't deal combat damage. If you wait until the combat damage step, but that creature is dealt lethal damage, it'll be destroyed before you get a chance to sacrifice it. <br>4/15/2013 : You must sacrifice exactly one creature to cast this spell; you cannot cast it without sacrificing a creature, and you cannot sacrifice additional creatures. <br>4/15/2013 : Players can only respond once this spell has been cast and all its costs have been paid. No one can try to destroy the creature you sacrificed to prevent you from casting this spell.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276456]]></id><name><![CDATA[Forest]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Forest]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{G}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Vincent Proce]]></artist><number><![CDATA[155]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[265151]]></id><name><![CDATA[Fractured Powerstone]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.<br>{T}: Roll the planar die. Activate this ability only any time you could cast a sorcery.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The Thran learned to capture mana, but power inevitably escapes its bonds.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Rob Alexander]]></artist><number><![CDATA[111]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/1/2012 : In non-Planechase games, Fractured Powerstone's second ability will have no effect. <br>6/1/2012 : Rolling the planar die this way doesn't count when determining the cost of the special action of rolling the planar die. For example, if you roll the planar die twice in a turn, then activate Fractured Powerstone to roll it a third time, rolling the planar die again that turn will cost {2}.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271139]]></id><name><![CDATA[Fusion Elemental]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{W}{U}{B}{R}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[8]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[8]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[As the shards merged into the Maelstrom, their mana energies fused into new monstrosities.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Michael Komarck]]></artist><number><![CDATA[93]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[275264]]></id><name><![CDATA[Ghostly Prison]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Creatures can't attack you unless their controller pays {2} for each creature he or she controls that's attacking you.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["May the memory of our fallen heroes ensnare the violent hearts of lesser men."<br>—Great Threshold of Monserkat inscription]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Wayne England]]></artist><number><![CDATA[7]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2007 : In the Two-Headed Giant format, you still only have to pay once per creature.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271215]]></id><name><![CDATA[Glen Elendra Liege]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Faerie Knight]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{UB}{UB}{UB}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Other blue creatures you control get +1/+1.<br>Other black creatures you control get +1/+1.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Those who displease Oona soon learn the extent of the armies she commands.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kev Walker]]></artist><number><![CDATA[94]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>5/1/2008 : The abilities are separate and cumulative. If another creature you control is both of the listed colors, it will get a total of +2/+2.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271140]]></id><name><![CDATA[Gluttonous Slime]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Ooze]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flash<br>Devour 1 (As this enters the battlefield, you may sacrifice any number of creatures. This creature enters the battlefield with that many +1/+1 counters on it.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[On Jund, everything eventually ends up in something else's stomach.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Trevor Claxton]]></artist><number><![CDATA[65]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271131]]></id><name><![CDATA[Graypelt Refuge]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Graypelt Refuge enters the battlefield tapped.<br>When Graypelt Refuge enters the battlefield, you gain 1 life.<br>{T}: Add {G} or {W} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Philip Straub]]></artist><number><![CDATA[118]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271228]]></id><name><![CDATA[Gruul Turf]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Gruul Turf enters the battlefield tapped.<br>When Gruul Turf enters the battlefield, return a land you control to its owner's hand.<br>{T}: Add {R}{G} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[John Avon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[119]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>4/15/2013 : If this land enters the battlefield and you control no other lands, its ability will force you to return it to your hand.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[279846]]></id><name><![CDATA[Guard Gomazoa]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Jellyfish]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Defender, flying<br>Prevent all combat damage that would be dealt to Guard Gomazoa.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It lingers near the outposts of the Makindi Trenches, inadvertently granting another layer of defense.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Rob Alexander]]></artist><number><![CDATA[17]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271158]]></id><name><![CDATA[Hellion Eruption]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Sacrifice all creatures you control, then put that many 4/4 red Hellion creature tokens onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Just when you thought you'd be safe, in the middle of an open field with no Eldrazi around for miles.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Anthony Francisco]]></artist><number><![CDATA[45]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271141]]></id><name><![CDATA[Hellkite Hatchling]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Dragon]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Devour 1 (As this enters the battlefield, you may sacrifice any number of creatures. This creature enters the battlefield with that many +1/+1 counters on it.)<br>Hellkite Hatchling has flying and trample if it devoured a creature.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[A killing machine from birth.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Daarken]]></artist><number><![CDATA[95]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : Hellkite Hatchling has flying and trample if at least one creature was sacrificed as a result of the Hatchling's devour ability as it entered the battlefield. It retains those abilities even if its +1/+1 counters are somehow removed. <br>2/1/2009 : If another creature becomes a copy of Hellkite Hatchling (due to Mirrorweave, for example), the second ability checks to see whether that creature -- not the original Hellkite Hatchling -- devoured a creature as it entered the battlefield.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271181]]></id><name><![CDATA[Higure, the Still Wind]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Human Ninja]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Ninjutsu {2}{U}{U} ({2}{U}{U}, Return an unblocked attacker you control to hand: Put this card onto the battlefield from your hand tapped and attacking.)<br>Whenever Higure, the Still Wind deals combat damage to a player, you may search your library for a Ninja card, reveal it, and put it into your hand. If you do, shuffle your library.<br>{2}: Target Ninja creature is unblockable this turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Christopher Moeller]]></artist><number><![CDATA[18]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2005 : If Higure deals regular combat damage and you use its ability to search for another Ninja, that card won't be in your hand in time to activate its ninjutsu ability to put it onto the battlefield and deal damage. However, the card you searched for could still be swapped for an unblocked creature, including Higure, as long as you activate its ninjutsu ability before the end of combat. <br>2/1/2005 : If Higure deals first strike damage (or the first part of double strike damage), the triggered ability would resolve before regular combat damage, and the searched-for Ninja would be able to get swapped with an unblocked creature and still deal its regular damage.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271160]]></id><name><![CDATA[Hissing Iguanar]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Lizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever another creature dies, you may have Hissing Iguanar deal 1 damage to target player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Viashino thrashes keep iguanars as hunting companions, giving them wounded captives as playthings.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Brandon Kitkouski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[46]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271150]]></id><name><![CDATA[Hyena Umbra]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 and has first strike.<br>Totem armor (If enchanted creature would be destroyed, instead remove all damage from it and destroy this Aura.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Howard Lyon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[8]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/15/2010 :  Totem armor's effect is mandatory. If the enchanted permanent would be destroyed, you must remove all damage from it and destroy the Aura that has totem armor instead. <br>6/15/2010 :  Totem armor's effect is applied no matter why the enchanted permanent would be destroyed: because it's been dealt lethal damage, or because it's being affected by an effect that says to "destroy" it (such as Doom Blade). In either case, all damage is removed from the permanent and the Aura is destroyed instead. <br>6/15/2010 : Totem armor has no effect if the enchanted permanent is put into a graveyard for any other reason, such as if it's sacrificed, if it's legendary and another legendary permanent with the same name is on the battlefield, or if its toughness is 0 or less. <br>6/15/2010 : If a permanent you control is enchanted with multiple Auras that have totem armor, and the enchanted permanent would be destroyed, one of those Auras is destroyed instead -- but only one of them. You choose which one because you control the enchanted permanent. <br>6/15/2010 : If a creature enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor is indestructible, lethal damage and effects that try to destroy it simply have no effect. Totem armor won't do anything because it won't have to. <br>6/15/2010 : If a creature enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor would be destroyed by multiple state-based actions at the same time the totem armor's effect will replace all of them and save the creature. <br>6/15/2010 : If a spell or ability (such as Planar Cleansing) would destroy both an Aura with totem armor and the permanent it's enchanting at the same time, totem armor's effect will save the enchanted permanent from being destroyed. Instead, the spell or ability will destroy the Aura in two different ways at the same time, but the result is the same as destroying it once. <br>6/15/2010 : Totem armor's effect is not regeneration. Specifically, if totem armor's effect is applied, the enchanted permanent does not become tapped and is not removed from combat as a result. Effects that say the enchanted permanent can't be regenerated (as Vendetta does) won't prevent totem armor's effect from being applied. <br>6/15/2010 : Say you control a permanent enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor, and the enchanted permanent has gained a regeneration shield. The next time it would be destroyed, you choose whether to apply the regeneration effect or the totem armor effect. The other effect is unused and remains, in case the permanent would be destroyed again. <br>6/15/2010 : Say you control a permanent enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor, and that Aura has gained a regeneration shield. The next time the enchanted permanent would be destroyed, the Aura would be destroyed instead -- but it regenerates, so nothing is destroyed at all. Alternately, if that Aura somehow becomes indestructible, the enchanted permanent is effectively indestructible as well. <br>6/15/2010 : If a spell or ability says that it would "destroy" a permanent enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor, that spell or ability causes the Aura to be destroyed instead. (This matters for cards such as Karmic Justice.) Totem armor doesn't destroy the Aura; rather, it changes the effects of the spell or ability. On the other hand, if a spell or ability deals lethal damage to a creature enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor, the game rules regarding lethal damage cause the Aura to be destroyed, not that spell or ability.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[265143]]></id><name><![CDATA[Illusory Angel]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Angel Illusion]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Cast Illusory Angel only if you've cast another spell this turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Yes, she is made of pure belief—but I hardly see why that makes her unique."<br>—Reith, master illusionist]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Allen Williams]]></artist><number><![CDATA[19]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/1/2012 : Notably, if you exile Illusory Angel because of a cascade ability of a spell with converted mana cost 4 or greater, you'll be able to cast Illusory Angel.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[270724]]></id><name><![CDATA[Indrik Umbra]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{G}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature gets +4/+4 and has first strike, and all creatures able to block it do so.<br>Totem armor (If enchanted creature would be destroyed, instead remove all damage from it and destroy this Aura.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Christopher Moeller]]></artist><number><![CDATA[96]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/1/2012 : Indrik Umbra does not give any creature the ability to block the enchanted creature. It just forces those creatures which are already able to block that creature to do so. <br>6/1/2012 : If, during a player's declare blockers step, a creature is tapped or it's affected by a spell or ability that says it can't block, then it doesn't block. If there's a cost associated with having a creature block, its controller isn't forced to pay that cost. The creature doesn't have to block.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271182]]></id><name><![CDATA[Ink-Eyes, Servant of Oni]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Rat Ninja]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[5]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Ninjutsu {3}{B}{B} ({3}{B}{B}, Return an unblocked attacker you control to hand: Put this card onto the battlefield from your hand tapped and attacking.)<br>Whenever Ink-Eyes, Servant of Oni deals combat damage to a player, you may put target creature card from that player's graveyard onto the battlefield under your control.<br>{1}{B}: Regenerate Ink-Eyes.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Wayne Reynolds]]></artist><number><![CDATA[33]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2005 : If, during the combat damage step, a creature is destroyed during combat and Ink-Eyes also deals combat damage to a player, the destroyed creature can be a legal target for Ink-Eyes's ability.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271216]]></id><name><![CDATA[Inkfathom Witch]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Merfolk Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{UB}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Fear (This creature can't be blocked except by artifact creatures and/or black creatures.)<br>{2}{U}{B}: Each unblocked creature becomes 4/1 until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The murk of the Wanderbrine concealed unseemly rituals designed to bring out the worst in merrowkind.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Larry MacDougall]]></artist><number><![CDATA[97]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>5/1/2008 : An "unblocked creature" is a creature that attacked and wasn't blocked. Creatures aren't "blocked" or "unblocked" until the declare blockers step, so activating this ability before then (or after combat ends) will have no effect. <br>5/1/2008 : Creatures stop being unblocked as the combat phase ends. However, they'll stay 4/1 until turn ends. <br>5/1/2008 : Inkfathom Witch doesn't cause creatures to lose their abilities. <br>5/1/2008 : If Inkfathom Witch is attacking and unblocked, it can make itself 4/1. <br>10/1/2009 : The effect from the ability overwrites other effects that set power and/or toughness if and only if those effects existed before the ability resolved. It will not overwrite effects that modify power or toughness (whether from a static ability, counters, or a resolved spell or ability), nor will it overwrite effects that set power and toughness which come into existence after the ability resolves. Effects that switch the creature's power and toughness are always applied after any other power or toughness changing effects, including this one, regardless of the order in which they are created.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276471]]></id><name><![CDATA[Island]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Island]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{U}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Martina Pilcerova]]></artist><number><![CDATA[140]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271132]]></id><name><![CDATA[Jwar Isle Refuge]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Jwar Isle Refuge enters the battlefield tapped.<br>When Jwar Isle Refuge enters the battlefield, you gain 1 life.<br>{T}: Add {U} or {B} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Cyril Van Der Haegen]]></artist><number><![CDATA[120]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271189]]></id><name><![CDATA[Kathari Remnant]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Bird Skeleton]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>{B}: Regenerate Kathari Remnant.<br>Cascade (When you cast this spell, exile cards from the top of your library until you exile a nonland card that costs less. You may cast it without paying its mana cost. Put the exiled cards on the bottom in a random order.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Anthony S. Waters]]></artist><number><![CDATA[98]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>5/1/2009 : Cascade triggers when you cast the spell, meaning that it resolves before that spell. If you end up casting the exiled card, it will go on the stack above the spell with Cascade. <br>5/1/2009 : When the Cascade ability resolves, you must exile cards. The only optional part of the ability is whether or not your cast the last card exiled. <br>5/1/2009 : If a spell with Cascade is countered, the Cascade ability will still resolve normally. <br>5/1/2009 : You exile  the cards face-up. All players will be able to see them. <br>5/1/2009 : If you exile a split card with Cascade, check if at least one half of that split card has a converted mana cost that's less than the converted mana cost of the spell with cascade. If so, you can cast either half of that split card. <br>5/1/2009 : If you cast the last exiled card, you're casting it as a spell. It can be countered. If that card has cascade, the new spell's cascade ability will trigger, and you'll repeat the process for the new spell. <br>5/1/2009 : After you're done exiling cards and casting the last one if you chose to do so, the remaining exiled cards are randomly placed on the bottom of your library. Neither you nor any other player is allowed to know the order of those cards.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271133]]></id><name><![CDATA[Kazandu Refuge]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Kazandu Refuge enters the battlefield tapped.<br>When Kazandu Refuge enters the battlefield, you gain 1 life.<br>{T}: Add {R} or {G} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Franz Vohwinkel]]></artist><number><![CDATA[121]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271227]]></id><name><![CDATA[Khalni Garden]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Khalni Garden enters the battlefield tapped.<br>When Khalni Garden enters the battlefield, put a 0/1 green Plant creature token onto the battlefield.<br>{T}: Add {G} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ryan Pancoast]]></artist><number><![CDATA[122]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271151]]></id><name><![CDATA[Kor Spiritdancer]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Kor Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Kor Spiritdancer gets +2/+2 for each Aura attached to it.<br>Whenever you cast an Aura spell, you may draw a card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[She reaches beyond the physical realm, touching the ideals from which all creatures draw their power.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Scott Chou]]></artist><number><![CDATA[9]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/15/2010 : If you cast an Aura spell, Kor Spiritdancer's second ability triggers and goes on the stack on top of it. The ability will resolve before the spell does. <br>6/15/2010 : The second ability triggers when you cast any Aura spell, not just one that targets Kor Spiritdancer.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[270738]]></id><name><![CDATA[Krond the Dawn-Clad]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Archon]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}{G}{G}{W}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[6]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying, vigilance<br>Whenever Krond the Dawn-Clad attacks, if it's enchanted, exile target permanent.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Krond, the personification of the dawn's light, lives to exact justice on his nemesis Vela.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Zoltan Boros]]></artist><number><![CDATA[99]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/1/2012 : If Krond isn't enchanted when it's declared as an attacking creature, the ability won't trigger. If Krond isn't enchanted when the ability resolves, the ability won't do anything.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271177]]></id><name><![CDATA[Krosan Verge]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Krosan Verge enters the battlefield tapped.<br>{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.<br>{2}, {T}, Sacrifice Krosan Verge: Search your library for a Forest card and a Plains card and put them onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Tony Szczudlo]]></artist><number><![CDATA[123]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271164]]></id><name><![CDATA[Last Stand]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{W}{U}{B}{R}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Target opponent loses 2 life for each Swamp you control. Last Stand deals damage equal to the number of Mountains you control to target creature. Put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield for each Forest you control. You gain 2 life for each Plains you control. Draw a card for each Island you control, then discard that many cards.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ron Spencer]]></artist><number><![CDATA[100]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271194]]></id><name><![CDATA[Liliana's Specter]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Specter]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>When Liliana's Specter enters the battlefield, each opponent discards a card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["The finest minions know what I need without me ever saying a thing."<br>—Liliana Vess]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Vance Kovacs]]></artist><number><![CDATA[34]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271235]]></id><name><![CDATA[Lumberknot]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Treefolk]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Hexproof (This creature can't be the target of spells or abilities your opponents control.)<br>Whenever a creature dies, put a +1/+1 counter on Lumberknot.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Animated by geists fused in its oak, it hungers for more life to add to its core.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jason A. Engle]]></artist><number><![CDATA[66]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[265154]]></id><name><![CDATA[Maelstrom Wanderer]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{U}{R}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[8]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[7]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Creatures you control have haste.<br>Cascade, cascade (When you cast this spell, exile cards from the top of your library until you exile a nonland card that costs less. You may cast it without paying its mana cost. Put the exiled cards on the bottom in a random order. Then do it again.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Thomas M. Baxa]]></artist><number><![CDATA[101]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/1/2012 : Maelstrom Wanderer gives itself haste. <br>6/1/2012 : Each instance of cascade triggers and resolves separately. The spell you cast due to the first cascade ability will go on the stack on top of the second cascade ability. That spell will resolve before you exile cards for the second cascade ability. Casting that spell may cause additional cascade abilities to trigger. <br>6/1/2012 : No matter what spell you cast with the first cascade trigger (or any cascade triggers that result from casting that spell), the second cascade trigger will look for a spell with converted mana cost less than Maelstrom Wanderer's converted mana cost of 8.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271152]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mammoth Umbra]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature gets +3/+3 and has vigilance.<br>Totem armor (If enchanted creature would be destroyed, instead remove all damage from it and destroy this Aura.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Howard Lyon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[10]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/15/2010 :  Totem armor's effect is mandatory. If the enchanted permanent would be destroyed, you must remove all damage from it and destroy the Aura that has totem armor instead. <br>6/15/2010 :  Totem armor's effect is applied no matter why the enchanted permanent would be destroyed: because it's been dealt lethal damage, or because it's being affected by an effect that says to "destroy" it (such as Doom Blade). In either case, all damage is removed from the permanent and the Aura is destroyed instead. <br>6/15/2010 : Totem armor has no effect if the enchanted permanent is put into a graveyard for any other reason, such as if it's sacrificed, if it's legendary and another legendary permanent with the same name is on the battlefield, or if its toughness is 0 or less. <br>6/15/2010 : If a permanent you control is enchanted with multiple Auras that have totem armor, and the enchanted permanent would be destroyed, one of those Auras is destroyed instead -- but only one of them. You choose which one because you control the enchanted permanent. <br>6/15/2010 : If a creature enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor is indestructible, lethal damage and effects that try to destroy it simply have no effect. Totem armor won't do anything because it won't have to. <br>6/15/2010 : If a creature enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor would be destroyed by multiple state-based actions at the same time the totem armor's effect will replace all of them and save the creature. <br>6/15/2010 : If a spell or ability (such as Planar Cleansing) would destroy both an Aura with totem armor and the permanent it's enchanting at the same time, totem armor's effect will save the enchanted permanent from being destroyed. Instead, the spell or ability will destroy the Aura in two different ways at the same time, but the result is the same as destroying it once. <br>6/15/2010 : Totem armor's effect is not regeneration. Specifically, if totem armor's effect is applied, the enchanted permanent does not become tapped and is not removed from combat as a result. Effects that say the enchanted permanent can't be regenerated (as Vendetta does) won't prevent totem armor's effect from being applied. <br>6/15/2010 : Say you control a permanent enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor, and the enchanted permanent has gained a regeneration shield. The next time it would be destroyed, you choose whether to apply the regeneration effect or the totem armor effect. The other effect is unused and remains, in case the permanent would be destroyed again. <br>6/15/2010 : Say you control a permanent enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor, and that Aura has gained a regeneration shield. The next time the enchanted permanent would be destroyed, the Aura would be destroyed instead -- but it regenerates, so nothing is destroyed at all. Alternately, if that Aura somehow becomes indestructible, the enchanted permanent is effectively indestructible as well. <br>6/15/2010 : If a spell or ability says that it would "destroy" a permanent enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor, that spell or ability causes the Aura to be destroyed instead. (This matters for cards such as Karmic Justice.) Totem armor doesn't destroy the Aura; rather, it changes the effects of the spell or ability. On the other hand, if a spell or ability deals lethal damage to a creature enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor, the game rules regarding lethal damage cause the Aura to be destroyed, not that spell or ability.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271135]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mark of Mutiny]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Gain control of target creature until end of turn. Put a +1/+1 counter on it and untap it. That creature gains haste until end of turn. (It can attack and {T} this turn.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The flame of anger is hard to douse once lit.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mike Bierek]]></artist><number><![CDATA[47]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : You may target a creature you already control. You may target a creature that's already untapped. <br>10/1/2009 : The +1/+1 counter remains on the creature after the control-changing effect ends.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[270743]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mass Mutiny]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[For each opponent, gain control of up to one target creature that player controls until end of turn. Untap those creatures. They gain haste until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["What say you, my most trusted advisors? . . . Advisors?"<br>—Edra, merfolk sovereign]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Carl Critchlow]]></artist><number><![CDATA[48]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/1/2012 : The phrase "up to one" was inadvertently omitted from Mass Mutiny's rules text. The card has received errata to correct this. <br>6/1/2012 : You can cast Mass Mutiny even if an opponent doesn't control any creatures. You simply won't choose a target for that opponent. <br>6/1/2012 : Mass Mutiny can target untapped creatures. <br>6/1/2012 : Gaining control of a creature doesn't cause you to gain control of any Auras or Equipment attached to it. However, if you gain control of a creature enchanted by an Aura with totem armor and that creature would be destroyed that turn, instead the Aura will be destroyed and the creature will survive.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271183]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mistblade Shinobi]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Ninja]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Ninjutsu {U} ({U}, Return an unblocked attacker you control to hand: Put this card onto the battlefield from your hand tapped and attacking.)<br>Whenever Mistblade Shinobi deals combat damage to a player, you may return target creature that player controls to its owner's hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kev Walker]]></artist><number><![CDATA[20]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271195]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mitotic Slime]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Ooze]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Mitotic Slime dies, put two 2/2 green Ooze creature tokens onto the battlefield. They have "When this creature dies, put two 1/1 green Ooze creature tokens onto the battlefield."]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Raymond Swanland]]></artist><number><![CDATA[67]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276465]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mountain]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Mountain]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[D. Alexander Gregory]]></artist><number><![CDATA[149]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271222]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mudbutton Torchrunner]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Goblin Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Mudbutton Torchrunner dies, it deals 3 damage to target creature or player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The oil sloshes against his skull as he nears his destination: the Frogtosser Games and the lighting of the Flaming Boggart.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Ellis]]></artist><number><![CDATA[49]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271161]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mycoloth]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Fungus]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Devour 2 (As this enters the battlefield, you may sacrifice any number of creatures. This creature enters the battlefield with twice that many +1/+1 counters on it.)<br>At the beginning of your upkeep, put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield for each +1/+1 counter on Mycoloth.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Raymond Swanland]]></artist><number><![CDATA[68]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2008 : You may choose not to sacrifice any creatures for the Devour ability. <br>10/1/2008 : If you cast this as a spell, you choose how many and which creatures to devour as part of the resolution of that spell. (It can't be countered at this point.) The same is true of a spell or ability that lets you put a creature with devour onto the battlefield. <br>10/1/2008 : You may sacrifice only creatures that are already on the battlefield. If a creature with devour and another creature are entering the battlefield under your control at the same time, the creature with devour can't devour that other creature. The creature with devour also can't devour itself. <br>10/1/2008 : If multiple creatures with devour are entering the battlefield under your control at the same time, you may use each one's devour ability. A creature you already control can be devoured by only one of them, however. (In other words, you can't sacrifice the same creature to satisfy multiple devour abilities.) All creatures devoured this way are sacrificed at the same time. <br>10/1/2008 : The number of Saproling tokens created by the triggered ability is based on the number of +1/+1 counters on Mycoloth, not on the number of creatures Mycoloth devoured. It doesn't matter where the +1/+1 counters came from.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[275261]]></id><name><![CDATA[Nest Invader]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Eldrazi Drone]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Nest Invader enters the battlefield, put a 0/1 colorless Eldrazi Spawn creature token onto the battlefield. It has "Sacrifice this creature: Add {1} to your mana pool."]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[It nurtures its masters' glorious future.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Trevor Claxton]]></artist><number><![CDATA[69]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271184]]></id><name><![CDATA[Ninja of the Deep Hours]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Ninja]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Ninjutsu {1}{U} ({1}{U}, Return an unblocked attacker you control to hand: Put this card onto the battlefield from your hand tapped and attacking.)<br>Whenever Ninja of the Deep Hours deals combat damage to a player, you may draw a card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dan Scott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[21]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271144]]></id><name><![CDATA[Noggle Ransacker]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Noggle Rogue]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{UR}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Noggle Ransacker enters the battlefield, each player draws two cards, then discards a card at random.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Noggles live purely by what they can scavenge. There is not a single thing a noggle eats, wears, or uses that did not once belong to another.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Alex Horley-Orlandelli]]></artist><number><![CDATA[102]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>8/1/2008 : First the player whose turn it is draws two cards, then each other player in turn order does so. Then the player whose turn it is randomly selects a card from his or her hand, then each other player in turn order does so. Finally, all cards selected this way are discarded at the same time.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271178]]></id><name><![CDATA[Nullmage Advocate]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Insect Druid]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Return two target cards from an opponent's graveyard to his or her hand. Destroy target artifact or enchantment.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Our unity unmasks your deceit."]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Darrell Riche]]></artist><number><![CDATA[70]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/4/2004 : You can't activate this ability unless a single opponent has at least two cards in their graveyard to target. ]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271185]]></id><name><![CDATA[Okiba-Gang Shinobi]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Rat Ninja]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Ninjutsu {3}{B} ({3}{B}, Return an unblocked attacker you control to hand: Put this card onto the battlefield from your hand tapped and attacking.)<br>Whenever Okiba-Gang Shinobi deals combat damage to a player, that player discards two cards.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mark Zug]]></artist><number><![CDATA[35]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2005 : If the defending player has two or fewer cards in hand when Okiba-Gang Shinobi deals combat damage to that player, they are all discarded.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271153]]></id><name><![CDATA[Ondu Giant]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Giant Druid]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Ondu Giant enters the battlefield, you may search your library for a basic land card, put it onto the battlefield tapped, then shuffle your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Some druids nurture gardens. Others nurture continents.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Igor Kieryluk]]></artist><number><![CDATA[71]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271201]]></id><name><![CDATA[Overrun]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Creatures you control get +3/+3 and gain trample until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Nature doesn't walk.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Carl Critchlow]]></artist><number><![CDATA[72]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : Overrun affects only creatures you control at the time it resolves. It won't affect creatures that come under your control later in the turn.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271223]]></id><name><![CDATA[Penumbra Spider]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Spider]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Reach<br>When Penumbra Spider dies, put a 2/4 black Spider creature token with reach onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[When it snared a passing cockatrice, its own soul darkly doubled.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jeff Easley]]></artist><number><![CDATA[73]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271190]]></id><name><![CDATA[Peregrine Drake]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Drake]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>When Peregrine Drake enters the battlefield, untap up to five lands.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[That the Tolarian mists parted for the drakes was warning enough to stay away.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Bob Eggleton]]></artist><number><![CDATA[22]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/4/2004 : You can untap another player's lands. <br>10/4/2004 : This does not target the lands. ]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276459]]></id><name><![CDATA[Plains]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Plains]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{W}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jung Park]]></artist><number><![CDATA[135]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271211]]></id><name><![CDATA[Pollenbright Wings]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{G}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature has flying.<br>Whenever enchanted creature deals combat damage to a player, put that many 1/1 green Saproling creature tokens onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Terese Nielsen]]></artist><number><![CDATA[103]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271136]]></id><name><![CDATA[Predatory Urge]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature has "{T}: This creature deals damage equal to its power to target creature. That creature deals damage equal to its power to this creature."]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Scott Chou]]></artist><number><![CDATA[74]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : The controller of the enchanted creature may activate the ability, not the controller of Predatory Urge. <br>10/1/2009 : If the enchanted creature's ability is activated, that creature is the one that will deal and be dealt damage when the ability resolves. It doesn't matter if Predatory Urge leaves the battlefield or somehow becomes attached to another creature by that time. <br>10/1/2009 : If the targeted creature leaves the battlefield (or otherwise becomes an illegal target) before the ability resolves, the ability is countered. The enchanted creature isn't dealt damage. <br>10/1/2009 : On the other hand, if the enchanted creature leaves the battlefield before the ability resolves, the ability continues to resolve. The enchanted creature deals damage to the targeted creature equal to the power the enchanted creature had as it last existed on the battlefield. <br>10/1/2009 : You may have the enchanted creature target itself with its own ability. If you do, it will deal damage to itself equal to its power, then immediately do it again.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[265150]]></id><name><![CDATA[Preyseizer Dragon]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Dragon]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{R}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Flying<br>Devour 2 (As this enters the battlefield, you may sacrifice any number of creatures. This creature enters the battlefield with twice that many +1/+1 counters on it.)<br>Whenever Preyseizer Dragon attacks, it deals damage to target creature or player equal to the number of +1/+1 counters on Preyseizer Dragon.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Daarken]]></artist><number><![CDATA[50]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/1/2012 : Preyseizer Dragon's ability counts the number of +1/+1 counters on it when the ability resolves. It counts any +1/+1 counters, not just ones put on it due to devour.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271175]]></id><name><![CDATA[Primal Plasma]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental Shapeshifter]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[*]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[*]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[As Primal Plasma enters the battlefield, it becomes your choice of a 3/3 creature, a 2/2 creature with flying, or a 1/6 creature with defender.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Tocasia brushed the gears and cogs from the table. There, before two wide-eyed brothers, she began a lesson on raw elemental magic.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Luca Zontini]]></artist><number><![CDATA[23]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2007 : If a creature that's already on the battlefield becomes a copy of Primal Plasma, it copies the power, toughness, and abilities that were chosen for Primal Plasma when it entered the battlefield. <br>2/1/2007 : This is the timeshifted version of Primal Clay. <br>7/1/2012 : In zones other than the battlefield, Primal Plasma is 0/0. <br>7/1/2012 : If another permanent enters the battlefield as a copy of Primal Clay, the controller of that permanent will get to make a new choice. The copy won't necessarily have the same power, toughness, and abilities as the original.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271238]]></id><name><![CDATA[Quiet Disrepair]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant artifact or enchantment<br>At the beginning of your upkeep, choose one — Destroy enchanted permanent; or you gain 2 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Artifice has always stood upon nature's shoulders. Let us watch nature take a turn."<br>—Freyalise]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Glen Angus]]></artist><number><![CDATA[75]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>5/1/2007 : If you choose the "destroy" mode and Quiet Disrepair is moved to a different permanent while the ability is on the stack, the newly enchanted permanent will be destroyed when the ability resolves. <br>5/1/2007 : If you choose the "destroy" mode and Quiet Disrepair leaves the battlefield while the ability is on the stack, the last permanent it enchanted will be destroyed.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271219]]></id><name><![CDATA[Quietus Spike]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact — Equipment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Equipped creature has deathtouch.<br>Whenever equipped creature deals combat damage to a player, that player loses half his or her life, rounded up.<br>Equip {3}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mark Brill]]></artist><number><![CDATA[112]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2008 : That player loses half his or her life after combat damage has been subtracted from the player's life total. The amount of life the player loses is determined as the triggered ability resolves. <br>10/1/2008 : If multiple Quietus Spikes trigger at the same time, that player loses half his or her life when the first ability resolves, then loses half of the remainder when the next ability resolves, and so on. The player does not lose the same amount each time. <br>6/15/2010 : In a Two-Headed Giant game, if a creature equipped with Quietus Spike would assign combat damage to the defending team, its damage is assigned to only one of the defending players. After combat damage is dealt, Quietus Spike looks at that player's life total (which is the same as the team's life total) when determining how much life the team will lose, which basically means the team's life total is halved. Here's an example of the math: The team has 19 life, so the player has 19 life. Quietus Spike causes the team to lose 10 life (19 divided by 2, rounded up). The team's life total becomes 9 (19 minus 10).]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[275266]]></id><name><![CDATA[Rancor]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature gets +2/+0 and has trample.<br>When Rancor is put into a graveyard from the battlefield, return Rancor to its owner's hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kev Walker]]></artist><number><![CDATA[76]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>7/1/2012 : If the target of Rancor when it's cast as a spell is an illegal target when Rancor tries to resolve, Rancor will be countered and put into its owner's graveyard. It won't return to its owner's hand.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271200]]></id><name><![CDATA[Rivals' Duel]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Choose two target creatures that share no creature types. Those creatures fight each other. (Each deals damage equal to its power to the other.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[They could agree on one thing only: one of them must die.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Zoltan Boros & Gabor Szikszai]]></artist><number><![CDATA[51]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>4/1/2008 : The two creatures may be controlled by the same player. <br>4/1/2008 : If either one of the creatures leaves the battlefield before Rivals' Duel resolves, no damage is dealt to or by the remaining creature. If both creatures leave the battlefield before Rivals' Duel resolves, the spell is countered for having no legal targets. <br>4/1/2008 : If, by the time Rivals' Duel resolves, an effect has caused the two target creatures to share a creature type, Rivals' Duel is countered for having no legal targets.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271142]]></id><name><![CDATA[Rupture Spire]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Rupture Spire enters the battlefield tapped.<br>When Rupture Spire enters the battlefield, sacrifice it unless you pay {1}.<br>{T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jaime Jones]]></artist><number><![CDATA[124]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[270731]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sai of the Shinobi]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact — Equipment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Equipped creature gets +1/+1.<br>Whenever a creature enters the battlefield under your control, you may attach Sai of the Shinobi to it.<br>Equip {2}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The passing of the sai presages the end of the old clan and the ascent of the new.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Brian Snoddy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[113]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/1/2012 : If you choose not to attach Sai of the Shinobi to the creature, or if you can't (perhaps because the creature has protection from artifacts or has left the battlefield by the time the trigger resolves), Sai of the Shinobi doesn't move.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[265159]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sakashima's Student]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Ninja]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[0]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Ninjutsu {1}{U} ({1}{U}, Return an unblocked attacker you control to hand: Put this card onto the battlefield from your hand tapped and attacking.)<br>You may have Sakashima's Student enter the battlefield as a copy of any creature on the battlefield, except it's still a Ninja in addition to its other creature types.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Brian Snoddy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[24]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/1/2012 : Because you return the unblocked attacking creature to its owner's hand while activating the ninjutsu ability, you can't have Sakashima's Student enter the battlefield as a copy of that creature. <br>6/1/2012 : Sakashima's Student copies exactly what was printed on the original creature (unless that creature is copying something else or is a token; see below) and it is a Ninja in addition to its other types. It doesn't copy whether that creature is tapped or untapped, whether it has any counters on it or any Auras and Equipment attached to it, or any non-copy effects that have changed its power, toughness, types, color, or so on. <br>6/1/2012 : If the chosen creature has {X} in its mana cost, X is zero. <br>6/1/2012 : If the chosen creature is copying something else (for example, if the chosen creature is another Sakashima's Student), then your Sakashima's Student enters the battlefield as whatever the chosen creature copied. <br>6/1/2012 : If the chosen creature is a token, Sakashima's Student copies the original characteristics of that token as stated by the effect that put the token onto the battlefield. Sakashima's Student is not a token. <br>6/1/2012 : Any enters-the-battlefield abilities of the copied creature will trigger when Sakashima's Student enters the battlefield. Any "as [this creature] enters the battlefield" or "[this creature] enters the battlefield with" abilities of the chosen creature (like devour) will also work. <br>6/1/2012 : If Sakashima's Student somehow enters the battlefield at the same time as another creature, Sakashima's Student can't become a copy of that creature. You may only choose a creature that's already on the battlefield. <br>6/1/2012 : You can choose not to copy anything. In that case, Sakashima's Student enters the battlefield as a 0/0 creature, and is probably put into the graveyard immediately.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271154]]></id><name><![CDATA[See Beyond]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Draw two cards, then shuffle a card from your hand into your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Ancient lore locked in a mind driven mad is just as safe as when it was locked deep underground.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Andrew Robinson]]></artist><number><![CDATA[25]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/15/2010 : The card you shuffle into your library may be any card from your hand. It doesn't have to be one of the cards you drew with the spell. <br>6/15/2010 : You have to shuffle a card from your hand into your library even if you don't draw any cards (due to replacement effects or Maralen of the Mornsong's ability, for example). If your hand is empty, you don't shuffle your library.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271212]]></id><name><![CDATA[Selesnya Sanctuary]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Selesnya Sanctuary enters the battlefield tapped.<br>When Selesnya Sanctuary enters the battlefield, return a land you control to its owner's hand.<br>{T}: Add {G}{W} to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[John Avon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[125]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>4/15/2013 : If this land enters the battlefield and you control no other lands, its ability will force you to return it to your hand.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[270733]]></id><name><![CDATA[Shardless Agent]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Human Rogue]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Cascade (When you cast this spell, exile cards from the top of your library until you exile a nonland card that costs less. You may cast it without paying its mana cost. Put the exiled cards on the bottom in a random order.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Izzy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[104]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271203]]></id><name><![CDATA[Shimmering Grotto]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.<br>{1}, {T}: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["This is the price of being last in the food chain. We must keep our places of beauty hidden away instead of displayed for all to see."<br>—Hildin, priest of Avacyn]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Cliff Childs]]></artist><number><![CDATA[126]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[275258]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sigil of the Empty Throne]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{W}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever you cast an enchantment spell, put a 4/4 white Angel creature token with flying onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[When Asha left Bant, she ensured that the world would have protection and order in her absence.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Cyril Van Der Haegen]]></artist><number><![CDATA[11]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2009 : The triggered ability will resolve before the enchantment spell that caused it to trigger. <br>2/1/2009 : When you cast an Aura spell, you have to choose a target for it before this ability puts an Angel token onto the battlefield. In other words, you can't play an Aura spell intending to enchant the Angel that will be created as a result. <br>2/1/2009 : Casting Sigil of the Empty Throne won't trigger its own ability. It has to be on the battlefield for its ability to work.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[270727]]></id><name><![CDATA[Silent-Blade Oni]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Demon Ninja]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}{U}{B}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[7]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[6]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[5]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Ninjutsu {4}{U}{B} ({4}{U}{B}, Return an unblocked attacker you control to hand: Put this card onto the battlefield from your hand tapped and attacking.)<br>Whenever Silent-Blade Oni deals combat damage to a player, look at that player's hand. You may cast a nonland card in it without paying that card's mana cost.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Steve Prescott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[105]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/1/2012 : If you cast a permanent spell this way, it will enter the battlefield under your control when it resolves. If you cast an instant or sorcery spell this way, that card will be put into its owner's graveyard when it resolves. <br>6/1/2012 : The nonland card you cast via the triggered ability is cast as part of the resolution of that ability. Timing restrictions based on the card's type are ignored. Other restrictions, such as "Cast [this card] only during an opponent's turn," are not. <br>6/1/2012 : If you cast a card without paying its mana cost, you can't pay any alternative costs, such as evoke or the alternative cost provided by the morph ability. If it has {X} in its mana cost, X must be 0. However, you can pay optional additional costs, such as kicker, and you must still pay mandatory additional costs, such as the one on Fling.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271230]]></id><name><![CDATA[Silhana Ledgewalker]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elf Rogue]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Hexproof (This creature can't be the target of spells or abilities your opponents control.)<br>Silhana Ledgewalker can't be blocked except by creatures with flying.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Street folk call them "spire mice," but behind the mockery is an unspoken envy of the ledgewalkers' skill at avoiding harm.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[James Wong]]></artist><number><![CDATA[77]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>5/1/2007 : Creatures with the Reach ability (such as Giant Spider) don’t actually have Flying, so they can’t block this.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271231]]></id><name><![CDATA[Skarrg, the Rage Pits]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.<br>{R}{G}, {T}: Target creature gets +1/+1 and gains trample until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["This palace will be our fire-spit, and roasted prince our victory meal. Send in the torch-pigs!"<br>—Ghut Rak, Gruul guildmage]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Martina Pilcerova]]></artist><number><![CDATA[127]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271186]]></id><name><![CDATA[Skullsnatcher]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Rat Ninja]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Ninjutsu {B} ({B}, Return an unblocked attacker you control to hand: Put this card onto the battlefield from your hand tapped and attacking.)<br>Whenever Skullsnatcher deals combat damage to a player, exile up to two target cards from that player's graveyard.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Matt Cavotta]]></artist><number><![CDATA[36]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>2/1/2005 : Skullsnatcher's ability can target zero, one, or two cards in that player's graveyard.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271155]]></id><name><![CDATA[Snake Umbra]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 and has "Whenever this creature deals damage to an opponent, you may draw a card."<br>Totem armor (If enchanted creature would be destroyed, instead remove all damage from it and destroy this Aura.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Christopher Moeller]]></artist><number><![CDATA[78]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/15/2010 :  Totem armor's effect is mandatory. If the enchanted permanent would be destroyed, you must remove all damage from it and destroy the Aura that has totem armor instead. <br>6/15/2010 :  Totem armor's effect is applied no matter why the enchanted permanent would be destroyed: because it's been dealt lethal damage, or because it's being affected by an effect that says to "destroy" it (such as Doom Blade). In either case, all damage is removed from the permanent and the Aura is destroyed instead. <br>6/15/2010 : Totem armor has no effect if the enchanted permanent is put into a graveyard for any other reason, such as if it's sacrificed, if it's legendary and another legendary permanent with the same name is on the battlefield, or if its toughness is 0 or less. <br>6/15/2010 : If a permanent you control is enchanted with multiple Auras that have totem armor, and the enchanted permanent would be destroyed, one of those Auras is destroyed instead -- but only one of them. You choose which one because you control the enchanted permanent. <br>6/15/2010 : If a creature enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor is indestructible, lethal damage and effects that try to destroy it simply have no effect. Totem armor won't do anything because it won't have to. <br>6/15/2010 : If a creature enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor would be destroyed by multiple state-based actions at the same time the totem armor's effect will replace all of them and save the creature. <br>6/15/2010 : If a spell or ability (such as Planar Cleansing) would destroy both an Aura with totem armor and the permanent it's enchanting at the same time, totem armor's effect will save the enchanted permanent from being destroyed. Instead, the spell or ability will destroy the Aura in two different ways at the same time, but the result is the same as destroying it once. <br>6/15/2010 : Totem armor's effect is not regeneration. Specifically, if totem armor's effect is applied, the enchanted permanent does not become tapped and is not removed from combat as a result. Effects that say the enchanted permanent can't be regenerated (as Vendetta does) won't prevent totem armor's effect from being applied. <br>6/15/2010 : Say you control a permanent enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor, and the enchanted permanent has gained a regeneration shield. The next time it would be destroyed, you choose whether to apply the regeneration effect or the totem armor effect. The other effect is unused and remains, in case the permanent would be destroyed again. <br>6/15/2010 : Say you control a permanent enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor, and that Aura has gained a regeneration shield. The next time the enchanted permanent would be destroyed, the Aura would be destroyed instead -- but it regenerates, so nothing is destroyed at all. Alternately, if that Aura somehow becomes indestructible, the enchanted permanent is effectively indestructible as well. <br>6/15/2010 : If a spell or ability says that it would "destroy" a permanent enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor, that spell or ability causes the Aura to be destroyed instead. (This matters for cards such as Karmic Justice.) Totem armor doesn't destroy the Aura; rather, it changes the effects of the spell or ability. On the other hand, if a spell or ability deals lethal damage to a creature enchanted with an Aura that has totem armor, the game rules regarding lethal damage cause the Aura to be destroyed, not that spell or ability. <br>6/15/2010 : Snake Umbra grants the triggered ability to the creature. It triggers whenever the enchanted creature deals damage to an opponent of its controller (who is not necessarily an opponent of the Aura's controller). In other words, if your Snake Umbra winds up enchanting your opponent's creature, that opponent will draw a card whenever that creature damages you. <br>6/15/2010 : The ability triggers when the enchanted creature deals any damage, not just combat damage.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[275265]]></id><name><![CDATA[Spirit Mantle]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment — Aura]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Enchant creature<br>Enchanted creature gets +1/+1 and has protection from creatures.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The shield of unimpeachable purity is as strong as any wrought on the anvil.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Izzy]]></artist><number><![CDATA[12]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271202]]></id><name><![CDATA[Sunken Hope]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[At the beginning of each player's upkeep, that player returns a creature he or she controls to its owner's hand.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["I don't concern myself with my enemy's hopes. Hopes follow the tides. They will retreat soon enough."<br>—Ambassador Laquatus]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Volkan Baga]]></artist><number><![CDATA[26]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276455]]></id><name><![CDATA[Swamp]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Swamp]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{B}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jim Nelson]]></artist><number><![CDATA[143]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271239]]></id><name><![CDATA[Tainted Isle]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.<br>{T}: Add {U} or {B} to your mana pool. Activate this ability only if you control a Swamp.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Alan Pollack]]></artist><number><![CDATA[128]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271196]]></id><name><![CDATA[Terramorphic Expanse]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}, Sacrifice Terramorphic Expanse: Search your library for a basic land card and put it onto the battlefield tapped. Then shuffle your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Dan Scott]]></artist><number><![CDATA[129]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271162]]></id><name><![CDATA[Thorn-Thrash Viashino]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Viashino Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Devour 2 (As this enters the battlefield, you may sacrifice any number of creatures. This creature enters the battlefield with twice that many +1/+1 counters on it.)<br>{G}: Thorn-Thrash Viashino gains trample until end of turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jon Foster]]></artist><number><![CDATA[52]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2008 : You may choose not to sacrifice any creatures for the Devour ability. <br>10/1/2008 : If you cast this as a spell, you choose how many and which creatures to devour as part of the resolution of that spell. (It can't be countered at this point.) The same is true of a spell or ability that lets you put a creature with devour onto the battlefield. <br>10/1/2008 : You may sacrifice only creatures that are already on the battlefield. If a creature with devour and another creature are entering the battlefield under your control at the same time, the creature with devour can't devour that other creature. The creature with devour also can't devour itself. <br>10/1/2008 : If multiple creatures with devour are entering the battlefield under your control at the same time, you may use each one's devour ability. A creature you already control can be devoured by only one of them, however. (In other words, you can't sacrifice the same creature to satisfy multiple devour abilities.) All creatures devoured this way are sacrificed at the same time.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271173]]></id><name><![CDATA[Thran Golem]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact Creature — Golem]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[3]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[As long as Thran Golem is enchanted, it gets +2/+2 and has flying, first strike, and trample.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[The golems of the ancient Thran still draw power in ways that baffle the artificers of today.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Ron Spears]]></artist><number><![CDATA[114]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[275260]]></id><name><![CDATA[Three Dreams]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Sorcery]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{W}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Search your library for up to three Aura cards with different names, reveal them, and put them into your hand. Then shuffle your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Choose one to heal, one to harm, and one to grant you the prudence to use them."<br>—Miotri, auratouched mage]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Shishizaru]]></artist><number><![CDATA[13]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271187]]></id><name><![CDATA[Throat Slitter]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Rat Ninja]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Ninjutsu {2}{B} ({2}{B}, Return an unblocked attacker you control to hand: Put this card onto the battlefield from your hand tapped and attacking.)<br>Whenever Throat Slitter deals combat damage to a player, destroy target nonblack creature that player controls.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Parente]]></artist><number><![CDATA[37]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[265155]]></id><name><![CDATA[Thromok the Insatiable]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Hellion]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}{R}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[5]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[0]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Devour X, where X is the number of creatures devoured this way (As this enters the battlefield, you may sacrifice any number of creatures. This creature enters the battlefield with X +1/+1 counters on it for each of those creatures.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Terese Nielsen]]></artist><number><![CDATA[106]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/1/2012 : For example, if Thromok devours one creature, it will enter the battlefield with one +1/+1 counter on it. If it devours two creatures, it will enter with two +1/+1 counters for each of them, for a total of four +1/+1 counters. Devouring three creatures will produce nine +1/+1 counters, and so on.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271163]]></id><name><![CDATA[Thunder-Thrash Elder]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Viashino Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Devour 3 (As this enters the battlefield, you may sacrifice any number of creatures. This creature enters the battlefield with three times that many +1/+1 counters on it.)]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Viashino thrashes are led by elders who have survived countless challenges.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Brandon Kitkouski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[53]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2008 : You may choose not to sacrifice any creatures for the Devour ability. <br>10/1/2008 : If you cast this as a spell, you choose how many and which creatures to devour as part of the resolution of that spell. (It can't be countered at this point.) The same is true of a spell or ability that lets you put a creature with devour onto the battlefield. <br>10/1/2008 : You may sacrifice only creatures that are already on the battlefield. If a creature with devour and another creature are entering the battlefield under your control at the same time, the creature with devour can't devour that other creature. The creature with devour also can't devour itself. <br>10/1/2008 : If multiple creatures with devour are entering the battlefield under your control at the same time, you may use each one's devour ability. A creature you already control can be devoured by only one of them, however. (In other words, you can't sacrifice the same creature to satisfy multiple devour abilities.) All creatures devoured this way are sacrificed at the same time.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271174]]></id><name><![CDATA[Tormented Soul]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Spirit]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Tormented Soul can't block and is unblockable.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Those who raged most bitterly at the world in life are cursed to roam the nether realms in death.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Karl Kopinski]]></artist><number><![CDATA[38]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271143]]></id><name><![CDATA[Tukatongue Thallid]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Fungus]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[1]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Tukatongue Thallid dies, put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Jund's thallids tried to disguise their deliciousness by covering themselves in spines harvested from the tukatongue tree.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Vance Kovacs]]></artist><number><![CDATA[79]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[270729]]></id><name><![CDATA[Vela the Night-Clad]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Legendary Creature — Human Wizard]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[M]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{4}{U}{B}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Intimidate<br>Other creatures you control have intimidate.<br>Whenever Vela the Night-Clad or another creature you control leaves the battlefield, each opponent loses 1 life.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Vela snuffs out every trace of Krond's reign, leaving pure nightfall in her wake.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Allen Williams]]></artist><number><![CDATA[107]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/1/2012 : If Vela leaves the battlefield at the same time as other creatures you control, its ability will trigger for each of those creatures.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271146]]></id><name><![CDATA[Viridian Emissary]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elf Scout]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[1]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Viridian Emissary dies, you may search your library for a basic land card, put it onto the battlefield tapped, then shuffle your library.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Matt Stewart]]></artist><number><![CDATA[80]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271213]]></id><name><![CDATA[Vitu-Ghazi, the City-Tree]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{T}: Add {1} to your mana pool.<br>{2}{G}{W}, {T}: Put a 1/1 green Saproling creature token onto the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[In the autumn, she casts her seeds across the streets below, and come spring, her children rise in service to the Conclave.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Martina Pilcerova]]></artist><number><![CDATA[130]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271204]]></id><name><![CDATA[Vivid Creek]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Land]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Vivid Creek enters the battlefield tapped with two charge counters on it.<br>{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.<br>{T}, Remove a charge counter from Vivid Creek: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Fred Fields]]></artist><number><![CDATA[131]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271188]]></id><name><![CDATA[Walker of Secret Ways]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Human Ninja]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[1]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Ninjutsu {1}{U} ({1}{U}, Return an unblocked attacker you control to hand: Put this card onto the battlefield from your hand tapped and attacking.)<br>Whenever Walker of Secret Ways deals combat damage to a player, look at that player's hand.<br>{1}{U}: Return target Ninja you control to its owner's hand. Activate this ability only during your turn.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Scott M. Fischer]]></artist><number><![CDATA[27]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[275262]]></id><name><![CDATA[Wall of Blossoms]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Plant Wall]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[2]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[4]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Defender<br>When Wall of Blossoms enters the battlefield, draw a card.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Each flower identical, every leaf and petal disturbingly exact.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Heather Hudson]]></artist><number><![CDATA[81]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271197]]></id><name><![CDATA[Wall of Frost]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Wall]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{1}{U}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[0]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[7]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Defender<br>Whenever Wall of Frost blocks a creature, that creature doesn't untap during its controller's next untap step.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["I welcome it. The pasture is cleared of weeds and the wolves are frozen solid."<br>—Lumi, goatherd]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Mike Bierek]]></artist><number><![CDATA[28]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>10/1/2009 : Unlike Sleep, Wall of Frost's triggered ability tracks the creature, but not its controller. If the creature changes controllers before its first controller's next untap step has come around, then it won't untap during its new controller's next untap step.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271226]]></id><name><![CDATA[Warstorm Surge]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{5}{R}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[6]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Whenever a creature enters the battlefield under your control, it deals damage equal to its power to target creature or player.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA["Listen to the roar! Feel the thunder! The Immersturm shouts its approval with every bolt of lightning!"]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Raymond Swanland]]></artist><number><![CDATA[54]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>9/22/2011 : The creature that entered the battlefield deals damage equal to its current power to the targeted creature or player. If it's no longer on the battlefield, its last known existence on the battlefield is checked to determine its power. <br>9/22/2011 : Warstorm Surge is the source of the ability, but the creature is the source of the damage. The ability couldn't target a creature with protection from red, for example. It could target a creature with protection from creatures, but all the damage would be prevented. Since damage is dealt by the creature, abilities like lifelink, deathtouch and infect are taken into account, even if the creature has left the battlefield by the time it deals damage.]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271165]]></id><name><![CDATA[Whirlpool Warrior]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Merfolk Warrior]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{U}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[2]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[2]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[When Whirlpool Warrior enters the battlefield, shuffle the cards from your hand into your library, then draw that many cards.<br>{R}, Sacrifice Whirlpool Warrior: Each player shuffles the cards from his or her hand into his or her library, then draws that many cards.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Kev Walker]]></artist><number><![CDATA[29]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[271198]]></id><name><![CDATA[Whispersilk Cloak]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Artifact — Equipment]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[U]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{3}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[3]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Equipped creature is unblockable and has shroud.<br>Equip {2}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Such cloaks are in high demand both by assassins and by those who fear them.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Daren Bader]]></artist><number><![CDATA[115]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276464]]></id><name><![CDATA[Forest]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Forest]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{G}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Véronique Meignaud]]></artist><number><![CDATA[154]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276454]]></id><name><![CDATA[Forest]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Forest]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{G}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Stephen Tappin]]></artist><number><![CDATA[156]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276460]]></id><name><![CDATA[Forest]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Forest]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{G}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Aleksi Briclot]]></artist><number><![CDATA[153]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276468]]></id><name><![CDATA[Forest]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Forest]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{G}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[John Avon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[151]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276467]]></id><name><![CDATA[Forest]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Forest]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{G}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[John Avon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[152]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276462]]></id><name><![CDATA[Island]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Island]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{U}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Martina Pilcerova]]></artist><number><![CDATA[138]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276453]]></id><name><![CDATA[Island]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Island]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{U}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Martina Pilcerova]]></artist><number><![CDATA[139]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276466]]></id><name><![CDATA[Island]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Island]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{U}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[John Avon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[137]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276452]]></id><name><![CDATA[Island]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Island]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{U}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Martina Pilcerova]]></artist><number><![CDATA[141]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276447]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mountain]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Mountain]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[John Avon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[147]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276449]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mountain]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Mountain]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Aleksi Briclot]]></artist><number><![CDATA[148]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276470]]></id><name><![CDATA[Mountain]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Mountain]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Véronique Meignaud]]></artist><number><![CDATA[150]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276461]]></id><name><![CDATA[Plains]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Plains]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{W}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Vincent Proce]]></artist><number><![CDATA[136]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276469]]></id><name><![CDATA[Plains]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Plains]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{W}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[John Avon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[132]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276473]]></id><name><![CDATA[Plains]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Plains]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{W}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[John Avon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[133]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276458]]></id><name><![CDATA[Plains]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Plains]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{W}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Véronique Meignaud]]></artist><number><![CDATA[134]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276472]]></id><name><![CDATA[Swamp]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Swamp]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{B}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[John Avon]]></artist><number><![CDATA[142]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276457]]></id><name><![CDATA[Swamp]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Swamp]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{B}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jim Nelson]]></artist><number><![CDATA[144]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276448]]></id><name><![CDATA[Swamp]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Swamp]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{B}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jim Nelson]]></artist><number><![CDATA[145]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card><card><id><![CDATA[276463]]></id><name><![CDATA[Swamp]]></name><set><![CDATA[PC2]]></set><type><![CDATA[Basic Land — Swamp]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[C]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[0]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[]]></toughness><loyalty><![CDATA[]]></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[{B}]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Jim Nelson]]></artist><number><![CDATA[146]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[]]></ruling></card></cards></mtg_carddatabase>