<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><mtg_carddatabase><bdd_date><![CDATA[1-5-2013]]></bdd_date><bdd_version><![CDATA[1.00]]></bdd_version><bdd_name>Magic the Gathering® Card Database</bdd_name><bdd_editor>Wizards of the Coast LLC</bdd_editor><sets><set><name><![CDATA[World Magic Cup Qualifiers]]></name><code><![CDATA[WCQ]]></code><code_magiccards><![CDATA[WMCQ]]></code_magiccards><date><![CDATA[00/0000]]></date><is_promo><![CDATA[True]]></is_promo></set></sets><cards><card><id><![CDATA[WMCQ_1]]></id><name><![CDATA[Vengevine]]></name><set><![CDATA[WCQ]]></set><type><![CDATA[Creature — Elemental]]></type><rarity><![CDATA[R]]></rarity><manacost><![CDATA[{2}{G}{G}]]></manacost><converted_manacost><![CDATA[4]]></converted_manacost><power><![CDATA[4]]></power><toughness><![CDATA[3]]></toughness><loyalty></loyalty><ability><![CDATA[Haste<br>Whenever you cast a spell, if it's the second creature spell you cast this turn, you may return Vengevine from your graveyard to the battlefield.]]></ability><flavor><![CDATA[Leave but a shred of root and it will return, bursting with vigor.]]></flavor><artist><![CDATA[Trevor Claxton]]></artist><number><![CDATA[1]]></number><ruling><![CDATA[<br>6/15/2010: If you cast your second creature spell in a turn and <u>Vengevine</u> is in your graveyard, <u>Vengevine</u>'s second ability triggers and goes on the stack on top of it. The ability will resolve, allowing you to return <u>Vengevine</u> to the battlefield, before the creature spell does.<br><br>6/15/2010: <u>Vengevine</u>'s triggered ability works only if <u>Vengevine</u> is already in your graveyard as you finish casting your second creature spell in a turn, and it remains there continuously until the ability resolves.<br><br>6/15/2010: <u>Vengevine</u> doesn't need to be in your graveyard as you start casting your second creature spell in a turn, only as you finish. This matters if you sacrifice a <u>Vengevine</u> on the battlefield while casting that creature spell, perhaps to pay a cost of that spell or a cost of a mana ability.<br><br>6/15/2010: <u>Vengevine</u>'s triggered ability checks the card types of the spells you cast over the course of the entire turn, not just the ones you cast while <u>Vengevine</u> is in your graveyard. For example, if you cast a creature spell, then <u>Vengevine</u> is put into your graveyard, then you cast another creature spell, <u>Vengevine</u>'s ability triggers.<br><br>6/15/2010: <u>Vengevine</u>'s ability triggers only for the second creature spell you cast in a turn. It won't trigger for the third, fourth, or so on. It also doesn't matter how many noncreature spells you cast in a turn; the ability counts just the creature spells.]]></ruling></card></cards></mtg_carddatabase>